<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207627</rcn>
  <acronym>MARINET2</acronym>
  <objective>Integrating activities planned under MaRINET 2 build upon the achievements of the advanced community created in MaRINET FP7. MaRINET 2 will ensure the continued integration and enhancement of all leading European research infrastructure and facilities specialising in research, development and testing of offshore renewable energy systems including electrical sub systems and grid integration through a range of TRLs (1-7). MaRINET FP7 proved the added value of uniting these facilities, and substantially improving their capability as a community of practice to deliver consistent testing services ensuring, quantifiable, stepwise innovation and progress in the development of devices and key components, and identifying critical areas for further technical investigation and enhancement. Whilst activities proposed under MaRINET 2 will follow the same formula, balancing networking/ joint research/ and transnational access, the consortium and scope of work is expanded to include xx partners in xx countries with xx facilities. The e-infrastructure programme fills a strategic gap. Taking stock of existing capacities for data management/sharing; it addresses user requirements and demonstrates the operation of a new system based on standards and tools adapted from the SeaDataNet infrastructure. The European Commission and member states recognise offshore renewable energy as an important source of clean energy that can: generate economic growth and employment; increase energy security; and boost competitiveness and technological innovation. The realisation of this potential depends on the accelerated development, deployment and grid integration of reliable, efficient technologies for harvesting offshore renewable energy, which in turn requires robust and exhaustive testing in dedicated facilities operated by practitioners with specialised expertise. MaRINET 2 provides this ecosystem, and is pre-eminently suited to fostering the next generation of offshore renewable energy devices.</objective>
  <title>Marine Renewable Infrastructure Network for Enhancing Technologies 2</title>
<identifier>H2020INFRAIA20161</identifier>
</project>
