<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207932</rcn>
  <acronym>TRACY</acronym>
  <objective>AT-Biotech is a well established Spanish SME that offers high quality RFID traceability solutions to its clients in the healthcare sector. We have already developed a system, Rhesus, that focuses in the blood donor-to-patient cycle. Rhesus significantly improves patient safety and blood quality, but also optimises the efficiency of all operational processes. At the time of writing this proposal, Rhesus has successfully identified ~35K blood donations, identified, stored and distributed ~235K blood components, and helped complete ~18K transfusions. 

In just 3 years we have signed long-term contracts with main Spanish players, where we intend to reach 60% penetration in Spanish Blood Establishments (BEs) and 30% penetration in Spanish hospitals by 2021. We also have promising international business perspectives with the Red Cross in Germany, Austria and Switzerland.
Next steps to take will be:
1. Internationalisation.
2. Production-upscaling and industrialisation. 

TRACY, our innovative RFID-UHF traceability platform for human-derived products, is an evolution of our former Rhesus platform that will help us to up-scale our production and fully internationalise our business, while providing our customers:
1. Huge SAFETY improvement. We intend to achieve 75% safety improvement in the transfusion stage (blood products).
2. Huge PRODUCTIVITY and EFFICIENCY improvement. We intend to achieve 15% improvement in the production stage. 
3. Huge QUALITY improvement. As a result of a thorough traceability and cold-chain control in the whole blood life’s cycle.

Within first 3-years of business, TRACY will let us consolidate in Spain, UK, Germany, Austria &amp; Switzerland, as well as set up in business in Portugal, Italy &amp; France, which will let us obtain ~12M euro cumulative revenues by 2021 (RoI3-years = ~3).</objective>
  <title>Innovative RFID-UHF Traceability Platform for Human-Derived Products</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
