<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205585</rcn>
  <acronym>RADSAGA</acronym>
  <objective>Reliability and radiation damage issues have a long and important history in the domain of satellites and space missions. Qualification standards were established and expertise was built up in space agencies (ESA), supporting institutes and organizations (CNES, DLR, etc.) as well as universities and specialized companies. During recent years, radiation concerns are gaining attention also in aviation, automotive, medical and other industrial sectors due to the growing ubiquity and complexity of electronic systems and their increased radiation sensitivity owing to technology scaling. This raises the demand for dedicated design and qualification guidelines, as well as associated technical expertise. Addressing open questions linked to respective qualification requirements, the proposed training network “RADiation and Reliability
Challenges for Electronics used in Space, Aviation, Ground and Accelerators” (RADSAGA) will for the first time bring together industry, universities, laboratories and test-facilities in order to innovate and train young scientists and engineers in all aspects related to electronics exposed to radiation. The expertise of the space and avionics sectors will be complemented with new and unique test facilities, design and qualification methodologies of the accelerator sector, promising for other application areas. Driven by the industrial needs, the students will be trained by established specialists in all required skills, and acquire expertise through innovative scientific projects, allowing to: (i) push the scientific frontier in design, testing and qualification of complex electronic systems for mixed field radiation environments (ii) establish related courses to train future engineers/physicists; and (iii) issue design and test guidelines to support industry in the field, protecting European competitiveness when radiation effects become as important as thermal or mechanical constraints for the aviation, automotive and other industrial sectors.</objective>
  <title>RADiation and reliability challenges for electronics used in Space, Avionics, on the Ground and at Accelerators</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2016</identifier>
</project>
