<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196626</rcn>
  <acronym>CLOUDWATCH2</acronym>
  <objective>CloudWATCH2 supports EU R&amp;D on cloud computing, software, services across the full innovation lifecycle &amp; the move to market, promoting technology advancements, supporting OS software re-usability through clustering, championing standards for interoperability &amp; security, providing a roadmap on the cloud market structure to encourage transparent pricing &amp; offering educational services on risk management &amp; legal issues to lower adoption barriers for SMEs &amp; public administration. CloudWATCH2 focuses on the cloud ecosystem emerging from EU research &amp; innovation projects, where technology &amp; pricing are an equally important part of market equation. It takes a pragmatic approach to market uptake &amp; sustainable competitiveness by clustering projects around common themes &amp; challenges, with deep dive training for wider uptake &amp; commercial exploitation. It analyses the fast evolving standards landscape, new implementations, extensions &amp; protocols focusing on the value creation of interoperable and secure services, identifying gaps &amp; making recommendations to address them. It brings interoperability testing to the forefront supporting Cloud Interoperability Plugfests. It supports market-oriented approaches to new products, services &amp; solutions, including OS developments, where “free” &amp; “profitability” are not mutually exclusive. It introduces a novel activity around cloud pricing analysis, strengthens support of sustainability, to encourage faster time-to-value &amp; commercialisation of innovative products &amp; services. On the demand side, it supports key stakeholders in the EU digital market by providing training on legal aspects addressing increasingly common consumer concerns. Consortium: TRUST-IT, coordination, outreach, a renowned international network &amp; SDO liaisons; CSA a leading, global player in cloud security; UOXF OeRC part of UK eScience programme; StrategicBlue cloud billing &amp; price risk management experts. ICT Legal, represents IT, ISP, SW, CSP, IoT &amp; IT service vendors</objective>
  <title>Think Cloud Services for Government, Business  Research</title>
<identifier>H2020ICT20141</identifier>
</project>
