<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206229</rcn>
  <acronym>INNOWAG</acronym>
  <objective>This proposal responds to the first Open Calls issued by the Shift2Rail Joint Undertaking, as part of Shift2Rail Horizon 2020 programme. It specifically addresses the topic S2R-OC-IP5-03-2015: Intelligent freight wagon with predictive maintenance. This topic is complementary with topic S2R-CFM-IP5-02-2015: Start-up activities for Freight Automation. 
The INNOWAG project will work towards increasing rail freight competitiveness and the development of the next generation of lightweight and intelligent freight wagons by addressing specific challenges in the three essential areas, identified by the call, through three subsequent work streams, namely:
- Work Stream 1 (WS1): Cargo condition monitoring;
- Work Stream 2 (WS2): Wagon design; and
- Work Stream 3 (WS3): Predictive maintenance.
Moreover, INNOWAG will consider the compatibility between the solutions proposed and researched in the three areas, as well as their integration into a novel concept of wagon. 
The aim of the proposed INNOWAG project is to develop intelligent cargo monitoring and predictive maintenance solutions integrated on a novel concept of lightweight wagon, which would respond to major challenges in rail freight competitiveness, in relation to the increase of trans
The INNOWAG project will determine how to effectively integrate innovative technologies for cargo condition monitoring into a novel high performance lightweight freight wagon, supported by effective health monitoring technologies, and predictive maintenance models for sustainable and attractive European rail freight. The development of novel technology concepts and predictive maintenance models and procedures will be separately addresses by the INNOWAG work streams.
The concept underpinning the INNOWAG project relies on the actual needs of rail freight for increasing its competitiveness and attractiveness. The INNOWAG project therefore aims at developing a rail freight service that fits the needs of modern manufacturing and supply chain.</objective>
  <title>INNOvative monitoring and predictive maintenance solutions on lightweight WAGon</title>
<identifier>H2020S2RJUOC2015012</identifier>
</project>
