<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>204387</rcn>
  <acronym>EXPANDCUSTOM</acronym>
  <objective>There is a lack of widely available, easy to use, e-commerce tools adapted to the idiosyncrasy of design-driven customised
footwear.
Customizable goods are not manufactured until the customer co-design/customize the product and makes a formal order:
this implies the absence of physical samples, and supposes a huge number of possible functional, aesthetic and design
combinations. Specialized tools are required to offer the customer the co-design possibilities, additional tools for virtual test
and for fitting are required to mitigate the absence of physical samples, and specific e-commerce tools are required to
adequately offer the product to the potential customer. A notable lack is the absence of a specific CSE (Comparison Search
Engine) focused on customizable footwear.
ExpandCustom make available to any customizable footwear manufacturer (no matter the big or the small they are) the
opportunity to easily and competitively market their products in Internet, by means of a set of specialized tools that allow the
fast deployment of a shopping site connected to a CSE focused on customizable consumer goods.
ExpandCustom appears to the consumer and to the manufacturer as two sides of a mirror:
-For the consumer is a specialized CSE: allow buyers to focus their Internet search on a unique location specialize in
customizable footwear, rather than having to navigate through a huge number of sites.
-For the manufacturer is a set of tools that allow an easy deployment of a shopping site integrated with existing ERP/CRM
and with unassisted CSE feed of products, including functionalities specific to customizable products: co-design tool, virtual
models creation/conversion, virtual materials, virtual tester tool and fitting tool.
The CSE will be the driver of all Internet traffic to the manufacturer of customizable footwear, and the creation tools will be
the brick of the shopping site.</objective>
  <title>Expanding and widening customized design-based consumer goods access</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
