<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>204339</rcn>
  <acronym>MadridERN2016-2017</acronym>
  <objective>Under the motto ‘Researchers, moving Europe forward. Meet them, join them!‘, European Researchers’ Night in Madrid, 2016-2017 underlines the importance of researchers’ work for the advancement in Europe, offering public at large, students, children and families the opportunity to meet them, talk to them, know the work they carry out and  how they spend their free time. Showing their hobbies, their hopes and their enthusiasm for the work they accomplish. 
A strong and timely awareness campaign will be launched combining traditional communication vectors with on line ones ( social networks, website, blogs…)
72 appealing activities will be held in a playful and relaxing atmosphere in different venues of seven cities in the Region of Madrid covering varied neighbourhood where people with diverse interests and backgrounds live. Special attention will be paid to young people in order to encourage them to embark on scientific careers and also to foster the entrepreneurial and innovative spirit among them.
All scientific disciplines will be represented along with other issues such as arts, sports, literature, cooking, etc. Gender balanced will be also taken into account as well as the Responsible Research and Innovation (RRI) in order to foster the design of inclusive and sustainable research and innovation. The involvement of the societal actors and stakeholders is a guarantee of public engagement. 
Researchers benefited by European programmes and Marie Skłodowska-Curie fellows will join the activities, having a real presence in the Europeans’ corners, highlighting therefore the European dimension of the event.
Common actions will be performed together with another European Researchers’ Night in Europe and in Spain and also if appropriate in the same Region.</objective>
  <title>Researchers, moving Europe forward. Meet them, join them!</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCANIGHT2016</identifier>
</project>
