<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207949</rcn>
  <acronym>CONCILIO</acronym>
  <objective>Question: How would you find the best specialist if you or your loved one were ill? Answer: by asking your physician, your friends and family or Google. However, only medical specialists have the insider knowledge of who are their most competent peers, but often use it solely to the benefit of their relatives or of their own patients. The rest of the population doesn’t have access to this information, which could have a profound impact on health outcomes (e.g. second opinions lead to changes in diagnosis or treatment plans in up to 77% of cases). 
The Information Company is a digital health company founded by medical and digital entrepreneurs in 2015, which has developed Concilio, a new concierge service leveraging the power of large numbers of peer-referrals in each speciality and proprietary algorithms validating and substantiating them by objective data. Its end goal is to help patients anywhere get access to the best possible care for any medical condition, reducing stress, medical costs and significantly improving clinical outcomes.
The proposed SME Instrument project’s objective is to scale-up and validate Concilio’s innovative business and healthcare model, along with its technology, to enable its users to gain access to detailed and verified professional networks of thousands of specialists throughout the world, without relying on any doctor’s or medical product company’s subscription to remain unbiased and objective. To do so, phase 1 actions will include (1) the development of a multilingual, multi-users and multi-countries web-site and mobile application, (2) the securization of intellectual property and (3) the validation of Concilio’s market/commercial and economic scalability. Based on the proof of concept obtained by the company with over 15,000 doctor names across 9 specialities already existing in the database, and 1.3M€ in capital, it will enable Concilio to fast track its business to €42 million and 179 job creation by 2020.</objective>
  <title>Development of a global, inclusive, digital health concierge</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
