<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205933</rcn>
  <acronym>SCREEN</acronym>
  <objective>SCREEN aims at the definition of a replicable systemic approach towards a transition to Circular Economy in EU regions within the context of the Smart Specialization Strategy, through the identification and implementation of operational synergies between R&amp;I investments from H2020 and the European Structural and Investment Funds, thus contributing to novel future eco-innovative and horizontal business models across different value chains. 
The concept of the action is to develop a EU reference framework for establish operational synergies between Horizon 2020 and the European Structural and Investment Funds related to Circular Economy by:
a) Sustaining the regional actors’ participation at H2020 
The mechanism of the “vouchers”, already adopted in the past, will be reinforced an harmonized, in order to ensure common rules in EU regions and therefore encouraging to composition of international Consortia applying for circular economy projects related to the regional Smart Specialisation.
b) Encouraging the entrepreneurial initiatives based on H2020 project’s results 
The participating Regions will agree about a specific rule in their Structural Funds giving an advantage for those initiatives targeted to the exploitation of the H2020 project results with a circular economy approach.
c) Investigating the possibility of maximizing the H2020 investment through a “recovery” (fully or partial) of well ranked unfinanced proposals dealing with circular economy
Even if there is a clear presence of several bureaucratic and operational barriers, a possible solution could  have an impressive multiplier effect on the H2020 results.
The approach of the action is to leverage on growing industry sectors in EU regions to act as a driver also for the less performing ones, through a circular economy approach, and to support the emergence of new actors in the regional economies leading to new or redesigned value chains.</objective>
  <title>Synergic Circular Economy across European Regions</title>
<identifier>H2020CIRC2016OneStage</identifier>
</project>
