<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>214754</rcn>
  <acronym>DELTA</acronym>
  <objective>DELTA proposes a DR management platform that distributes parts of the Aggregator’s intelligence into lower layers of a novel architecture, based on VPP principles, in order to establish a more easily manageable &amp; computationally efficient DR solution, ultimately aiming to introduce scalability &amp; adaptiveness into the Aggregator’s DR toolkits; the DELTA engine will be able to adopt &amp; integrate multiple strategies &amp; policies provided from its energy market stakeholders, making it authentically modular &amp; future-proof.
DELTA will also deliver a fully autonomous architectural design, enabling end-users to escape the hassle of responding to complex price/incentive-based signals, while facilitating active, aware &amp; engaged prosumers, based on innovative award schemes, a social collaboration platform &amp; enhanced DR visualisation.  Provision of full-scale market &amp; grid services will be made possible by delivering explicit &amp; implicit-based DR elasticity services, while pushing current market regulatory limitations so that they can be surpassed, and satisfying potential grid constraints related to flexibility activation through Multi-Factor Forecasting and Deep Reinforcement Learning Profiling.
Furthermore, DELTA will propose &amp; implement novel multi-agent based, self-learning energy matchmaking algorithms to enable aggregation, segmentation &amp; coordination of several diverse supply &amp; demand  clusters, designed end-to-end using well-known, open protocols (i.e. OpenADR), for increasing interoperability. DELTA will set the milestone for data security in future DR applications by not only implementing novel block-chain methods &amp; authentication mechanisms, but also by making use of Smart Contracts which would further secure &amp; facilitate Aggregators-to-Prosumers transactions.
Two pilots in UK &amp; Cyprus will realise the DELTA concept, covering a wide variety of residential/tertiary loads (&gt;11GWh), RES generation (&gt;14GWh) &amp; energy storage systems (&gt;9MWh) (average annual measurements).</objective>
  <title>Future tamper-proof Demand rEsponse framework through seLf-configured, self-opTimized and collAborative virtual distributed energy nodes</title>
<identifier>H2020LCE2017SGS</identifier>
</project>
