<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210631</rcn>
  <acronym>global5g.org</acronym>
  <objective>Global5G.org addresses the ICT-07 call as the EU led project dedicated to international technology advances in 5G, with a focus on: standardisation, regulations, &amp; market verticals &amp; identifying existing gaps in technology. A Collaboration web platform will showcase &amp; monitor EU &amp; international initiatives and joint R&amp;I programmes with regard to 5G capabilities, standardisation, verticals, &amp; related spectrum.
Global5G.org analyses the sustainability strategies and identifies new business models, considering also private &amp; public investments through pragmatic engagement drivers.
Global5G.org will report on research findings taken to standardisation, testing validation to market uptake with a close eye on the vertical markets selected and mapping them into the right stakeholder groups.
The Global5G.org consortium is domain-skilled &amp; complementary. Trust-IT: Expert SME in communicating ICT innovation, engaging in ICT standards activities, developing ICT tools &amp; go-to-market strategies. Aalto university: A Finnish multidisciplinary university takes an active role in shaping the 5G research agenda; IDC: Premier global provider of market intelligence, consumer technology market research, with over 1,100 analysts across the world; inno TSD: Experts in innovation management &amp; technology transfer, international cooperation &amp; EU &amp; US focus on 5G key to involving multiple stakeholder groups. An influential External Advisory Group (EAG), passionate and competent around 5G technology supports the consortium.
Main Outputs: Continuously updated technology radar &amp; online catalogue &amp; experimental platforms 5G PPP results through a collaboration web platform, a permanent international multi-stakeholder group, 3 market gathering workshops, 3 int. satellite events, 6 webinars, Roadmap on Int. cooperation &amp; standardisation, 3 Strategic Research Agendas; a Common Reference Model for regulations, a sustained, international Business oriented Working Group.</objective>
  <title>Global vision, standardisation  stakeholder engagement in 5G</title>
<identifier>H2020ICT20162</identifier>
</project>
