<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>213229</rcn>
  <acronym>Net4MobilityPlus</acronym>
  <objective>The National Contact Points (NCPs) play an important role in assisting potential applicants and project beneficiaries during their journey through the Horizon 2020 instruments. According to the EC Guide on the NCPs principles, they are responsible for raising awareness about available funding opportunities; advising and training potential applicants in the preparation, submission and follow-up of their grant proposals; providing support during the project execution as well as giving feedback on difficulties in the programme implementation. Thus, the NCPs constitute the main interface between the Programme and the R&amp;I community in Europe and beyond, as well as between them and the EC. Basing on such a position, Net4Mobility+ aims at strengthening the consistency and professionalism of the NCPs for Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions – part of H2020 supporting international and intersectoral mobility and researchers’ career development. The consortium of 19 beneficiaries and 6 associated partners representing the Member States, Associated and Third countries will execute a set of activities tailored to the nature of MSCA and to priorities and capacity of the entire NCPs network, including needs of the “widening countries”. The focus on sharing expertise and good practices, transfer of knowledge to less experienced NCPs, joint support provided on a daily basis, enhancing knowledge and skills, broadening tools and methodology will facilitate the improvement of the overall professionalism of NCP services across and outside Europe. Outcomes of project events (training, twinning, seminars), jointly developed materials (guides, recommendations) and communication and dissemination platform (website, social media) will result in lowering entry barriers for newcomers, simplifying access to MSCA calls and raising the quality of applications. For reaching the project objectives and ensuring the impact, the consortium will work closely, keeping high management and quality standards.</objective>
  <title>Network of the Marie Skłodowska-Curie Action National Contact Points for the mobile scientific and innovation community</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCANCP2017</identifier>
</project>
