<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>209555</rcn>
  <acronym>SCOOP</acronym>
  <objective>The objective of SCOOP is to study the impact of innovative technologies and new funding mechanisms on the role and working practices on investigative journalism. Investigative journalism should play a key role in democracy, but developments in digital media and new technologies (drones, mobile cameras) and changing funding models (crowd sourcing) is transforming this.
Traditional media organisations struggle to adapt to new patterns, work more efficiently with fewer journalists, and identifying new financing models for the resource-intensive practice of investigative journalism.  Studies find that alternative practices and professionals have emerged becoming a marketing strategy for media outlets and a tool to gain market share and new customers in a digital world. But there is a research gap about how investigative journalism is in flux. SCOOP will address this gap with findings on alternative financing models, new and creative use of technology and social media, and new forms for collaborations in the UK.
SCOOP involves a comprehensive ethnographic analysis of how investigative journalists in the UK media are adjusting to the challenges and possibilities created by new technologies; findings from a country with long tradition in investigative journalism will inform journalists, academics, decision makers, and the wider public in countries currently lacking funding and traditions for investigative journalism. I will interview and observe journalists and media actors from four major UK media organizations.
SCOOP will enhance my career as a professional journalist and as an educator of journalists. Cardiff University and HiOA will benefit from my enhanced skills and by the establishment of a virtual centre of investigative journalism to implement the outcomes of SCOOP, this should expand journalism research and training. SCOOP will benefit the media industry and journalism studies in general at a time of profound changes in the profession.</objective>
  <title>Innovation in Investigative Journalism</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAIF2016</identifier>
</project>
