<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207928</rcn>
  <acronym>EO-VAS</acronym>
  <objective>The proposed project (hereafter: EO-VAS project) will RESHAPE Earth Observation Value Chain by BREAKING “DOWNSTREAM” component and significantly SIMPLIFYING development and delivery of Earth Observation Adding Value Services (hereafter: EO VAS).

Project foundation is built around SINERGISE’s award-winning (2016 Copernicus Masters Award) Sentinel Hub Operational Prototype (world-first engine for archiving, processing and distribution of Sentinel data) and GEOVILLE’s extensive set of processing algorithms (applied in over 100 existent EO VAS).

Main project delivery, EO-Toolset has an ambition to become:
- First virtual market place for EO VAS, introducing completely NEW BUSSINESS MODEL in the area of EO services = model, benefiting all participants in EO value chain - from data providers, through service providers to end-users.
- EO VAS innovation hub: fostering development of EO services, becoming a virtual meeting place for the exchange of new ideas and encouraging EO VAS experimenting 
- Virtual business incubator for emerging earth-observation oriented start-ups, that lack the means to commercialise their EO services by themselves. 
- Pre-processing engine for other EO domain services, helping them to reduce pre-processing costs and to turn their attention into domain expertise and higher quality of their products.

EO-VAS will focus on the agriculture and non-life insurance as high revenue entry markets, with the entire optical EO space industry application domain field as revenue market. Conservative investment ROI turning point is 2022 with project’s 15-year’s Net present value of almost € 11,2 MIO, Internal rate of return of 46%. Importantly, due to the setup of EO-VAS enabling customer processing capacities, an significant economic benefit is expected to the entire EO application market, with an estimated leverage effect of 30, putting the effective value of EO-VAS at € 336 MIO.</objective>
  <title>Earth Observation Value Adding Services – Earth Observation Design and Publishing Service</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST220162017</identifier>
</project>
