<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>213220</rcn>
  <acronym>SmartHeat</acronym>
  <objective>SUNTHERM has developed a Worlds first 25 kWh thermal storage compact battery, based on salt hydrate dissolved in mineral oil that enables up to 25 hours of heat displacement (patent pending). SUNTHERM’s game-changer integrated heating system for households - SmartHeat - consists of:
- Smart heating and heat storage, provided by a 25 kWh thermal battery (60 × 60 × 200 cm), coupled to a module of cloudbased management with an online control unit for real-time control over heat management, acting as a buffer in the grid;
- Solar thermal collectors, for higher flexibility and 100% zero-carbon, sustainable heat production;
- Heat pump, smart grid enabled, providing the management of energy loads - peak load shaving -, the storage of excess power during low demand periods for release during peak demand periods - load balancing -, and the integrated optimization of the heat pump operation.
SmartHeat can effectively cover normal family's daily needs for radiators, floor heating or hot water, with a heat release capacity above any other heating unit available, due to its intelligent and huge storage capacity - equivalent to an oil burner in a utility room and delivery of twice the amount of hot water than a conventional hot water tank. By storing energy from the sun - or when the power is cheap - in our unique battery and delivering it when the house requires heating, we will offer the homeowner the opportunity to reduce the heat bill by 75% in comparison to the use of an oil burner, due to 40% increase in efficiency vs. a stand-alone heat pump.
Through the successful development and implementation of SmartHeat WWF award winning technology, SUNTHERM will be in a strong position to exploit a market worth at 34.5 billion € and enhance its profitability by the stream of the sales, with an expected cumulated turnover of 83 million €, 5 years after project completion.</objective>
  <title>SmartHeat – An eco-innovative solution towards zero-carbon household heating</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST220162017</identifier>
</project>
