<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210629</rcn>
  <acronym>EuConNeCts3</acronym>
  <objective>It is the purpose of EuConNeCts3, a Supporting Action, to organise the following 2 editions, 2018 and 2019, of the EC sponsored conference in the area of communication networks and systems (EuCNC - European Conference on Networks and Communications), continuing the successful organisation of this conference since 2014.  EuCNC will continue to serve as a technical and scientific conference for researchers, namely European ones, to show their work in the area of Telecommunications, focusing on communication networks and systems, and also reaching services and applications.  The conference will not be restricted to European researchers, rather aiming at attracting others from all the other regions in the world.  It will also serve as a showcase for the work developed by projects co-financed by the EC, namely those arising from H2020 calls, and more specifically, those addressing 5G and beyond.  Nonetheless, it also aims at attracting works in the area of communication networks and systems from other objectives.  EuCNC will: 1) be a European conference, but with a large international dimension; 2) showcase the R&amp;D activities performed within EC programmes, directly and indirectly; 3) showcase the cooperation in R&amp;D between European organisations and worldwide ones; 4) bridge between academia / research centres and industry; 5) coordinate its goals with the EC and the main European players; 6) be a high-quality R&amp;D conference; 7) be a well-recognised conference in Telecommunications; 8) provide a forum for the presentation of state-of-the-art technology, in both theoretical and experimental forms; 9) communicate the research results to the wide audience of the general public; 10) foster the participation of both established researchers and students, as well as industry members from various areas; 11) be a transparent and not-for-profit conference; 12) positively differentiate itself from other conferences, which will be achieved by reaching all previous objectives.</objective>
  <title>European Conferences on Networks and Communications (EuCNC)</title>
<identifier>H2020ICT20162</identifier>
</project>
