<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196652</rcn>
  <acronym>GULWESS-PROP</acronym>
  <objective>GULWESS-PROP overall innovation project aims at designing a commercial solution of efficient on-board energy storage for electrically propelled vehicles. The main goal is to substitute on-board electrical batteries and hydrogen storage.

Drage&amp;Mate International has a patented in-situ on-demand hydrogen generation process able to increase the total gravimetric energy density of the system. This improvement allows existing vehicles to multiply by 2 or even by 7 their existing range which means a very profitable new opportunity to market.

The current study will analyse how to progress to a commercial profitable product. To do that, GULWESS-PROP will validate the feasibility (technical, economic and operational) of the development and define a preliminary Business Plan.
The goal is to transform the prototype solution which is currently in a TRL6 development stage to TRL9 market commercial product by the end of phase 2.

Once GULWESS-PROP will be validated, a business chance will start-up to supply such technology to unmanned vehicles. In the close future similar system could be used in manned vehicles, and all kind of space vehicles. With this approach GULWESS-PROP will, at the end, lead a major impact within the decarbonised transportation goals in Europe. 

Although the lightweight hydrogen storage segment counts with several competitors, GULWESS-PROP has a competitive advantage over the rest of solutions related to the user experience: the final users consider that is easier to operate thanks to reactor cartridge refillable concept. 

Drage&amp;Mate International is a Technology-Based high innovative company with proven track record within the hydrogen generation market; and with enough experience and ambition to turn the innovation of GULWESS-PROP into a sustainable product.</objective>
  <title>Green Ultra Light Weight Energy Storage System for Propulsion</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
