<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207958</rcn>
  <acronym>Logist-IoT</acronym>
  <objective>Tertium technology has a successful track of record in developing and commercializing sensing devices that integrate and
enhance business processes. More than 21,000 sold products support Tertium’s success, quality and reliability in previous
innovative products. The introduction of Logist-IoT into the market is the result of our latest research efforts to advance in our
strategic business line “internet of things on the road”. Growth is supported by strong distribution partnerships, such as Tom
Tom telematics, which opens up an enormous market for initial introduction of our newly developed solutions; however, it
also represents a key opportunity for the company to progressively transition from hardware manufacturer to a
comprehensive service provider. Logist-IoT is a Mobile SensorToCloud platform that provides real-time monitoring of the
conditions of the delivery (temperature, humidity and sealed doors) providing a tool to protect revenues (by checking of state
of preservation), support compliance with cold chain and other transport regulations (by providing automatic feed of data)
and increase efficiency (by reducing energy consumption, anticipating weak areas and pinpointing operational inefficiencies).
The Logist-IoT project was triggered by the request from our client base, most specifically by companies in the large-scale
distribution. It allowed us to develop a scalable solution adapted to our end user needs. The versatility of our IoT sensors
enables an innovative business model based on a leasing or pay-per-use service rather than an upfront investment,
facilitating adoption in the industry. From the initial assessments carried out with pilot customers, in the food and
pharmaceutical industries, we estimate benefits that range 10 times to 100 times the cost of services. The attractiveness of
our value proposition has been validated with the market acceptance of the first version of our platform,operational in over
1000 vehicles of distribution companies.</objective>
  <title>SensorToCloud Technologies for Loss Prevention and Smart “Last Mile” Logistics Operations</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
