<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>208315</rcn>
  <acronym>INFRAVEC2</acronym>
  <objective>The overall objective of the Infravec2 project is to integrate key specialized research facilities necessary for European excellence in insect vector biology, to open the infrastructure for European access, and to develop new vector control measures targeting the greatest threats to human health and animal industries. Infravec2 is an Advanced Community, following a four-year Starting Community lifecycle (FP7 Infravec1). Lack of access to key infrastructures limits European vector research and impedes development of vector control measures. Insect vectors transmit parasitic diseases such as malaria and leishmaniasis, and viral infections such as chikungunya, dengue, Zika, Japanese encephalitis and yellow fever. Vector-borne diseases, which have historically been a problem of tropical countries, now represent a threat for temperate regions of the world including much of Europe. The 24 consortium partners, including 4 commercial companies, hold the major European biosecure insectaries for experimental infection and containment of insect vectors under Containment Level 2 and 3 (CL2/CL3) conditions, other key insect vector facilities, and include front-line field sites in Africa, the Pacific, and the Americas. Infravec2 will implement comparable standards across the secure insectary facilities as a world first, improving exploitation of European vector infrastructures for research and public health, and will develop other innovative methodologies and technologies. Networking activities will assure that the project achieves full impact, producing a step change in European vector biology research and the product pipeline, and consolidating European global leadership in insect vectors. The goal of the Infravec2 project is to build a durable European infrastructure to control insect vector-borne disease, including with power to predict and prevent the inevitable next epidemic outbreak in advance.</objective>
  <title>Research Infrastructures for the control of vector-borne diseases</title>
<identifier>H2020INFRAIA20161</identifier>
</project>
