<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207705</rcn>
  <acronym>CEBRABIC</acronym>
  <objective>This CSA intends to establish and deploy the Centre for Europe-Brazil Business Innovation Cooperation (CEBRABIC). The Centre will connect and support European Research &amp; Innovation &amp; Business (R&amp;I&amp;B) organizations in the Brazilian market, while strengthening the European Union’s position as a world leader in Science, Technology and Innovation. The Centre will achieve these goals by sustainably offering a diverse set of services, including networking and partnering; business consultancy; pooling and sharing resources; investment attraction; capacity building and awareness raising.
The proposed methodology for setting up CEBRABIC relies upon a pillar-based approach – each corresponding to different chapters of a Business Plan: Strategic pillar (market analysis – Work Package (WP) 1 and strategic planning (WP2)); Marketing pillar (WP3); Operational pillar (WP4); and Financial pillar (WP5). The business model implementation (WP6) and the monitoring and evaluation (WP7) are also further pillars in the CEBRABIC methodological approach.
The implementation of CEBRABIC will follow a three-staged strategy: the planning stage (from M1 to M12), in which the Centre’s business model (WP1-WP5) will be developed; the piloting stage (M12 to M24), focused on delivering services on an experimental basis (WP6); and the full implementation stage (M24-M48), in which CEBRABIC will be established as an independent legal entity and as a financially self-sustainable organization.
As an open and dynamic Centre, CEBRABIC will build upon synergies and complementarities with relevant R&amp;I&amp;B organizations, particularly with European R&amp;I&amp;B organizations with presence in Brazil and SENAI Innovation Institutes, aiming to increase, diversify and consolidate the CEBRABIC service demand and offer. 
The project is implemented by a partnership of 12 organizations, led by Fraunhofer Gesellschaft, and including leading R&amp;I&amp;B organizations from Brazil, Portugal, Spain, Austria, Belgium, Hungary and Turkey.</objective>
  <title>Centre for Europe-Brazil Business and Innovation Cooperation</title>
<identifier>H2020SC6ENGGLOBALLY20161</identifier>
</project>
