<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207095</rcn>
  <acronym>CORE</acronym>
  <objective>From banking to travel, almost everything today is done via digital information and the Internet. One notable exception is
academic diplomas, most of which are still paper based. Academic records generation, issue and exchange by education
providers involves slow, costly and forgery-susceptible processes with very low control over the protection of the information
released. Digitary CORE is a web service that allows education providers to securely issue, certify and share digital
academic records online eliminating the hassle associated with having to produce and manage original paper documents.
This streamlined system enables higher education institutions (HEIs) to reduce administrative costs, protect academic
brands, increase administrative efficiency, eliminate credential fraud and improve service levels for students and graduates.
CORE represents the implementation of the original Digitary workflow, that is already on the market and whose
demonstration has been proved in several education systems. Ten years after Digitary’s world-first implementation of
digitally signed Degree Certificates at the University of Limerick, almost a million online records have been issued by
international institutions via Digitary branded platform. After having released the cloud-implemented platform (end of 2015)
and integrated their software with foreign service providers, Digitary now aim at promoting CORE to verify credentials from
any University in the world. Accomplished Phase 2 objectives - demonstration of the implemented technology and market
replication – will pave the way to increase Digitary visibility and then attract customers’ attention. This, in turn, will be crucial
for further strategic activities fostering the industrial-scale commercialization of CORE and developing new services that
enhance the user-experience.</objective>
  <title>An innovative web-service to securely issue, store and verify online academic credentials</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
