<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>198862</rcn>
  <acronym>RoadWriter</acronym>
  <objective>Our project is aiming to develop a computer-aided Road Marking Machine-RoadWriter being able to print any kind of sign/graphic of road markings which are generated from a computer and appropriate to standards without using any template or any other tool. The signs in road marking are still applied manually by using some templates or some mechanic tools which needs lots of work force and time. The lack of digitalization of road marking applications is providing a great business opportunity with our disruptive innovation.
The initial research for RoadWriter has been funded by TUBİTAK (Scientific and Technological Research Council of Turkey), which funds the research projects in Turkey that have an excellent research infrastructure and big market potential. Our technology was demonstrated and approved as TRL6 in an industrially relevant environment at the helm of specialized academicians assigned by TUBITAK. 
The RoadWriter project will transform the existing methods to a new digital way for more precision, less work force and standardized marking worldwide. Road marking is a basic need for each country, especially for technologically advanced ones such as EU member countries, USA and Japan. RoadWriter has a high volume market of over 400 million EUR market size with a high growth rate of 5-10%.
The target users of the RoadWriter are highway directorates, municipalities, airports, parking areas, hospitals, malls, defense industry, everywhere where horizontal marking is needed.
Its innovative aspects are;
• Computer-aided machine
• Ability to print at full width of standard traffic lane and unlimited length
• Autonomous workout as long as needed
• Standardization of signs and graphics library
The feasibility study that will be completed in Phase 1 will mainly cover;
• Market and stakeholder research
• IPR management
• Developing the embedded and interface software of the machine
• Preparing user-friendly library of standard traffic signs and graphics
• Detailed Business Plan</objective>
  <title>Computer-aided road marking machine - RoadWriter</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12015</identifier>
</project>
