<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205936</rcn>
  <acronym>inSSIght</acronym>
  <objective>The objective of the proposed CSA is to support and complement R&amp;I activities in Smart Systems Integration (SSI) by structuring industrial cooperation and facilitating end-user adoption for the next generations of miniaturised smart objects and systems.
Previous CSAs have revealed the immense breadth of SSI in its technology demands, its application sectors, its business ramifications, its provider and user communities, and have commenced the task of joining all these aspects for concerted action. They have also developed support tools, whose proven value can continue to be instrumental in the new CSA.
Building on the above and supporting the strategic activities of EPoSS, the role for inSSIght is to deepen and implant this understanding through a cadre of influential partners from SSI-related clusters, research institutes and industries who will define and encourage actions to unlock and exploit innovation opportunities, provide practice-oriented support to the SSI ecosystem, underline the vital position of SSI as a Key Enabling Technology for competitive advantage and future innovation, and give credit to their enabling role as building blocks in sectors with high potential for growth and high return on investment, such as IoT, Industry 4.0, electric mobility, automated driving, smart medical devices etc.
Very practically, inSSIght 
• organises 4 thematic conferences, two of which on MNBS, 7 demonstration sessions, 2 brokerage events, 11 expert and information workshops and 11 webinars
• publishes 5 White Papers on Customised Innovation Priorities
• leads a marketing campaign for SSI based on a trademark
inSSIght addresses all 5 activities required in the scope description of ICT-03-2016b, considering them as inseparable and most efficiently tackled in a single concerted action.</objective>
  <title>In-depth support for innovation and exploitation in Smart Systems Integration</title>
<identifier>H2020ICT20161</identifier>
</project>
