<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207430</rcn>
  <acronym>INFRAFRONTIER2020</acronym>
  <objective>The INFRAFRONTIER RI integrates European Mouse Clinics and the European Mouse Mutant Archive with the common goal to ensure access to mouse models for basic research of human health and disease, and to translate this knowledge into therapeutic approaches for the benefit of the European society. 

The expanded INFRAFRONTIER2020 network, coordinated by the INFRAFRONTIER GmbH, includes 3 SMEs and is strategically responding to the INFRADEV3 call with aligned objectives to advance the long-term sustainability which are 1) development of business models and a stable legal framework; 2) raise awareness of the INFRAFRONTIER RI; 3) provide bespoke services aligned with user demands; 4) promote best practices in mouse phenogenomics; 5) enhance robustness of the INFRAFRONTIER IT infrastructure and use of the EMMA strain resource; and 6) improve business processes. Towards achieving these objectives key INFRAFRONTIER2020 project deliverables are:
  
• INFRAFRONTIER Business Plan2.0, and business models for all services
• Stable legal framework built on the INFRAFRONTIER legal entity
• INFRAFRONTIER annual stakeholder conferences 
• Customised mouse model and secondary phenotyping pilot services  
• INFRAFRONTIER advanced training schools in mouse phenogenomics
• Reengineered EMMA Database2.0 system
• Annotated mouse models of human diseases
• Quality management system for the legal entity

INFRAFRONTIER2020 will 1) enhance the sustainable operation of the INFRAFRONTIER RI; 2) continue to structure the ERA, 3) foster innovation, and 4) address major societal challenges in human health by customised service pilots supporting research into common and rare diseases. A sustainable INFRAFRONTIER RI will ensure the quality of deposited mice and support the reproducibility of biological results. Outreach efforts will raise awareness of resources and services and facilitate sustainable engagement with industry and global consortia such as the International Mouse Phenotyping Consortium.</objective>
  <title>Towards enduring mouse resources and services advancing research into human health and disease</title>
<identifier>H2020INFRADEV20161</identifier>
</project>
