<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>209454</rcn>
  <acronym>PERISCOPE</acronym>
  <objective>Pertussis vaccines have been very successful in reducing the global burden of pertussis-related disease. However, in the last decade there has been a rise in pertussis incidence, particularly in vaccinated adolescents and adults in industrialized countries. The increased circulation of B. pertussis (Bp) constitutes a risk for transmission to vulnerable infants and older adults. Additionally, immunity in humans has been shown to wane rapidly after immunization with pertussis vaccines, especially with acellular pertussis (aP) vaccines, suggesting that the improved reactogenicity profile of aP compared to whole cell pertussis vaccines, may be accompanied by differences in duration of immunity. The key objectives of PERISCOPE are to 1. identify biomarkers of protection against Bp colonization and disease; 2. foster scientific innovation and rebuild the ecosystem and technical infrastructure needed in Europe to allow the future evaluation of novel pertussis vaccine candidates and 3. improve understanding of the pathogenesis of Bp infection and its potential impact on the recently observed changes in pertussis epidemiology. To reach these objectives, PERISCOPE brings together a selected group of internationally recognized public and EFPIA partners with strong expertise in clinical trials, immunology, molecular microbiology, human and animal challenge models and bioinformatics. We will initiate a series of (pre)clinical studies and develop harmonized human and animal challenge models, standardized assays and cutting-edge techniques to unravel the innate and adaptive responses to Bp. This will allow us to identify biomarkers of protection and durable immunity. PERISCOPE will thus facilitate the accelerated development and registration of novel pertussis vaccines and/or guide optimal use of vaccination strategies. The introduction of improved pertussis vaccines will help to reduce the global burden of pertussis.</objective>
  <title>PERtussIS COrrelates of Protection Europe</title>
<identifier>H2020JTIIMI2201503twostage</identifier>
</project>
