<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>214785</rcn>
  <acronym>FODIAC</acronym>
  <objective>FODIAC aims to develop a dietary solution to tackle type 2 diabetes and cognitive dysfunction of the elderly. FODIAC will enhance the quality of R&amp;I in Europe, promoting cooperation along the Food Value Chain. This is achieved through advanced international, intersectoral, cooperation between 7 academic and 8 industry partners. For this purpose, FODIAC assembles a European multi/interdisciplinary consortium, composed of partners in 5 countries that provide expertise in: extraction and purification of bioactive molecules, nanotechnology, nano/micro-encapsulation, toxicology, nutrition, biomarkers, clinical trial management. 
Rationale: lack of knowledge sharing among academia and industry  acts as a barrier for the development of functional foods for the elderly, who represent one of the fastest-growing population segments worldwide. 
Approach and Outcomes: FODIAC coordinates the actions of individual partners, academic and industrial, using Exchange of Staff as a tool to capitalize on complementary competences to: i) conduct joint research; ii) protect the Intellectual Property based on this research; iii) foster the transference of the generated knowledge, skills, and technology to the industrial sector; and iv) exploit research output to the benefit of society. FODIAC’s outcomes will include: i) an increase in the R&amp;I capacity among participating partners; ii) boosting of knowledge transfer of emerging micro/nano-biotechnologies from academia to industry, to develop cost-effective processes; iii) commercialization of new functional ingredients and functional foods containing antidiabetic and cognitive-enhancing bioactive molecules; iv) acceleration of the development of dietary recommendations and interventions based on those products, to improve the quality of life of the elderly; iv) a sustainable research network of academic and industrial partners and v) the leveraging of career perspectives of individual researchers, both in and outside academic institution.</objective>
  <title>Foods for diabetes and cognition</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCARISE2017</identifier>
</project>
