<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>198246</rcn>
  <acronym>EEN H2020</acronym>
  <objective>"The Enterprise Europe Network "Normandie-Picardie" consortium is composed of the 5 following partners:
• CCI Basse-Normandie
• CCI Haute-Normandie
• CCI Picardie
• MIRIADE (regional agency for innovation in Basse-Normandie)
• SEINARI (regional agency for innovation in Haute-Normandie)
To act complementarily with the COSME Enterprise Europe Network "Normandie-Picardie" project, the consortium will set up a Horizon 2020 action called “Enhancing the innovation management capacity of SMEs”. This action should help companies of the Normandy-Picardy area to organise their innovation strategy in order to overcome the barriers to the emergence of innovative projects. 
This specific action will be divided into two main activities (Work packages). The first one called “Key Account Management” (KAM) will target the beneficiaries of the SME Instrument. The Key Account Managers (innovation experts of the consortium) will ensure that the beneficiaries receive the most appropriate services to underscore the successful and profitable exploitation of their innovation project. They will be in charge of helping SMEs to select their coach and will ensure there is no conflict between the coach and the SMEs all along the coaching phase.
The second one called “enhancing SME innovation management capacity” (EIMC) will target SMEs with significant innovation activities and a high potential of internationalization. The consortium advisors will deliver a quality management assessment and support service to conduct innovation processes in a more effective way. They will be in charge of assessing innovation management capacity of the company and to develop an action plan with the support of an appropriate diagnostic tool. 
Both activities of the consortium should complement each other’s and offer the best integrated support to SMEs on two different growth factors: innovation and internationalization. 
The consortium plans to deliver both services to a total number of 51 companies in 2015-2016."</objective>
  <title>Enhancing innovation management capacity of SMEs under H2020 programme in the Enterprise Europe Network «Normandie-Picardie»</title>
<identifier>H2020Adhoc201420</identifier>
</project>
