<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211677</rcn>
  <acronym>MAESTRO</acronym>
  <objective>The European Training Network MAESTRO (MAking pErovskiteS TRuly explOitable) will generate new skills, knowledge and innovation in the exploitation of perovskite materials in solar power and efficient lighting through establishing exploitation paths for perovskite devices in an integrated unitary approach. MAESTRO is an intersectoral and multidisciplinary network of 10 academic and 7 industrial beneficiaries from 8 EU and Associated countries, including 2 countries in the EU-13. It focusses on perovskite semiconductors, a material shown in the last 4 years to have a major impact on solar power and potentially also in display technology. Our research aims to make perovskite based devices commercially viable.  MAESTRO offers broad skills development and experience of cross sector research to 15 Early Stage Researchers, ESRs. Training is provided in (i) science and technology across physics, chemistry, materials science, electrical engineering, in two major application areas, solar cells and light emitting diodes, and other uses such as lasers and photodiodes; (ii) exploitation from laboratory to fabrication; (iii) transferable skills of communication, information technology, organization, planning, teamwork, leadership; (iv) skills needed for innovation, such as understanding markets, product life cycles, business models, return on investment. Gender aspects are addressed through supervisors, mentors and training. The research undertaken by MAESTRO will teach the ESRs how to deal with complexities and uncertainties, making them very broad and highly adaptable. Their PhDs will position them to be comfortable in both corporate and academic worlds. They will be able to seek careers that are rewarding professionally and financially, through career paths in self-employment, finance, consultancy, contracting, engineering, computer science, production</objective>
  <title>MAking pErovskiteS TRuly explOitable</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2017</identifier>
</project>
