<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205701</rcn>
  <acronym>4PRIMA</acronym>
  <objective>The 4PRIMA Coordination and Support Action will create the bases and will develop a set of activities aimed at supporting the establishment of a long-term, well-structured and integrated partnership for research and innovation (R&amp;I) on food systems and water resources, among countries from both sides of the Mediterranean Sea (“PRIMA Initiative”). In order to enable a sustainable development in this area, 4PRIMA will facilitate the establishment of favourable and stable conditions for a reinforced international cooperation on food systems and water research, based on a better coordination, collective ownership of R&amp;I programmes and, consequently, clear and tangible mutual benefits.
4PRIMA will develop a Strategic Research and Innovation Agenda (SRIA) and an associated implementation plan, as a result of an extensive participatory process that will target a critical mass of key players at international level and all relevant stakeholders of the food and water sectors. To achieve this main objective, 4PRIMA will take advantage of a wide portfolio of results and relationship generated in previous and on-going EU projects, as well as it will seek cooperation between EU and Mediterranean Partner Countries (MPCs), in coherence with the activities of the Strategic Forum for International Cooperation. 
Given the strategic relevance of an appropriate development and uptake of the SRIA to establish a long lasting partnership in the region, 4PRIMA science diplomacy actions will be essential to ensure the support to R&amp;I policy dialogue addressing sensitive challenges between EU and MPCs. Moreover, in order to maximise its expected impact, 4PRIMA project will explore avenues for awareness raising and development of strategic alliances with key stakeholders, including EU, AC and MPCs countries that did not take part to the PRIMA joint programming process, with the goal to enlarge the participation to the “PRIMA Initiative”.</objective>
  <title>Partnership for Research and Innovation in the Mediterranean Area</title>
<identifier>H2020SC52016OneStageA</identifier>
</project>
