<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211681</rcn>
  <acronym>mCBEEs</acronym>
  <objective>mCBEEs Innovative Training Network is a joint venture between academy and industry with a primary goal to train young researchers in the field of corrosion and corrosion protection of micro- and nanodevices. The network focuses on the study of corrosion mechanisms beyond microscale of components in miniaturized systems in different environments using localized techniques, and the development of multifunctional protective coatings to increase the long-term durability of such components. Corrosion phenomena occurring in micro- and nanodimensional components can develop in a completely different path than in their bulk counterparts and corrosion might influence the functional properties of small components in a much more severe manner. Three main strategic fields where corrosion could seriously compromise the performance of micro- or nanodevices have been identified: biotechnology (micro/nano-robotic implants, micro/nano-electrodes for recording and stimulating neuronal activity, or micro-featured prosthesis implants); electronics (micro/nano-components in electronic boards, magnetooptical thin films, multiferroic micro/nano-devices); and energy technology (metallic foam-based micro- and nanostructured electrodes, self-standing nanoarchitectures). Several disciplines (physics, electrochemistry, engineering, biology and robotics) converge to provide a multidisciplinary approach to accomplish mCBEEs goals. The ITN brings together 15 beneficiaries and 3 partners including 4 research institutes and 4 private companies belonging to 9 EU Member states, and to 2 associated states (Switzerland, Turkey). The Consortium complementarity will enable a high-level, multifaceted educational programme, where specials efforts will be done to bridge fundamental research with industrial applications. The educational programme is integrated with training in soft skills and aims at providing a network of highly qualified researchers able to tackle challenges both in Academia and Industry.</objective>
  <title>Advanced integrative solutions to Corrosion problems beyond micro–scale: towards long-termdurability of miniaturized Biomedical, Electronic and Energy systems</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2017</identifier>
</project>
