<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>208026</rcn>
  <acronym>InnSpect IoT</acronym>
  <objective>We are adapting InnSpect to be able to test connected devices and the next generation of IoT equipment such as smart 
home (fridge, washing machine, air conditioning and home security. This new product is called InnSpect IoT. InnSpect IoT is 
a Quality of Experience solution, based on the InnSpect product that provides automated testing with a graphical user 
interface (used for final quality testing at the factory for the produced equipment), that replicates user interactions on Set-Top 
Boxes, mobile devices, and IoT devices.  
Our overall objective of for the later Phase II project is to scale-up the breakthrough InnSpect testing solution to be able to 
test connected IoT devices as well, i.e. to finalize the InnSpect IoT product and to bring it to market. The expected outcome 
of the Phase II project is a miniaturized, scaled-up and marketable InnSpect IoT product that can be marketed right after the 
project ends.  
The specific objectives of Phase I Feasibility include: Technological Feasibility Study, Market Assessment, Business Model 
Assessment, Risk Assessment, IP Assessment, Work Plan for Phase II, Business Plan 
InnSpect IoT answers to the market gap of a simple automated testing solution capable of performing cross device testing 
that anyone can manage. When we worked on InnSpect, we learned a lot from the major failures and benefits of the different 
automated testing solutions already established on the market, which has allowed us to create a solution better prepared to 
follow new market trends. The InnSpect architecture was developed with scalability and flexibility in mind. Time to market is 
of the essence, and being able to put the first flag is key, InnSpect is well prepared in terms of structure and with the right 
amount of resources. 
At InnoWave, we see InnSpect IoT as the next logical step for our business as it offers major growth potential for us. We will 
start sales in Portugal, then expand to all of Europe and eventually beyond that</objective>
  <title>Providing Quality of Experience Through Automated Testing of Devices</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
