<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>214294</rcn>
  <acronym>One Health EJP</acronym>
  <objective>The One Health concept recognizes that the human health is tightly connected to the health of animals and the environment, i.e. that animal feed, human food, animal and human health, and environmental contamination are closely linked. These are the main focus of our European joint programme (EJP). One reference laboratory from the public health / medicine domain and one reference laboratory from the food / veterinary domain are associated within a network of 41 European laboratories and research centers, distributed in 19 participating member states, with the aim to reach significant advances in the fields of foodborne zoonoses (FBZ), antimicrobial resistance (AMR) and emerging threats (ET) within a global One Health approach. Most of these laboratories have reference responsibilities, representing a sustainable framework for an integrated research community. Consistent with the “Prevent-Detect-Respond” concept, the One Health EJP aims at reinforcing collaboration between institutes by enhancing transdisciplinary cooperation and integration of activities by means of dedicated Joint Research Projects, Joint Integrative Project and through education and training in the fields of FBZ, AMR and ET. While alignment and harmonization with on-going EC-funded research project will also be considered, deliverables from the EJP activities should feed the approach of evidence based risk assessment and therefore the management of risks by the competent national authorities. Therefore, it is of utmost importance to efficiently and regularly updated the dissemination of knowledge between the research community and major International and European stakeholders, national authorities and further afield.
The One Health EJP will also develop sustainable programs and projects beyond the lifetime of the EJP, through the production of a Strategic Research and Innovation Agenda (2021-2030) and a European P2P One Health Cooperative Joint Initiative.</objective>
  <title>Promoting One Health in Europe through joint actions on foodborne zoonoses, antimicrobial resistance and emerging microbiological hazards.</title>
<identifier>H2020SFS20171</identifier>
</project>
