<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211913</rcn>
  <acronym>ZULF</acronym>
  <objective>Nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) is a powerful technique employed in many areas of modern science and industry. While a seemingly indispensable element of NMR is a strong (&gt;5 T) magnetic field, recent progress in physics and chemistry have enabled detection of NMR signals at ultra-low and truly zero magnetic fields. This completely reverses conditions under which spin-dynamics are investigated and gives access to information unavailable in conventional NMR. A secondary horizon is microscopic low-field magnetic sensors that probe NMR signals of a single molecule, and provide interesting information about molecular dynamics and structures not accessible with conventional NMR. The address of specific molecular sites is a step towards realizing single-molecule quantum information storage.

In project ZULF, for the first time, we plan to connect experts of non-conventional NMR to create a network of zero- and ultra-low-field (ZULF) NMR science. We will gather and synergize scientists working on NMR J-spectroscopy, NMR hyperpolarization, ultra-precise and small-scale magnetometry to enhance the field and train a new generation of NMR researchers. Close collaboration with industry will address important challenges of modern NMR. Through frequent meetings, secondments, workshops, and a summer school the early-stage researchers (ESRs) will receive a unique training program on the most modern and advanced aspects of ZULF NMR that is unavailable in any current university course. The network covers a diverse range of projects aimed at bringing the technique to the next level, including spectrometer development, single-molecule detection, analytical chemistry, medical contrast agent imaging and exotic-physics searches.</objective>
  <title>Zero and ultra-low field nuclear magnetic resonance</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2017</identifier>
</project>
