<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206256</rcn>
  <acronym>PJ03b SAFE</acronym>
  <objective>Safety is aviation’s top priority. To work for even safer airports, Project 03b SAFE will define, consolidate and validate additional safety bareers to mitigate the risks of runway incursion, runway excursion and more generally the risk of incidents and accidents involving aircraft at the airport. They will be declined into four Solutions:

Solution ‘Enhanced airport safety support tools for controllers’ will provide Air Traffic Controllers with means to prevent the delivery of conflicting clearances and detect non-conformance to clearances on the entire airport.

Solution ‘Conformance monitoring alerts for pilots’ will warn pilots when an inconsistency between the aircraft behaviour with either ATC Clearance or procedure is detected. 

Solution ‘Traffic alerts for pilots for airport operations’ is a key feature to significantly decrease the risk of collision with any mobile on runway and taxiways, improving safety on airport surface. 

Solution ‘Safety support tools for avoiding runway excursions’ will address the most frequent type of runway safety accident (22% of all accidents over the 2010-2014 period according to IATA Safety Report). The work will focus on how the risk of runway excursion can be mitigated by on-board and ground systems that could warn pilots, controllers or both when appropriate. This solution requires a better knowledge of runway braking conditions, and can improve the runway capacity and environmental aspects through a better management of decontamination operations. 

Dedicated tasks to support standardization activities will be performed in each solution when appropriate.
PJ03b Consortium involves key stakeholders of Airborne Industry, Ground ATM Industry, Service Providers (ATM and Airports), Aerospace Research and EUROCONTROL. Those members of the SJU will cooperate for implementing SESAR 2020 in an efficient, open and timely manner, providing a wide range of expertise and committing together to deliver high-quality results.</objective>
  <title>Airport Safety Nets</title>
<identifier>H2020SESAR20152</identifier>
</project>
