<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205800</rcn>
  <acronym>Fundsphere Terms</acronym>
  <objective>The continued use of a paper-based Contract Lifecycle Process in the Asset Management Industry creates needless inefficiencies, errors, risk and limitations. Asset Managers using state-of-the-art spreadsheets and document assembly tools find their paper chaos transformed into even bigger digital chaos without meaningful improvement of current methods. Furthermore, recent financial regulations (MiFID II in EU, RDR in UK, Dodd-Frank Act in USA) reinforce the need for disruptive technologies to stay competitive in the new investor environment. 
Metrosoft is set to revolutionize the way the agreements are created and managed in the Asset Management Industry. Fundsphere Terms is a native digital platform that creates, manages and exchanges legal agreements covering Terms of Business between the Sell Side and the Buy Side in a structured database solution. The benefits of such dematerialisation have been demonstrated in the successfully finalised Phase 1 Feasibility Study: Fundsphere Terms disrupts current contract creation by simplifying the workflow and speeding up the process from months to weeks and in the case of amendments from weeks to a single day.
The need for Fundsphere Terms was confirmed by key finance firms during the two biggest sectorial conferences in Luxembourg and Hong Kong (ALFI, ITAS) and Key Opinion Leaders who are strong supporters of industry dematerialisation. To fully exploit this EU-based technology, we will drive growth through B2B model and target the top 400 Assets Manager decision-makers and industry influencers. Later growth will be by “snowball effect” (counterparties of Assets Managers). By bringing Fundsphere Terms into the rapidly growing market we estimate to attract min. ≥ 25% of the global Asset Managers, which means volume of approx. +/-20 customers annually, with an estimated revenue €17.4mln after 5 years.</objective>
  <title>Disruptive Regulatory Technology for Asset Management Industry. FinTech company changes the global Asset Industry forever</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST220162017</identifier>
</project>
