<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>193207</rcn>
  <acronym>RESSQUA</acronym>
  <objective>‘Researchers Square’ is designed to increase the awareness of research as a solution to the numerous challenges faced by people all around the world and mainly in Europe. The idea of the project, ‘Better Living through Science: from Social Sciences and Humanities to Maths and Technology’, has been conceived in times of crisis, a moment where becomes clearer that we must join efforts to find innovative solutions to encourage young people’s interest in research. It responds also to the challenge of building bridges between researchers and general public, showing that science could give answer to the societal challenges that we are facing in Europe.

The project is the third experience of Andalusia in the ERN. Fundación Descubre will coordinate this project, based in its experience through the last 5 years working with relevant projects in Spain and in its consortium experience in the two editions of this project in Andalusia. The consortium is composed by eight Andalusian universities, the Spanish National Research Council (CSIC), the Ministry of Economy, Innovation, Science and Employment (CEICE), the Institute for Agricultural and Fisheries Research and Training (IFAPA) and two of the most important botanical institutions, all dedicated to higher education, research and science popularization in Andalusia.

The project's major strength is the high mobilization of researchers, the support and involvement of Municipalities and the numerous activities taking place on main busy streets and historical buildings of the eight Andalusian cities, which will have a high social impact in the region. Given the project’s dimensions, it will be developed with a high mobilization of personnel and technical resources and with the collaboration of the local institutions, NGOs, private companies, teachers and civil associations.
The communication campaign aims at reach every third citizen of Andalusia, and with activities in city-center venues more than 53.000 attendees are expected.</objective>
  <title>RESEARCHERS SQUARE</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCANIGHT2014</identifier>
</project>
