<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>200737</rcn>
  <acronym>ANaPSyS</acronym>
  <objective>"Traditionally, natural products are classified into "natural product families". Within a family all congeners display specific structure elements, owing to their common biosynthetic pathway. This suggests a bio-inspired or "collective synthesis", as has been devised by D: W. MacMillan. However, a biosynthetic pathway is confined to these structure elements, thus limiting synthesis with regard to structure diversification. In this research proposal the applicant exemplarily devises a strategic concept to overcome these limitations, by replacing the dogma of "retrosynthetic analysis" with "structure pattern recognition". This concept is termed "Artificial Natural Product Systems Synthesis — ANaPSyS", and aims to supersede the current "logic of chemical synthesis" as a standard practice in this field.
ANaPSyS exclusively categorizes natural products based on structural relationships — regardless of biogenetic origin. The structure pattern analysis groups natural products according to their shared core structure, and thereof creates a common precursor called "privileged intermediate (PI)". This intermediate is resembled in each of these natural products and is architecturally less complex. As a result every member of this natural product group can originate from a different natural product family and is obtained via this "privileged intermediate", which serves as basis for the artificial synthetic network.
With ANaPSyS a synthetic route is not restricted to a single target structure anymore (as in conventional synthesis). In comparison with bio-inspired synthesis, which is limited to a single natural product family, ANaPSyS enables the synthesis of a whole set of natural product families. With every synthesis accomplished, the network is upgraded — hence diversification leads to a rise in revenue. As a consequence, synthetic efficiency is drastically enhanced, therefore profoundly boosting and facilitating lead structure development."</objective>
  <title>Artificial Natural Products System Synthesis</title>
<identifier>ERC2015STG</identifier>
</project>
