<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>209863</rcn>
  <acronym>INNODIA</acronym>
  <objective>Preclinical type 1 diabetes (T1D) research has made important advances in recent years, but less progress has been made in translating findings from in vitro and animal models into effective clinical interventions. INNODIA aims to achieve a break-through in the way in which we study T1D to enable us to move closer towards prevention and cure of T1D. To this end, INNODIA joins together the leading European experts from the fields of basic and clinical T1D research, four leading pharmaceutical companies with strong expertise in the discovery and development of diabetes medicines and the two leading public organizations involved in T1D research into one comprehensive collaborative consortium. The clinicians in INNODIA oversee T1D registries and have access to large populations of children and adults with T1D and family members at increased risk of developing the disease. The basic science researchers are experts in beta-cell pathophysiology, immunology, biomarker discovery, bioinformatics, systems biology and clinical trial design. INNODIA will accelerate understanding of T1D through coordinated studies of unique clinical samples and translation-oriented preclinical models. This should deliver novel biomarkers and interventions for testing in appropriately designed trials, to be developed in active collaboration with regulators and patients.
INNODIA provides access to unique historical bio-repositories and will create the Clinical Sample Network, a clinical EU infrastructure to recruit T1D subjects at diagnosis and at-risk relatives. These individuals will be deep-phenotyped and will provide bio-samples, allowing the establishment of a ‘living biobank’ of subjects consented for recall. They will be characterized using standardized clinical, genetic and metabolic phenotyping procedures, including prospective, longitudinal sample collection to facilitate novel biomarker discovery. Diverse biological samples (blood, plasma, serum, urine, stools, etc.) will be collected at specific time points, following strict and standardized operating procedures throughout the network. The large network of clinical partners in INNODIA has access to over 2,500 new onset T1D patients (children and adults) per year and the potential to recruit 1,500 and screen 5,000 high-risk subjects. INNODIA will also create an EU-wide collection of pancreases and tissues from T1D and at-risk donors as well as T2D and normoglycemic controls (EUnPOD). Strict standard operating procedures will be established for organ and tissue collection, in collaboration with the US-based nPOD initiative. The samples collected from living donors and EUnPOD will be available for high throughput screening discovery technologies in expert partner laboratories (academic and industry).
Research in INNODIA will be based on the following modules:
1. Beta-cell function (measuring/imaging functional beta-cell mass, early signs of beta-cell death); 
2. Immunome to be performed in 3 Immune Hubs (flow cytometry, CyTOF, autoAbs, cyto- and chemokines, immune activation and regulation); 
3. Genome and transcriptome of beta- and immune cells (genotyping, epigenome, lncRNA, splice-variants, immune cell subset and single cell analysis of TCR and transcriptome); 
4. Proteome and peptidome (Immunome via MS (CyTOF), T-cell phosphoproteome, beta-cell peptidome and proteome, serum proteome; 
5. Metabolome-Lipidome (lipidomics and metabolomics). Biobanks for samples available for later analysis (e.g. immune cells, stools for microbiome analysis) will be established.
Novel in vitro and in vivo models will be used, as well as a combination of existing techniques, made possible through the complementary expertise of the basic research group. The focus will be on the exploration of novel biomarkers (recently discovered by INNODIA partners) of beta-cell dysfunction or death, such as post-translationally modified proteins and alternatively spliced  variants as well as beta-cell specific miRNAs and meta</objective>
  <title>Translational approaches to disease modifying therapy of type 1 diabetes: an innovative approach towards understanding and arresting type 1 diabetes.</title>
<identifier>H2020JTIIMI2201401twostage</identifier>
</project>
