<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196484</rcn>
  <acronym>NZE Buildings</acronym>
  <objective>"The building sector is responsible for the majority of the energy consumption in the world. It is also a key challenge for the
20-20-20 strategy of the EU.

Sustainable housing starts with 'near zero-energy' buildings, i.e. homes that are so well insulated that it becomes easy to
produce more renewable energy on site than what is consumed.

Today, house construction in Europe is mainly performed by craftsmen who are small local builders and who work with
traditional technics and who are not keen to invest on research and development of Modern Methods of Construction
(MMC). As a consequence, it remains very difficult for consumers and investors to buy 'plus energy' houses in Europe (costs
and lack of offer due to lack of know-how).

The objective of the project is to provide to local builders the products and the tools so that they can offer to their customers
'nearly zero-energy' buildings with guaranteed performance and cost controls.

To do so, ECOXIA has developed the concept of ""Smart Envelope"". Built in the ideal conditions of the factory, the envelope
is installed in a 'Plug &amp; Play' way on site in one day. It includes both energy performance and the components to make it
smart.

ECOXIA developed a prototype in 2012 to check the performance of its building envelope. Installed in Yerres, France, it
proved the interest of the concept from a mechanical, thermal, comfort and cost standpoints. The recorded consumption
proves that the prototype is a 'plus energy' building with the production of only 20 sqm of photovoltaic solar panels.

To be able to commercialise the right solution and help Europe to develop a new industry, ECOXIA needs to go further into
its feasibility study by addressing the following questions:
- which is the best level of prefabrication?
- how can we improve the price of our solution for the European market ?
- who are the best potential partners for our project in Europe?
- what are the regulatory issues on the most relevant markets in Europe?"</objective>
  <title>Developing replicable and cost effective Nearly Zero-Energy' building solutions for small builders in Europe</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
