<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212876</rcn>
  <acronym>SENSE</acronym>
  <objective>Results from a simulation experiment with top retailers Carrefour and Casino in France and their 100 top suppliers moving from actual practice to a “Physical Internet Model” showed a potential economic benefit of 32%, a 60% reduction of greenhouse gas emissions and a potential of 50% of volume shifted from road to rail. 
Accelerating the Path Towards Physical Internet -SENSE-  project strategic objective is to accelerate the path towards the Physical Internet (PI), so advanced pilot implementations of the PI concept are well functioning and extended in industry practice by 2030, and hence contributing to at least 30 % reduction in congestion, emissions and energy consumption.
To that end, SENSE aims to increase the level of understanding of PI concept and the opportunities that brings to transport and logistics. By building stronger and wider support of industry, public bodies and research worlds towards the PI we may reach consensus and enable coordinated strategic public and private investments in research and innovation embracing Physical Internet that could lead us to a new much more efficient and sustainable paradigm.
SENSE will: 1) enhance, and stabilize a solid framework for industry, research and public bodies to share advances, barriers, opportunities and best practices regarding Physical Internet implementation, 2) build awareness and raise wide consensus on the Detailed Roadmap towards the Physical Internet developed in the frame of the project, 3) Create The Reference Knowledge Platform so the Physical Internet Community has access to recent developments including: PI implementation cases assessment, industry programs and activities, related start-ups, research and innovation projects, public initiatives and programs and last, but not least, 4) assist and support Industry, European Commission, Member States and Regional Governments in the process of defining high impact research policies to fast track to Physical Internet.</objective>
  <title>Accelerating the Path Towards Physical Internet</title>
<identifier>H2020MG2017SingleStageRTDMOVE</identifier>
</project>
