<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210212</rcn>
  <acronym>ENTRAP</acronym>
  <objective>ENTRAP will deliver combined operational research (OR) methods for assessing and identifying emerging and future counter-measures. The tools will be used for identifying the needed step-changes for countering present, emerging and future explosive threats.
 

The OR tools will encompass methods including morphological analysis, attack-defence trees, Bow-tie diagrams and wargaming. The tools have been well-established for decades and they will be further developed and adapted for explosive threats. The proposed research aims to assess the effectiveness of counter-tools and their combinations across the plot. This will give a value on the efficiency they can provide for historical cases or emerging and future scenarios for an attack. The project will strive to identify commonalities in the timeline where a counter-tool can be effective for several different scenarios. Thus, an effectiveness assessment will be made not only across the timeline for one scenario but also across different scenarios. The research and development efforts on a European level over the last decades will be a main source of background data.


A gap analysis over the plot will in combination with the OR methods identify the need of required preventive counter-measures. A gap bridging assessment will together with the researcher and practitioner think-tank in ENTRAP ensure a step-change vision of counter-tools for important gaps. Historical attacks, scenarios defined in FP 7 projects, the EU Matrix group and NDE will be used as the basis. A cost assessment will be included giving an estimate for the required further developments.


The ENTRAP consortium will bring together a world-leading team where the consortium includes 11 practitioners supported by an advisory board of key entities whereof 18 Letter of Supports have been obtained.</objective>
  <title>Enhanced Neutralisation of explosive Threats Reaching Across the Plot</title>
<identifier>H2020SEC201620171</identifier>
</project>
