<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212384</rcn>
  <acronym>CoSIE</acronym>
  <objective>There is growing consensus that public services can be improved through experiments which bring together service providers and their users. This proposal is for H2020-SC6-Co-Creation-2016-217: Applied co-creation to deliver public services. The CoSIE project contributes to democratic dimensions and social inclusion through co-creating public services by engaging diverse citizen groups and stakeholders. Utilizing blended data sources (open data, social media) with innovative deployment of ICT (data-analytics, Living Lab, Community reporting) in nine pilots, the project introduces the culture of experiments that encompasses various stakeholders for co-creating service innovations. 
The CoSIE project has two overarching aims: i) advance the active shaping of service priorities by end users and their informal support networks, ii) engage citizens, especially groups often called ‘hard to reach’, in the collaborative design of public services. The aims are divided into six objectives: 1) develop practical resources grounded in asset based knowledge to support new ways for public service actors to re-define operational processes, 2) produce and deliver nine real-life pilots to co-create a set of relational public services with various combinations of public sector, civil society and commercial actors, 3) draw together cross-cutting lessons from pilots and utilise innovative visualisation methods to share and validate new ideas and models of good governance, 4) apply innovative approaches appropriate to local contexts and user groups to gather the necessary user insight to co-create services, 5) ensure sustainability by establishing local trainers for animating dialogue and collating user voice, embedded in community networks, 6) mobilise new knowledge from piloting and validating by creating an accessible, user friendly roadmap to co-creation for service providers and their partners.

The project will be implemented as a joint venture with 24 partners from 10 EU countries.</objective>
  <title>Co-creation of service innovation in Europe</title>
<identifier>H2020SC6COCREATION2017</identifier>
</project>
