<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>199882</rcn>
  <acronym>IMAGE</acronym>
  <objective>The proposed project, IMAGE, is relevant to Topic MG-1.10-2015, aiming to enhance the EU-China collaborative effort focusing on “Innovative methods and numerical technologies for airframe and engine noise reduction”. The project consortium consists of 12 partners.

The purpose of IMAGE is to investigate experimentally and numerically innovative airframe and engine noise-reduction technologies and, in a systematic conjunction, to develop robust methodologies of addressing these technologies. Airframe noise is addressed by tackling landing gears and high-lift devices, and engine noise through its fan component. Fundamental investigations of three key control strategies are carried out: plasma actuation, turbulence screens and innovative porous materials, on a platform of three configurations, relevant to airframe and aero-engine noise generation and control, including a wing mock-up, tandem cylinder and engine-fan duct. Beyond this, IMAGE explores further the installation effect of aeroacoustic engine-jet/wing interaction with a simplified configuration, as well as low-noise concepts and optimal noise-actuation methods by means of aeroacoustic optimization.

The project will conclude a comprehensive understanding of the physical mechanisms concerning flow-induced airframe and engine-fan noise generation, propagation and control, and of further improvement of beam-forming technology and noise source identification in aero-acoustic experimental analysis. The experiment will generate well-documented database, supporting the development of numerical modelling and simulation methodologies for reliable validation and verification. To this end, with technical synthesis and industrial assessment, the noise control methods will be optimized and be facilitated towards potential industrial use, and the methodologies developed should form a robust part of advanced tools in industrial practice.</objective>
  <title>Innovative Methodologies and technologies for reducing Aircraft noise Generation and Emission</title>
<identifier>H2020MG2015SingleStageA</identifier>
</project>
