<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>198858</rcn>
  <acronym>EPICHECK</acronym>
  <objective>Nucleix developed a revolutionary platform for the development of Methylation Bio-markers and Bio-Marker panels for screening (early detection of disease) and diagnosis based on epigenetic markers.  The platform identifies changes in specific methylation locations of DNA extracted from body fluids such as – urine, blood, stools and sputum.  A Bio-Markers panel goal is to distinguish between sick and healthy individuals.  The company’s expertise include the identification of the specific loci, comprising a panel of markers that can work in multiplex and generate highly accurate test.  Nucleix technology was proven to be extremely sensitive and specific in its first application. 
Nucleix focuses initially on the field of cancer detection and screening. Cancer cost the EU €126 billion in 2009, which was 1.07% of EU GDP. 2.45m People in the EU were diagnosed with cancer in 2008, when 1.23 million people in the EU died from cancer in 2008. This is one of the most significant public health issues in the world and in the EU.  Nucleix first product, Bladder EpiCheck is a urine test for the detection of Bladder Cancer. It is aimed for monitoring bladder cancer patients as this is a disease with high recurrence rate and requires tight surveillance. This product will be launched in Q4 of 2015. The test is based on a panel of 15 non-overlapping Methylation markers at loci that were identified, developed and owned by the company.  This product which has better sensitivity and specificity than any other non-invasive test is a proof of the company’s ability to translate its technology to applicable products.   
The company plans to develop EPICHECK - diagnostic kits using multi-loci panel of markers, for the detection and screening of lung cancer and colorectal cancer in blood samples – which is the subject of this applications.  
EPICHECK will be launched rapidly, and will provide revenues of over 320m Euro in its 5th year of commercial activities.</objective>
  <title>Detection of Various Cancer Types for Screening and Diagnosis through Blood Samples with Epigenetic Biomarkers Panels</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12015</identifier>
</project>
