<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210211</rcn>
  <acronym>MINDb4ACT</acronym>
  <objective>MINDb4ACT is a collaborative project participated by 7 LEAs, think-tanks, reserach centres, universities, industry associations and NGO based in 10 Member States (Austria, Belgium, Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, Italy, Poland, Spain and United Kingdom). The project will align its research priorities with some of the most relevant issues already identified by the European Commission:

Priority 1. Systematizing the available knowledge and expertise to support strategic decision-making
Priority 2. Enhancing interdisciplinary fieldwork on terrorists' recruiting grounds, socialisation and techniques
Priority 3. Using big data in order to analyse the information related to the communication practices of violent radicalisation
Priority 4.Improving existing links between academia including non-EU researchers, policy-makers and other stakeholders

MINDb4ACT will contribute to such priorities for the improvement of current counter-violent extremism policies (CVEs) in the countries represented in the consortium (Austria, Belgium Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, Italy Poland, Spain and United Kingdom) and the generation of new ones connecting through collaboration ecosystems (innovative, open, participatory, user-centred environments) to co-design  interventions such as research actions, exchanges, strategic-policy exercises, training courses and pilot projects based on social innovation and civic engagement schemes (a community of practice of 1,500 people). All actions will be developed in 5 specific domains: prisons and judiciary system; migration hotspots and asylum centres, schools, cities (peri-urban contexts) and the Internet and media. A special contribution of the project will be the integration of technology based practical solutions with the contribution of the industry. 

As mentioned in the call, MINDb4ACT will NOT be "focused on studying the phenomenon of radicalization" but focused on "developing policy recommendations and practical solutions for end-users".</objective>
  <title>Mapping, IdentifyiNg and Developing skills and opportunities in operating environments to co-create innovative, ethical and effective ACTions to tackle radicalization leading to violent extremism</title>
<identifier>H2020SEC201620171</identifier>
</project>
