<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>209908</rcn>
  <acronym>ESIT</acronym>
  <objective>The European School for interdisciplinary tinnitus research (ESIT) provides an opportunity for young researchers to work on leading-edge research projects, which will radically improve the situation of 42 million European tinnitus patients. They will develop new treatment solutions for tinnitus, fundamentally improve existing treatment paradigms, implement innovative research methods, perform the first genetic studies on tinnitus and establish the largest pan-European tinnitus dataset, which will allow the implementation of innovative solutions for personalized tinnitus treatment. High quality network-wide training will prepare the individual researchers with outstanding academic as well as personal skills to perform these tasks. 
The international training programme offered by the ESIT network extends far beyond the doctoral training that can be offered by single universities. A distinctive feature of ESIT is therefore the tight integration of academic, clinical, and industrial partners together with patient organisations and public health authorities. Fellows will be trained by leading specialists from multiple domains and become familiar with the various work environments in the European health sector. The strong intersectoral and interdisciplinary training provides them with all relevant skills and experiences to excel internationally, to recognise their full potential and to take mature career decisions. ESIT will thereby build up a future generation of creative, entrepreneurial and innovative researchers for the European Research Area, trained to master the upcoming challenges in the field, to implement sustained changes in the clinical management of tinnitus, and to shape PhD education programmes for forthcoming students.</objective>
  <title>European School for Interdisciplinary Tinnitus Research</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2016</identifier>
</project>
