<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205686</rcn>
  <acronym>TAVAC</acronym>
  <objective>In aircraft cabin environments, vibrations and noise co-exist affecting the passenger comfort, quality of flight, but also aircraft efficiency. To progress on airframe and engine efficiency while supporting the high level of customer comfort requested, the faced challenges are to develop and integrate into the airframe and cabin new technologies of active noise and vibration reduction, without penalizing the weight, fuel efficiency and performance of the aircraft. 
The main aim of the proposed research is the development of novel integrated active technologies for noise and vibration reduction and their integration into aircraft fuselage and cabin. This is accommodated in two discrete, but highly related directions: (1) Active vibration isolation and control of engines and aerodynamically induced loads; (2) Active noise control. Each of the approaches is subjected to its own specific performance and weight limitations.
The project focuses on the application of light-weight, power efficient and compact in size 3D printed electro active loudspeaker arrays for noise control, and on induced-strain piezoceramic actuators for vibration control. Advanced and light-weight controller and amplifier electronic modules will be developed by the industrial partner MILTEC. Virtual testing and optimal system design methods are proposed for the detection of the appropriate actuator characteristics, locations for the more efficient placement, required power and optimized controllers, in connection to the specific application details attention will be focused. Miltech as the industrial partner, will use the experience from previous project related with aircraft integrated systems. These should balance between the potentially optimum provided performance with the compact size and weight.  TAVAC is expected to have a significant impact on CleanSky program, great technical and economic impact on the competitiveness of European aircraft industry, and a substantial socioeconomic impact.</objective>
  <title>Technologies for Active Vibration and Acoustic Comfort</title>
<identifier>H2020CS2CFP02201501</identifier>
</project>
