<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205674</rcn>
  <acronym>EXPAND</acronym>
  <objective>EXPAND intends to support the implementation of the JPI Urban Europe Strategic Research and Innovation Agenda (SRIA) by (1) supporting JPI Urban Europe’s widening activities towards new countries, stakeholders and partners; and (2)  focusing on the development and piloting of new instruments, framework conditions and methods for transnational and transdisciplinary cooperation. 

Since urban transformations to sustainable and liveable futures depends on a broad commitment and co-creation among a diverse set of actors, the identified challenge to be tackled by EXPAND is widening the community. Specifically in terms of member countries. But also in terms of stakeholder involvement in core activities. Furthermore, the challenge is also to be tackled by the development and implementation of new instruments and framework conditions that support such a co-creation and alignment of European, national and local research and innovation actions. 

As the basic concept for widening participation, a Stakeholder Involvement Platform (SIP) will be developed that anticipates the needs of different stakeholder groups and regions to facilitate the strategic dialogue between all stakeholder groups and implement the SRIA. 

The SIP relates to new approaches in programme management, alignment of national programmes, strategies and policies as well as new instruments for research funding and new formats for dissemination and exploitation of research results. 

Strategic relationships will be developed with national, European and international organisations and special attention will be given to reach out and mobilise actors in Widening countries. Two JPI Urban Europe Conferences will be organised to position JPI Urban Europe in the wider European Research and Innovation community and a self-monitoring system will be developed and tested to allow a consistent monitoring of JPI Urban Europe activities.</objective>
  <title>EXPAND - enhancing co-creation in JPI Urban Europe through widening Member State and stakeholder participation</title>
<identifier>H2020WIDESPREAD022016JPIUrbanEurope</identifier>
</project>
