<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205408</rcn>
  <acronym>ELENA</acronym>
  <objective>Chemistry is fundamental to nanotechnology, as chemistry can prepare specifically tailored molecules to serve, in a bottom-up approach, as the building blocks for the fabrication of functional and structured nano-materials. Nanotechnology is the technology of the 21st century with applications from electronics to biotechnology and medicine. The next decade will thus be characterized by an increasing industrial demand for novel nanostructures with individual physical and chemical properties tuned to specific applications. This, in turn, requires increased flexibility and control over material composition, shape and resolution. To meet this demand the chemistry and the physics behind new and emerging nanoscale fabrication methods must be well understood and this understanding must be systematically deployed to advance these methods into commercially viable fabrication technologies. Simultaneously to ensure that Europe is a significant player in this economically and technologically important industry, the European nanotechnology industry must have access to well trained individuals with both the technical skills and a broad understanding of the physical and chemical parameters governing the performance of next generation processing techniques and, the skills and drive needed for further innovation and entrepreneurship in the nano-technology field. ELENA addresses these scientific and training needs by: i) studying the chemistry underpinning two emerging nano-technology writing techniques; Focused Electron Beam Induced Processing and Extreme Ultra Violet Lithography, ii) exploiting knowledge gained in (i) to develop these techniques such that they may be made commercially competitive, and iii) training a new generation of European scientists with a fundamental understanding of the physics and chemistry behind these processes and the mind set for innovation and entrepreneurship to provide an exemplar for up-skilling European nanotechnology industry.</objective>
  <title>Low energy ELEctron driven chemistry for the advantage of emerging NAno-fabrication methods</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2016</identifier>
</project>
