<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196767</rcn>
  <acronym>QuantGeomLangTFT</acronym>
  <objective>We will use modern techniques in derived algebraic geometry, topological field theory and quantum groups to construct quantizations of character varieties, moduli spaces parameterizing G-bundles with flat connection on a surface.  We will leverage our construction to shine new light on the geometric representation theory of quantum groups and double affine Hecke algebras (DAHA's), and to produce new invariants of knots and 3-manifolds.

Our previous research has uncovered strong evidence for the existence of a novel construction of quantum differential operators -- and their extension to higher genus surfaces -- in terms of a four-dimensional topological field theory, which we have dubbed the Quantum Geometric Langlands (QGL) theory.  By construction, the QGL theory of a surface yields a quantization of its character variety; quantum differential operators form just the first interesting example.  We thus propose the following long-term projects:

1. Build higher genus analogs of DAHA's, equipped with mapping class group actions -- thereby solving a long open problem -- by computing QGL theory of arbitrary surfaces; recover quantum differential operators and the (non-degenerate, spherical) DAHA of G, respectively, from the once-punctured and closed two-torus.
2. Obtain a unified construction of both the quantized A-polynomial and the Oblomkov-Rasmussen-Shende invariants, two celebrated -- and previously unrelated -- conjectural knot invariants which have received a great deal of attention.
3. By studying special features of our construction when the quantization parameter is a root of unity, realize the Verlinde algebra as a module over the DAHA, shedding new light on fundamental results of Cherednik and Witten.
4. Develop genus one, and higher, quantum Springer theory -- a geometric approach to constructing representations of quantum algebras -- with deep connections to rational and elliptic Springer theory, and geometric Langlands program.</objective>
  <title>The Quantum Geometric Langlands Topological Field Theory</title>
<identifier>ERC2014STG</identifier>
</project>
