<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210210</rcn>
  <acronym>LETS-CROWD</acronym>
  <objective>LETS–CROWD will overcome challenges preventing the effective implementation of the European Security Model (ESM)  with regards to mass gatherings. This will be achieved by providing the following to security policy practitioners and in particular, LEAs:
(1) A dynamic risk assessment methodology for the protection of crowds during mass gatherings centred on human factors in order to effectively produce policies and deploy adequate solutions. 
(2) A policy making toolkit for the long-term and strategic decision making of security policy makers, including a database of empirical data, statistics and an analytical tool for security policies modelling, and
(3) A set of human centred tools for Law Enforcement Agencies (LEAs), including real time crowd behaviour forecasting, innovative communication procedures, semantic intelligence applied to social networks and the internet, and novel computer vision techniques.
LETS-CROWD will be a security practitioner driven project, fostering the communication and cooperation among LEAs, first responders, civil protection and citizens in the fight against crime and terrorism during mass gatherings by a set of cooperation actions. The project will put citizens at the centre of the research and will assess and evaluate how security measures affect them, and how they perceive them, while respecting EU fundamental rights.
LETS-CROWD impact will be measured under practical demonstrations involving seven LEAs and relevant emergency services units. In order to facilitate the assessment of the performance, transferability, scalability and large scale deployment of these solutions, the demonstrations will be conducted following eleven use cases.</objective>
  <title>Law Enforcement agencies human factor methods and Toolkit for the Security and protection of CROWDs in mass gatherings</title>
<identifier>H2020SEC201620171</identifier>
</project>
