<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196463</rcn>
  <acronym>ADHESION</acronym>
  <objective>The aim of the ADHESION Project is to strengthen the anti-adhesion and anti-bacterial characteristics of a NOVAGENIT® proprietary  product (DAC®), by tuning and validating a new more competitive solution targeted to the orthopaedic and cardiovascular surgery. NOVAGENIT® will take the opportunity to expand its own business in the anti-adhesion market by taking advantage of the intrinsic barrier effect of the DAC® hydrogel. A new formulation of the DAC® product will add an anti-bacterial power to the anti-fouling/anti-adhesion intrinsic action. This could be due to a combination of silver nano-particles and to Vitamin C added to the derivatized hyaluronan based gel original formulation. The new formulation, comprising a lyophilized membrane, will increase the usability for the end user, and will prolong the shelf life of the biotech, advanced material product.NOVAGENIT® intends to address both the adhesion and infection issues, as it is a complete novelty in the market of anti-adhesion products. Specifically the business opportunity consists in the combination of the three key product features (anti-fouling, antibiotic and usability) into a novel product not yet market available, and to target two surgery markets (cardiovascular and orthopaedic ones) in order to generate the appropriate return on the investment.
This phase 1 consists in the feasibility study devoted to assess the economic/technological viability of the innovative idea and to generate its business plan. It will be followed by a phase 2 where the product will be industrialized and make ready for sales through a targeted marketing plan. The envisaged advantage for the European Health-care system from the results of the ADHESION Project is to spare the costs of re-interventions, both for the post-surgical adhesions (about 2 billion Euros/year), and the post-surgical infections (about 3 to 5 billion Euros/year). Future opportunities of this product on different markets will be exploited.</objective>
  <title>Development of new biotech AdvanceD materials based on Hyaluronic acid and nanoparticlEs to prevent Surgical adhesIons and pOst surgical infectionNs</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
