<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211968</rcn>
  <acronym>IN2STEMPO</acronym>
  <objective>Innovative Solutions in Future Stations, Energy Metering and Power Supply (IN2STEMPO) addresses the call S2R-CFM-IP3-01-2017 Smart System Energy Management Solutions and Future Station Solutions.  IN2STEMPO aligns with the Shift2Rail objectives and aims to reduce lifecycle costs, improve reliability and punctuality, whilst increasing capacity, enhancing interoperability and improving the customer experience.
The IN2STEMPO Smart Power Supply activities seek to contribute to the development of a railway smart grid based on the development of an unique railway power grid in an interconnected system. This new railway network will integrate smart metering, innovative power electronic components, energy management and energy storage systems.  This new concept will lead to improved and optimised train traffic, energy costs, and energy supply security for the railway system.  In parallel it will allow for optimised solutions to be developed through optimising investment, operation costs and maintenance. 
The IN2STEMPO Smart Metering research activities will realise a non-intrusive smart metering sensor network at a railway system level. It will demonstrate an open system and interface for data collection, aggregation and analysis at an open source ODM (Operational Data Management) level. The applications will exploit the energy analysis process with the aim of enhancing energy decision-making and line operation patterns.  Other possible applications include preventative maintenance plans, asset management and Life Cycle Cost dashboards.
The IN2STEMPO Future Stations activities are aimed at improving the customer experience and safety at stations, resulting in a better passenger experience for customers using the railway. Research will be focussed on improving crowd management in high capacity stations, station design and components, accessibility to trains and new ticketing technologies.</objective>
  <title>Innovative Solutions in Future Stations, Energy Metering and Power Supply</title>
<identifier>H2020S2RJUCFM2017</identifier>
</project>
