<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205523</rcn>
  <acronym>ERA CoBioTech</acronym>
  <objective>"The ERA-Net “Cofund on BioTechnologies” (CoBioTech) aims to better use synergies between current mechanisms of biotechnology research funding in Europe, to highlight the benefits of a bio-based economy for society, and to thus maintain and strengthen Europe’s global lead in modern biotechnology.
The co-funded call will focus on application-oriented research in:
a) Synthetic biology approaches to design and construct new biological parts, devices and systems
b) Systems biology approaches to metabolic engineering and optimisation of biological processes
c) Identification and use of the metabolic potentials of genomic data
d) Chemical and biotechnological approaches to transform bio-based molecules into molecules with high added value.
Bundling three predecessor ERA-Nets in the area of biotechnology, CoBioTech significantly increases public funding (call volume ~ 30 Mio €), intensifies collaboration across relevant sectors and countries, and thus
- advances RD&amp;I in industrial biotechnology
- establishes systems and synthetic biology as technology drivers in applied biotechnology, and
- enhances the potential for exploitation through active industry involvement.
Necessary steps and measures to achieve these goals will be encompassed in a joint Strategic Agenda.
With a “European Biotechnology Hub”, CoBioTech realises an entirely new concept, reaching out to key actors and stakeholders from multiple biotechnology-related areas in order to align different European strategic instruments with the goals of the KET biotechnology programme under Horizon 2020 and to increase public awareness of biotechnology for industrial uses.
CoBioTech will implement additional funding activities without EC co-funding, which will advance RD&amp;I in industrial biotechnology in line with the Strategic Agenda and the outcomes of the ""European Biotechnology Hub.""
CoBioTech thus provides biotechnology stakeholders with tailor-made support regarding information, communication, networking and funding."</objective>
  <title>Cofund on Biotechnologies</title>
<identifier>H2020NMBPERANET2016</identifier>
</project>
