<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206221</rcn>
  <acronym>R2PI</acronym>
  <objective>"R2π examines the shift from the broad concept of a Circular Economy (CE) to one of a Circular Economy Business Models (CEBM), by tackling both market failure (business, consumers) and policy failure (conflicts, assumptions, unintended consequence). Its innovation lies in having a strong business-focus, examining stimuli beyond environmental goals (including ICT and eco-innovation), and in examining the role of policy innovation (including the use of policy nudges and of ""Policy Packages""). R2π unfolds in diverse contexts with a strong emphasis on involvement and exchange. The research design employs mixed-methods, with a strong emphasis on case studies but also including desktop research, feasibility assessments (including surveys where applicable), policy formulation &amp; stakeholder involvement. The ultimate goal of the project is to see the widespread implementation of the CE based on successful Business Models to ensure sustained economic development, to minimize environmental impact and to maximize social welfare. 
The goal of the R²π project is therefore to develop sustainable business models that would facilitate the circular economy and to propose ""Policy Package"" that will support these business models. The R2Pi Consortium consists of 14 partners from 9 Member states and associated countries. The wide range of expertise, knowledge, tools and connections existing among the consortium members will be leveraged to develop innovative practical tools and procedural guidelines that may be widely and systematically applied across many different business sectors in diverse regions and countries, across the spectrum from large established EU countries to newer and smaller member states.. Through these innovative business models and ""Policy Packages"", the European economy will move into a more sustainable, resource efficient and resilient economic track.
R²π will position Europe as a world leader in advancing the circular economy model. 
"</objective>
  <title>TRANSITION FROM LINEAR 2 CIRCULAR: POLICY AND INNOVATION</title>
<identifier>H2020CIRC2016OneStage</identifier>
</project>
