<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212229</rcn>
  <acronym>SMARTELECTRODES</acronym>
  <objective>Demand of “smart” electrodes/systems has recently increased due to significant role of various devices/equipment based on these electrodes - urgent needs of present and forthcoming human activities. The multi- and interdisciplinary project SMARTELECTRODES is proposing elaboration of advanced systems covered under umbrella of “smart” electrodes which will be involved and play significant roles in several important electrochemical/electrophysical applications as catalysis/electrocatalysis, sensoring, thermoelectrics, electrowinning, electrochemical machining and electrospark alloying. The development of multiscaled (from nano- to macro-; from nanodot to volumized 3D-) metallic and semiconductor electrodes and integration of them into working systems/equipment is the main target of SMARTELECTRODES. The project is well-balanced, highly innovative R&amp;D training network, which aims: 
To develop long lasting collaborations between four academic (Vilnius University, Lithuania; Institute of Applied Physics, Moldova; Northeastern University, USA; Research Institute for Physical Chemical Problems of BSU, Belarus) and two companies (JSC Topaz, Moldova and JSC “Electronics Treatment Technologies”, EPT, Lithuania);  
To develop new electrodes (based on chalcogenides, iron group metals and “technological” electrodes) by well-established institutions;  
To increase career perspectives of each participant that will lead to benefit of each member and partnership as a whole. 
Partners will be complimentary involved into realization of the proposed research. The research tasks will be implemented through multidisciplinary Work Packages devoted to the fabrication, adapting and investigation of electrodes/materials, also they include the activities towards training and management. Namely, advanced training will be provided to the seconded staff through well-integrated programs, including workshops and conferences.</objective>
  <title>Multiscaled Smart Metallic and Semiconductor Electrodes for Electrochemical Processing and Devices</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCARISE2017</identifier>
</project>
