<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196456</rcn>
  <acronym>Remote Sanitation</acronym>
  <objective>Low quality sanitation is a huge global, growing environmental and health problem with large costs to society. Poor hygiene
and waste treatment results in lower productivity, spreading of diseases and pollution. There is a lack of efficient and green
solutions addressing specific sanitation needs in remote areas such as: refugee and military camps, remote industrial and
household sites.
The awareness of the problem is increasing and authorities have begun to act within this area - e.g. the United Nations
Environment Programme has stated that “every dollar invested in safe water and sanitation has a pay back of US$3 to US
$34 depending on the region and the technology deployed”.
Aalborg Rørteknik ApS (ART) have invented a new sanitation solution, applicable in remote areas without access to sewage
infrastructure. This turnkey system solution, consisting of 3 main modules (hygiene unit, waste water treatment, sludge
handling), has superior advantages to alternative solutions by being e.g. mobile, reusable, hygienic, environmentally friendly
and affordable. In addition, ART will include services such as camp architecture, installation and maintenance, ensuring
maxmized efficiency of the solution.
Red Cross have been an important contributor in the project and also led the way to market introduction targetting aidworker
base camps. The unique selling points of the new solution are estimated to secure a market share of 15% within 5
years, resulting in an enhanced profitability and significant growth for ART.
In this phase 1 study, ART will perform a demonstration exercice, as well as conduct extended market studies to develop an
appropriate IP strategy, in preparation of a phase 2 project. The outcome of this stage, will be a feasibility report and
business plan. This project and requested financial support, will address an innovative and sustainable solution, with clear
benefits for users, with consequent impacts in the environment and the society as a whole.</objective>
  <title>Remote Sanitation – New sustainable sanitation solution for remote areas</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
