<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212377</rcn>
  <acronym>iModBatt</acronym>
  <objective>iModBatt stands for Industrial Modular Battery Pack Concept Addressing High Energy Density, Environmental Friendliness, Flexibility and Cost Efficiency for Automotive Applications. The aim of iModBatt is to design and manufacture, with minimum environmental impact, a high energy density modular battery pack flexible enough to be used in automotive and small stationary applications. This battery pack will be suitable for industrial automated assembly with an easy disassembly design, to make possible the shift from primary applications to secondary ones, and to facilitate the pack recyclability or parts replacement if necessary. 
The project concept is built around an already existing technologically breakthrough, modular battery pack design primarily developed for specialty applications, that has proven excellent performance and cost efficiency in such a manner that higher ambition, wider spread electric vehicle applications seem the natural next developmental step for such a concept.
The project focuses into maximization of the energy density of a lithium ion pack through the optimization of the structural design and components of a battery pack for a given cell form factor. In this sense the strategy is to increase the energy density by reducing the weight of the battery pack while keeping structural integrity and easy assembly and manufacturing. Chemistry and BMS work is beyond the scope of the project, which focuses in the structural design and manufacturing.
The Consortium includes industrial partners of every step of the battery pack value chain, including  automotive OEMs, battery parts manufacturers as well as leading European research centres with ample experience in the field of batteries.</objective>
  <title>Industrial Modular Battery Pack Concept Addressing High Energy Density, Environmental Friendliness, Flexibility and Cost Efficiency for Automotive Applications</title>
<identifier>H2020GV2017</identifier>
</project>
