<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206500</rcn>
  <acronym>ADMS</acronym>
  <objective>A critical challenge for electricity Smartgrids is to optimise Distribution System Operators’ (DSO) ROI &amp; avoid grid instabilities with ever increasing Renewable Energy Sources. ADMS will continuously monitor the dynamic state of networks &amp; potential grid instability right to the LV grid-edge. It will disruptively change how Europe’s 2,400 DSOs manage &amp; control their networks to improve network stability by 20% &amp; grid capacity by 25%, reduce networks outages duration &amp; customer losses by 20% &amp; enable 25% more renewable connections, to help achieve their 2020 carbon reduction targets. The aim is a TRL9 operational product on the market, feeding into Altea’s global presence &amp; commercial channels, within 3 years from the start of this FTI project. This Innovation phase follows-on from the very successful H2020-SMEINST-1-2014 feasibility project (GA 673607) that identified a huge market &amp; opportunity. ADMS will seamlessly integrate MAC’s mass deployable, low-cost network monitoring solutions (patented Flexible Magnetic sensors, micro Phasor Measurement Units (mPMU) &amp; LV Network monitoring) &amp; Gridhound’s innovative patented data-driven Artificial-Neural-Networks-based Advanced Distribution Automation (ADA) monitoring system. These will be productised by RWTH to meet the IEC61850 substation automation standard &amp; mPMU enhanced with the patented TFT-WLS algorithm to meet the IEEE C37.118-1 standard. All components are TRL6/7. This project will fast-track integration &amp; productisation to a TRL8 innovative prototype to pilot/operate/validate at 4 diverse DSO reference sites over 12 months with Alliander, ENEL, ESB &amp; SPEN in DE,IT, IE,UK. Based on a market analysis &amp; ongoing feedback from the pilots, the project will disseminate ADMS to potential customers &amp; business collaborators through various media &amp; 2 specific events, &amp; develop/validate a Business Plan to commercially deploy a TRL9 ADMS. €36M sales from a potential market of €0.5BM &amp; 3700% ROI are forecast over 7 years.</objective>
  <title>SmartGrid Active Distribution Management System to accommodate Renewable Energy Sources and Low Carbon Emissions</title>
<identifier>H2020FTIPilot20161</identifier>
</project>
