<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207438</rcn>
  <acronym>InSCOPE</acronym>
  <objective>The InSCOPE project will set-up an open access pilot line service for Hybrid TOLAE (H-TOLAE) technologies capable of sampling products at TRL6-7. It positions itself in between R&amp;D and industry and deploys a service for validating potential H-TOLAE products. Manufacturing progresses beyond R&amp;D level (TRL5 towards 6) by improving processes, functionality and reliability allowing sampling at high quality and in relevant numbers needed for industrial qualification (TRL 6-7). The applications addressed cover automotive, healthcare, smart packaging and buildings. After InSCOPE, the Pilot line service will remain accessible to interested parties. The pilot line is serviced by top European RTD’s with leading technological positions and state of the art equipment in the domain of H-TOLAE.


InSCOPE will set up an open access pilot line infrastructure for H-TOLAE technology, which is modular ensuring a comprehensive toolbox of printing, assembly, production integration and process validation distributed over the partners. InSCOPE will ensure interoperability between the differing modules at the partners enabling end-users to combine different processes step from different partners in their process flow. It will accelerate the uptake of H-TOLAE technology by delivering a public handbook describing functionalities, production guidelines and design rules of H-TOLAE, including new opportunities for “traditional” electronics. Validation of the pilot line service by 4 Showcases and 15 development cases are included within the project. The Showcases consist of H-TOLAE product prototypes at TRL 5 to be matured on functionality and on manufacturability. The showcases will steer the pilot line improvement. They are selected based on their economic impact as well as the technological status of the product and production in Europe. The development cases are devoted to new functionalities enabled by H-TOLAE. They are aimed at SME’s interested in exploring the broad advantages H-TOLAE.</objective>
  <title>INternational Smart Collaborative Open-access hybrid Printed Electronics pilot line</title>
<identifier>H2020ICT20161</identifier>
</project>
