<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>213380</rcn>
  <acronym>EUROVOLC</acronym>
  <objective>EUROVOLC will construct an integrated and harmonized European volcanological community able to fully support, exploit and build-upon existing and emerging national and pan-European research infrastructures, including e-Infrastructures of the European Supersite volcanoes. The harmonization includes linking scientists and stakeholders and connecting still isolated volcanological infrastructures located at in situ volcano observatories (VO) and volcanological research institutions (VRIs).  EUROVOLC will overcome fragmentation at various levels, including community, project and discipline fragmentation by addressing four main themes:  Community building, volcano-atmosphere interaction, sub-surface processes and volcanic crisis preparedness and risk  management. Examples of networking activities under these themes include collaboration and networking between VOs, VRIs and civil protection agencies, networking of atmospheric gas and aerosol observations as well as observations of subsurface processes, and initiation of access to multidisciplinary observations from Krafla Volcano Laboratory as a test bed. Joint research activities include production of services to initialize volcanic ash transport and dispersal models during eruptions, integrated modelling of pre-eruption data, and a complete catalogue of European Volcanoes. Trans-national access to European Volcano observatories will be facilitated and virtual access to various modelling and assessment tools for responding to volcanic unrest and eruptions will be offered. Through these activities EUROVOLC will integrate the European volcanological community and open up and provide a wider, simplified, and more efficient access to key, multidisciplinary European research infrastructures located at leading VOs and VRIs to conduct improved volcanological research, drive best practice at volcanological observatories and open pathways for enterprise to better exploit georesources in volcanic areas such as geothermal energy.</objective>
  <title>European Network of Observatories and Research Infrastructures for Volcanology</title>
<identifier>H2020INFRAIA20171twostage</identifier>
</project>
