<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212340</rcn>
  <acronym>CARMOF</acronym>
  <objective>CO2 capture process represents typically about 70% of the total cost of the CCS chain. Power plants that capture CO2 today use an old technology whereby flue gases are bubbled through organic amines in water, where the CO2 binds to amines. The liquid is then heated to 120-150ºC to release the gas, after which the liquids are reused. The entire process is expensive and inefficient: it consumes about 30 percent of the power generated.
One of the most promising technologies for CO2 capture is based on the adsorption process using solid sorbents, with the most important advantage being the potential energy penalty reduction for regeneration of the material compared to liquid absorption . Nevertheless, the challenge in this application remains the same, namely to intensify the production of a CO2 stream in terms of adsorption/desorption rates and energy use while preserving the textural characteristics of the sorbents. The key objectives of the CARMOF project are (1) to build a full demonstrator of a new energy and cost-competitive dry separation process for post-combustion CO2 capture based on hybrid porous Metal organic frameworks (MOFs) &amp; Carbon Nanotubes (CNTs) (2) to design customized, high packed density &amp; low pressure drop structures based on 3D printing technologies containing hybrid MOF/CNT to be used in CO2 capture system based on fluidized beds. The morphology of the printed absorber will be designed for the specific gas composition of each of the selected industries (ceramic, petrol products and steel) and (3) to optimize the CO2 desorption process by means of Joule effect combined with a vacuum temperature swing adsorption (VTSA)/membrane technology that will surpass the efficiency of the conventional heating procedures</objective>
  <title>CARMOF: New process for efficient CO2 capture by innovative adsorbents based on modified carbon nanotubes and MOF materials</title>
<identifier>H2020NMBP2017twostage</identifier>
</project>
