<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210048</rcn>
  <acronym>NewHoRRIzon</acronym>
  <objective>The Project “Excellence in science and innovation for Europe by adopting the concept of Responsible Research and Innovation (NewHoRRIzon)” sets out to promote the acceptance of RRI in Horizon 2020 (H2020) and beyond. It will work out the conceptual and operational basis to fully integrate RRI into European and national research and innovation (R&amp;I) practice and funding. In order to accomplish this goal, NewHoRRIzon will establish altogether 18 Social Labs that cover all sections of H2020. Together with a wide-ranging group of R&amp;I stakeholders, in these Social Labs, NewHoRRIzon will co-create tailor-made pilot actions that will stimulate an increased use and acceptance of RRI across H2020 and each of its parts. These pilot actions will address a variety of R&amp;I actors such as academia, business, non-university research institutes, research funding organisations, policy-makers on European, Member State and global level, civil society organisations (CSOs) and the general and specific public(s) as they arise from technological controversies. Ultimately, the pilot actions to be developed and tested in the Social Labs will contribute to R&amp;I projects that fully recognise the significance of RRI. NewHoRRIzon will stimulate learning about how to accomplish RRI in H2020 and beyond in its Social Labs, in two cross-sectional workshops and two transdisciplinary conferences. It will conceptualise and operationalise a Society Readiness Level (SRL) for R&amp;I that focuses on the alignment between the processes and products of R&amp;I on the one hand, and broader societal demands and expectations on the other. Finally, NewHoRRIzon will use a variety of target-group specific strategies to disseminate best practises to promote acceptance of RRI across H2020 and generate long-term impact. For that it will use existing spaces and networks as well as create new ones.</objective>
  <title>Excellence in science and innovation for Europe by adopting the concept of Responsible Research and Innovation</title>
<identifier>H2020SwafS20161</identifier>
</project>
