<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196694</rcn>
  <acronym>HyPoGA</acronym>
  <objective>Worldwide, over 280.000 General Aviation (GA) aircrafts are in use (28.000 in Europe) and most aircraft in this engine-power
class (approx. 200 kW) are operated several hours per day in commercial services. The total operating costs are about 213
T€ per year. Combustion engines are designed for the maximum power needed for take-off and climbs (peak-loading),
though in cruise flight only approx. 65 % of the power is required. The overall objective of the HyPoGA innovation project is
to develop a superefficient, hybridized 200 kW aircraft engine by integration of a 140 kW combustion and a 60 kW electrical
engine which will allow a fuel reduction of about 30% and a total cost reduction of 27% ~ 48 T€. This engine will be certified as a
replacement unit according to EU and US aviation laws and regulations. The annual demand for replacement engines is
~3.000. The additional weight of the electrical components (electrical engine, batteries) is counter played by the weight
reduction of a smaller combustion engine and the fuel savings. The innovative power train will contribute significantly to
reduced costs of operations and a massive reduction of CO2 emission. Furthermore, the electrical engine constitutes a
back-up increasing the safety of aircraft operations (two engines instead of one). These aspects create a unique selling point
and competitive advantage for potential customers.

The objectives of the feasibility study are (i) a market research study and analysis (SWOT-Analysis), (ii) a technological
feasibility (e.g. final design definition) and (iii) an economic and financial feasibility (including marketing strategy, certification,
financial plan). The results will be elaborated in a business plan.</objective>
  <title>Feasibility study of a superefficient hybrid power train as a replacement unit for existing engines - Hybrid Power for General Aviation (HyPoGA)</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
