<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211605</rcn>
  <acronym>EFINED</acronym>
  <objective>This project aims for revolutionary energy filtering nano-devices for information and communications technology (ICT). It is at the intersection of phononics, photonics, nanoscale electro-thermal devices and molecular engineering. By building new energy filtering devices down to molecular scales we aim to generate new knowledge and understanding of the electronic, phononic and near-field energy/heat fluxes at the fundamental limits of nano-scale energy management, and to demonstrate novel proof-of-concept non-equilibrium phonon engineered electro-thermal devices in real applications. The efficient nano-scale thermal management necessitate developing new theoretical and experimental tools for understanding and mastering the individual non-equilibrium energy/particle channels and inter-channel couplings. Control of the physical mechanisms behind non-equilibrium electronic energy filtering effects will be firstly addressed by non-linear transport in molecular junctions by developing new research tools that combine state-of-the-art molecular synthesis, bolometers, scanning probe microscopy technologies and theoretical modelling. In parallel with the molecular bottom-up approach, we will work with scalable thermionic nano-junctions, which not only have great technological potential of their own but also serve as a model system for the molecular devices. By employing non-linear out of equilibrium electro-thermal effects in molecular and scaled-down junction systems, we pursue the realization of proof-of-concept ICT devices utilizing these technologies within the time span of the project. This project will combine synergies in theory, experiment and technology-development covering different fields from chemistry to electronics. The project partners, who are leaders in their respective fields, form a consortium that is uniquely positioned to achieve the ambitious objectives.</objective>
  <title>Energy Filtering Non-Equilibrium Devices</title>
<identifier>H2020FETOPEN120162017</identifier>
</project>
