<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212165</rcn>
  <acronym>ST WI-FI</acronym>
  <objective>A new, disruptive, more economic and effective model of simultaneous translation system for the international events,
consisting in a cloud based software platform that handles all operations through Internet, with built-in configuration of the
related Wi-Fi networks and the possibility to use remotely connected professional interpreters chosen from a vast accredited
community. The same system can also be integrated within other popular web-conferencing platforms, enabling
multilanguage
web meetings.
ST WI-FI facilitates access and participation to live and on-line meetings &amp; events to multilanguage audiences, removing
geographic and language barriers, contributing to widespread dissemination of their contents.
Existing simultaneous translation systems are based upon specific, dedicated IR (infrared) equipment, which need to be
rented and installed at each event at relevant costs. ST WI-FI handles their same functionalities and workflow but uses
Internet and Wi-Fi instead of IR as means of communication. Event participants listen to translations through their own
mobile devices, not anymore considered as a limiting factor due to their widespread adoption.
For all live-events, ST WI-FI dramatically reduces all rental, setup and management costs connected to legacy IR systems
and enables further functionalities and options otherwise available through other different dedicated systems. For webbased
meetings and conferences, it provides multi-language interpreting facilities currently unavailable within existing
platforms.
ST WI-FI will be proposed to the market as SaaS, in different subscription packages. Customers will use their own
interpreters or engage them from the same platform at convenient pay-per-hour fees.
ST WI-FI has been awarded with the Seal of Excellence in its precedent proposals to Horizon 2020 SME2 (evaluation result:
12,91 in June 2016, 12,68 in October 2016 and 13,25 in April 2017.</objective>
  <title>Innovative model of a simultaneous translation service, consisting in a cloud-based softwareplatform that delivers audio translations to venue audience through automated managed Wi-Finetworks.</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST220162017</identifier>
</project>
