<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196638</rcn>
  <acronym>SEDEUF</acronym>
  <objective>Sedicii Innovations was formalised in December2013 with the objective to commercialise, promote &amp; support innovative methods of authenticating users online (based on 4 years of academic research).Achievements include US Patent,Independent Audit receipt, BT winner, shortlisted with TechCrunch, MasterCard,&amp;others and 2 pilots (BT &amp; Gemalto).We received positive feed back &amp;have identified many opportunities in gaining market/user acceptance.This feasibility study will help further research &amp; address such opportunities/challenges to establish reference clients&amp;users in building a sustainable business.Challenges include:A.Gain paying customers&amp;market creditability through reference users, coupled with independent, endorsementsB.To further finance development of the Sedicii solution to meet with market needs. Sedicii’s method of authenticating a user can be applied to different user authentication needs.These include: a)Single Sign-On Authentication:Market Value of over €1 Billion annually.b)Credit Card Tokenization: Market Value of $5BN annually.c)Identity Verification: Market Value in excess of €5BN annually.Sedicii’s methods will benefit both consumers &amp; suppliers of digital commerce/services.The ability to authenticate a user without the need to store or expose the personal information of the user will provide significant benefits to holders of such data. With the imminent development of new &amp; evolving markets based on the “Internet of Things”, it is expected that over 100BN devices will be connected to the internet in the future, which will require stronger security,authentication to protect personal data.Sedicii expects to achieve 3objectives during the feasibility study:1.Identify targeted customers in defining the Sedicii solution to meet market needs.2.Explore commercial models &amp; secure the regulatory / industry endorsement as part of the launch &amp; commercial efforts.3.Educate/profile to a wider EU audience, including those responsible for data protection/privacy.</objective>
  <title>Sedicii Innovative Authentication</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
