<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211173</rcn>
  <acronym>VIRIDIS MIST</acronym>
  <objective>Residual Barrier Technology Ltd. is an SME set up with the aim of developing disruptive, green sanitation products while
delivering higher performance than state of the art solutions and thus achieve impact globally.
Disinfectants are relied on as the last line of defense against ever-evolving bacteria and viruses – but due to current
chemistry they come with inherent disadvantages including, toxic/mutagenic ingredient use and offers no residual protection.
Methods application such as spraying, fogging and fumigation are time and labour intensive and provide inconsistent and
incomplete coverage.
We have developed VIRIDIS a patent pending non-toxic, non-mutagenic platform disinfectant that is a breakthrough in the
fight to effectively eradicate bacterial pathogens, spoilage organisms, and viruses. However, VIRIDIS MIST does not stop
there – once deposited on a surface the advanced micelles holding the active ingredients crystallise to create a protective
residual barrier that has been independently proven to continue to kill bacteria for days even when dry - preventing them
from rebuilding or mutating to form a resistance.
We currently work with clients in the food processing and agriculture market to design and fit bespoke large scale residual
misting systems for their facilities operating on a service charge model. However, there is a considerable expense and time
involved in installing the network of fixed pipes and nozzles at their sites – making it cost prohibitive in small to medium sites
and impossible to implement in haulage and shipping contexts. VIRIDIS MIST will service this much larger market micromedium
scale market through the use of autonomous mobile apparatus. We are requesting funding for the development and
production of 24 demonstrator application (8 x 3 different sizes) systems to gain customer confidence among our suppliers
and end users.</objective>
  <title>A toxin-free, food-safe, autonomous mobile misting disinfection system that eradicates pathogenswithin 5 minutes and gives residual protection for 24 hours reducing the need for water and antibiotics</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
