<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>198746</rcn>
  <acronym>KAM2EastPoland</acronym>
  <objective>Main objective of the project is increasing efficiency and effectiveness of R&amp;D and innovation investments which will contribute to smart growth in EU countries. The project also focuses on strengthening of collaboration between different actors important in innovation chain. Innovation development among SMEs (99% of enterprises in EU) is crucial to smart and sustainable growth. 

Specific objectives will be implemented by Enterprise Europe Network East Poland Consortium. Project duration is forseen for 24 months and will end by the end of December 2016. Within the Consortium – 10 WP 1 “Key account management” services packages and 36 WP2 “Enhancing the innovation management capacity of SMEs” service packages are foreseen. Number of service packages planned is based on economic indicators and Enterprise Europe Network experts’ experience.

The Enterprise Europe Network is the biggest network in Europe that provides high quality and specialised support for SMEs. The Network was established in 2008 and will still be operating in years 2015-2020, thus has great potential to provide additional support services for companies with possibilities for international growth and innovation implementation. 
Five Enterprise Europe Network partners in lubelskie, podlaskie and warminsko-mazurskie voivodeship are ready to participate in the action with the following input:
Lublin Development Foundation - P1 - 2 service packages,
Lublin University of Technology - P2 - 12 service packages
Podlaska Regional Development Foundation P3 - 10 service packages
University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn - P4 - 12 service packages
Warmia and Mazury Regional Development Agency - P5 - 10 service packages

The consortium management structure will be based on Enterprise Europe Network East Poland. WP1 and WP2 services will be provided in each region covered by the Consortium.</objective>
  <title>Enhancing the innovation management capacities of SMEs in East Poland</title>
<identifier>H2020Adhoc201420</identifier>
</project>
