<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205810</rcn>
  <acronym>SaferAfrica</acronym>
  <objective>SaferAfrica project aims at establishing a Dialogue Platform between Africa and Europe focused on road safety and traffic management issues. It will represent a high-level body with the main objective of providing recommendations to update the African Road Safety Action Plan and the African Road Safety Charter, as well as fostering the adoption of specific initiatives, properly funded. The involvement of Development Banks will ensure the identification of available resources and the definition of suitable schemes of funding. The activity of the Platform will also focus on the reinforcement of the endogenous African capabilities through the dissemination of the EU know-how. Twinning Programs will be set up, besides the conduction of different training activities. Local contexts will be duly taken into account and studies on specific risk factors as well as transferability analysis of measures already tested elsewhere will be conducted. The project activities will be oriented to the “Safe System” approach and grouped in four pillars: Road Safety Knowledge and Data; Road Safety and Traffic management Capacity Review; Capacity Building and Training; Sharing of Good Practices. 
The platform will work at two levels. A decision making level, run by a Management Board basing its actions on information provided and activities carried out by a technical level, with established Working Groups addressing specific topics. The Management Board will be constituted by prominent institutions like EC, the African Union Commission, Financial Institutions, Regional Economic Communities (UN). The technical level will involve government and research institutions, international and stakeholders organizations (e.g. NGOs), with a fair balance between African and EU partners, even for what concerns responsibilities (e.g. Euro-African work package co-leadership). The Dialogue Platform is intended to constitute a stable body, able to orient road safety policies beyond the project end.</objective>
  <title>Innovating dialogue and problems appraisal for a safer Africa</title>
<identifier>H2020MG2016SingleStageRTDMOVE</identifier>
</project>
