<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212681</rcn>
  <acronym>EURO SHOCK</acronym>
  <objective>Heart attacks are common and can leave survivors suffering cardiogenic shock (CGS), with its extremely high risk of early death (42% versus 4% for non-CGS) and high incidence of  chronic heart failure, with its associated socio-economic disease burden (ill-health, recurrent heart failure admissions, no return to full time activities, need for expensive therapeutic devices and life-long drugs). Outcomes from CGS are even worse in, females, the elderly (mortality&gt;70%) and high risk sub-groups. The incidence of CGS in Europe alone is &gt;50 000 patients pa. This unacceptably high mortality/morbidity rate represents a true unmet clinical need. No clear strategy exists to improve outcomes, with ad hoc therapies given too late in a spiralling, irrecoverable process.
EURO SHOCK aims to improve outcomes for CGS patients. At its core is a robust phase3 randomised trial comparing a novel strategy of very early use of ECMO (Extracorporeal Membrane Oxygenation) to current standard of care. Evidence suggests very early ECMO will halt the spiral of decline and so significantly reduce 12 month death rate and need for heart failure re-admissions. Since both costs of CGS, and ECMO are high a health-economic cost efficacy analysis will be core. A cardiac magnetic resonance imaging sub-study will test novel protocols in sick patients and provide mechanistic data. We will test transfer networks for CGS patients and analyse ECG data to determine which patients benefit most from early transfer.
Our multidisciplinary consortium comprises renowned physician-scientists, statisticians, health economists and technology providers, including specialised ECMO SME. 
EURO SHOCK will impact on heart attack survivors, healthcare providers and Europe`s medical technology sector by 1) reducing healthcare costs associated with CGS 2) provide novel cost effective framework for cardiac interventions 3) delivering innovative healthcare technologies and 4) informing guidelines for effective CGS intervention.</objective>
  <title>Testing the value of a novel strategic approach and its cost efficacy to improve the poor outcomes in Cardiogenic Shock</title>
<identifier>H2020SC12017TwoStageRTD</identifier>
</project>
