<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207637</rcn>
  <acronym>STILORMADE</acronym>
  <objective>STILORMADE will validate an innovative technology platform (developed by S’Tile) for the design and manufacture
of customized (non-standard) photovoltaic modules achieving &gt;18% module efficiency with tailored mode of
operation (current and voltage), &gt;99% production reproducibility, operational thermal (environmental) stability, and
mechanical flexibility; at a production cost of &lt;€0.7/Watt. Such advancements represent a &gt;50% power (efficiency)
improvement compared to existing custom modules at &gt;30% lower costs. The design freedoms enabled by the
STILORMADE platform empower product designers to fully integrate customized PV systems into their product
architectures with beautiful / stylised aesthetic appeal and without compromising performance or cost. Flexible
automated production processes enable the platform to rapidly reconfigure to the needs of niche markets enabling
rapid growth through mass customisation. Cell and module design and simulation software developed by TU-Wien
will be upgraded to enable faster design and optimisation of custom modules meeting unique client requirements. The
customised modules will be integrated into two product applications (Building Integrated Photovoltaics and Solar Street
Lighting) representing two of the largest markets for non-standard solar cells and validated at market replication sites
in Spain, Israel and France. Market replication results will be demonstrated to over300 potential users (manufacturers
of solar street lighting products, architects, construction companies, etc…) and stakeholders to accelerate market takeup
and exploitation. This will enable the consortium to capture ~1.5% of the €7 billion global customised modules
market five years after commercialisation, translating to consortium revenues of over €200m and a &gt;66 fold return
on investment.</objective>
  <title>Highly efficient non-standard solar modules manufactured through an automated,reconfigurable mass production processes delivering 30% reduction in costs</title>
<identifier>H2020FTIPilot20161</identifier>
</project>
