<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205951</rcn>
  <acronym>EURO-CAS</acronym>
  <objective>EURO-CAS, European eHealth Interoperability Conformity Assessment Scheme aims at maintaining and developing the adoption and take-up of testing the interoperability of ICT solutions against identified eHealth standards and profiles defined in the eHealth European Interoperability Framework (eEIF). The key deliverable is a sustainable Conformity Assessment Scheme (CAS) for Europe. Based on recommendations of the Antilope project and the state-of-art in interoperability testing in eHealth, EURO-CAS is committed to putting in place an operational CAS based on ISO/IEC 17025 that will meet the interoperability requirements of European eHealth projects as well as national and regional eHealth programs. This will allow testing the interoperability capabilities of products and services for a single digital market in eHealth in Europe in line with the Digital Agenda for Europe and based on international profiles and standards. The project will gather a multi-disciplinary consortium of high-level expertise, including organizations focused on implementing international standards as well as industry stakeholders and healthcare providers that will 1) review the state of the art of existing interoperability CAS, 2) collect the requirements and needs from cross border, national/regional levels, 3) establish the CAS for Europe with implementation guidelines and governance, 4) propose business models for the CAS for Europe, 5) validate results and foresee national/regional adoption, 6) inform and educate eHealth stakeholders and motivate industry and projects to participate in a European accreditation process. The CAS for Europe will provide a comprehensive framework completing the eEIF and aligned with the international CAS. Its flexibility will allow better sustainability and harmonization at European, national and regional levels.</objective>
  <title>EU eHealth Interoperability Conformity Assessment Scheme</title>
<identifier>H2020SC12016CNECT</identifier>
</project>
