<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>194855</rcn>
  <acronym>IECEU</acronym>
  <objective>The European Union (EU) is increasingly affected and challenged by geopolitical changes, increasing impact of conflict on civilians, globalized impact of local conflicts, technological developments and budgetary constraints challenges the Radicalization, the growing potential for individuals to create large security threats and transnational criminality further complicates the security landscape of EU missions. With global interconnectedness, the repercussions of outside conflict are also seen within the EU, and may lead to societal and security challenges within the EU. The key issue for the EU is how to improve its conflict response capabilities to create more lasting impact on the ground and to use limited resources more effectively. Comprehensive EU-security within the EU emphasizes the need for civil-military synergies, which correspond more closely to challenges on the ground and the incorporation of very different perspectives, priorities and operational cultures.  
The IECEU–project analyses and assesses best practices and lessons learned with a view to enhance the civilian conflict prevention and peace building capabilities of EU with a catalogue of practices, new solutions and approaches. It will seek to find out how to increase the interoperability of resources in the crisis management and peace building and what the potential for pooling and sharing of EU capabilities and technologies is. The main goals of the IECEU -project are:
1) Analysing and assessing the current situation of on-going and past missions and operations
2) Learning from lessons provided by these missions and assessing the different options 
3) Providing new solutions, approaches and recommendations for EU to guarantee long-term stability</objective>
  <title>Improving the Effectiveness of the Capabilities (IEC) in EU conflict prevention</title>
<identifier>H2020BES2014</identifier>
</project>
