<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>194380</rcn>
  <acronym>RISE_BPM</acronym>
  <objective>RISE_BPM networks world-leading research institutions and corporate innovators to develop new horizons for Business Process Management (BPM). BPM is a boundary-spanning discipline focused on division and re-integration of day-to-day work in organisations and on analysis of process data for organisational decision-making. Recent break-through innovations in Social Computing, Smart Devices, Real-Time Computing, and Big Data Technology create a strong impetus for propelling BPM into a pervasive corporate topic that enables design of entirely new products and services.
All RISE_BPM consortium members possess excellent expertise in distinct aspects of the BPM lifecycle, ranging from Strategy and Modelling to Implementation and Analysis of business processes. RISE_BPM networks this complementary knowledge to create a unique environment for BPM research and innovation. The research activities are organised with reference to the design-science paradigm, including joint activities for analysing technological enablers and societal impact factors, as well as designing innovative IT artefacts for the BPM lifecycle.
Staff secondments and joint events promote a cumulative exchange of knowledge in a think-pair-square-share approach that networks large-scale research capabilities and innovation projects carried out by the involved organisations. Key objectives of RISE_BPM are (a) to propel BPM research into the era of Social Computing, Smart Devices, Real-Time Computing, and Big Data Technology; (b) to enable companies to develop new products and services for designing and analysing business processes; and (c) to supply the involved staff with a unique intellectual environment for accumulating boundary-spanning knowledge and skills that refer to the entire BPM lifecycle.
RISE_BPM extends the established administrative structures of the European Research Center for Information Systems (ERCIS) by involving additional BPM thought leaders and corporate innovators.</objective>
  <title>Propelling Business Process Management by Research and Innovation Staff Exchange</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCARISE2014</identifier>
</project>
