<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210592</rcn>
  <acronym>Net-UBIEP</acronym>
  <objective>The building sector is the largest consumer of energy in Europe,  accounting for nearly 40% of the total consumption (EPBD 2010/31/EU). Furthermore the 2030 European Energy [COM(2014)16Final] and Energy Roadmap 2050 [COM(2011) 885 final], strongly requires more focus on the energy  efficiency on housing sector.
Finally, the Directive 2014/24/EU of the European Parliament and of the Council on public procurement, requires that all member states introduce electronic means to exchange information and communication in procurement procedures. 
For these reasons we believe that the integrated approach of the Net-UBIEP project, based on Building information Modelling, integrated with energy  performance requirements, will be key to solve all the problems in a more effective and efficient manner.
The project proposes BIM Qualification Models integrated with energy competences,  to  widespread a better comprehension of energy issues along all the value chain of building industry so that both existing and new building will have better energy performances.  Public Administrations, Professionals (Engineers /  Architects), Technicians (Installers / Maintainers) and Tenants will be therefore involved in the Net-UBIEP activities.
The definition of the BIM Qualification Models will pass through the  identification of specific energy BIM competences for each of the above target needed to implement BIM models during the whole building life cycle.  During the project the “integrated” BIM Qualification Models will be validated by stakeholders thanks to the delivering of  different training activities (Seminars / Classrooms Courses /  E-Learning Courses) addressed to at least six BIM Professional Profiles: BIM Manager, BIM Evaluator, BIM Coordinator, BIM Expert, BIM facility manager, BIM user. Once the schemes will be validated, they will be proposed for standardization to find  a broader acceptance at European and international level through regulatory  organizations (CEN / ISO).</objective>
  <title>Network for Using BIM to Increase the Energy Performance</title>
<identifier>H2020EE2016CSA</identifier>
</project>
