<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>194396</rcn>
  <acronym>WeLive</acronym>
  <objective>The WeLive project is devised to transform the current e-government approach by facilitating a more open model of design, production and delivery of public services leveraging on the collaboration between public administrations (PAs), citizens and entrepreneurs. WeLive applies the quadruple-helix approach based on the joint collaboration of 3 PAs, 4 research agents and 5 companies, constituing the consortium, plus citizens to deliver next generation personalised user-centric public services. WeLive aims to bridge the gap between innovation and adoption (i.e. take-up) of open government services. For that, it contributes with the WeLive Framework, an ICT infrastructure which adapts, enhances, extends and integrates Open Innovation, Open Data and Open Services components selected from consortium partners’ previous projects. An Open Innovation Area is proposed where stakeholders collaborate in the ideation, creation, funding and deployment of new services. A Visual Composer will enable non-ICT users to assemble public service apps from existing blocks. Stakeholders will upload/sell and download/purchase the generated apps to/from the WeLive Marketplace, thus impulsing economic activity around public services. Personalization and analytics of public services will be done through collaboration of the Citizen Data Vault, which manages personal information, with the Decision Engine, which matchmakes user preferences, profile and context against available public services. Two-phase pilots will be conducted in 3 cities (Bilbao, Novi Sad and Trento) and 1 region (Helsinki- Uusimaa) across Europe. Further, the business feasibility and commercial potential of the WeLive Framework, including its individual assets, will be validated by developing and deploying sustainable business models.</objective>
  <title>A neW concept of pubLic administration based on citizen co-created mobile urban services</title>
<identifier>H2020INSO2014</identifier>
</project>
