<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206818</rcn>
  <acronym>pCPR</acronym>
  <objective>Sudden cardiac arrest affects up to 1 million people in US and Europe per year, being the 3rd leading cause of death globally. Despite international medical efforts, 9 out of 10 people will die after a cardiac arrest (average survival rate 10.6%). In the European Union, cardiovascular disease costs to the economy more than €192 billion annually.
Emergency teams suffer the most with the extremely high mortality and morbidity rates due to cardiac arrest worldwide. Currently, medical assistive devices play a limited role on teams’ diagnostics and therapeutic actions during rescue emergencies. Nevertheless, the defibrillation/CPR devices global market was valued at $1.7B in 2014 and is expected to grow until 2019 with a CAGR of 8% reflecting a strong market demand.
pCPR is a portable, precise and personalized medical device to properly assist emergency teams during sudden cardiac arrest emergencies. It consists of a thoracic pad with sensors that doctors, nurses and paramedics apply directly to the patient linked to a new monitor display and defibrillator to support and guide their critical decision-making and patient-specific emergent therapy.
The value proposition of pCPR is based on emergency end-users’ feedback and experts’ calls for action, through a lean fast-to-market strategy, delivering unique selling points: 
- Adaptive physiological feedback (disruptive innovation);
- Focus on cerebral oxygen saturation, temperature and tcCO2 (new target indicators);
- Clinical reasoning algorithms (cognitive aids at point of care);
- Cardiac/Neurologic outcomes guidance (assisting device);
- Data management for Quality control (analytics);
- Exclusively non-invasive sensors (technology);
pCPR wants to be one of the leading assistive device for emergency teams worldwide in a 5-years’ time frame, building upon its patented thoracic pad and combined sensing capabilities to deliver better cost-effective patient care and health outcomes, namely the cardiac arrest survival rate.</objective>
  <title>Personalized cardiopulmonary resuscitation device for emergency teams</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
