<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206365</rcn>
  <acronym>CRISS</acronym>
  <objective>CRISS is a user-driven, flexible, scalable and cost-effective cloud-based digital learning ecosystem that allows the guided acquisition, evaluation and certification of digital competences in primary and secondary education, and easily scalable to other educational levels. CRISS proposes an innovative adaptive learning solution supported by the most advanced pedagogical methodologies and technologies that will be tested with a very large scale pilot with more than 490 schools including 25.400 students and 2.290 teachers across Europe.

CRISS aim to contribute to the modernisation of the educational and training system at different levels:
a) Support schools and educational institutions in the definition and creation of a curricular programming aligned to European and national policies, encouraging the active participation of all teachers and creating an interdisciplinary framework and highly diversified contents, activities and educational experiences for the acquisition and evaluation digital competences of students.
b) Offers teachers and students an adaptive and intelligent environment for personalizing the process of teaching and learning that allows them to easily and dynamically generate and integrate programming a wide variety of new learning experiences and integrate new methodologies, fostering a creative and motivating use of technologies focused on minimizing the distance between digital competences acquired at school and the required in the labour market. 
c) Through its learning analytics module CRISS can generate an innovative and unique student ICT Dynamic Profile, showing strengths and weaknesses, achievements, interests, skills acquired, certification and other recognition, on the one hand facilitating the personalization of teaching / learning, and on the other the entry into the labour world.
d) Thanks to its evaluation and certification of digital competences will contribute to the standardization of digital competences at European level.</objective>
  <title>Demonstration of a scalable and cost-effective cloud-based digital learning infrastructure through the Certification of digital competences in primary and secondary schools</title>
<identifier>H2020ICT20161</identifier>
</project>
