<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>202649</rcn>
  <acronym>ENSUF</acronym>
  <objective>The JPI for Urban Europe ERA-NET co-fund Smart Urban Futures (ENSUF) objectives are:
- To tackle fragmentation and the implementation gap. 
- To contribute to integrated sustainable urban development. 
- To strengthen European urban research and innovation alignment. 
- To scale up and translate best practices. 
- To develop, analyse and test new strategies and technologies of urban governance and urban living in order to shape the economic, social and environmental needs of citizens for sustainable urban development.

ENSUF will call for transnational research and innovation projects that operationalise and translate a framework of three main elements, and launch the Urban Europe response to the implementation gap in sustainable urban development. The three main elements are: 
- Transdiciplinary co-creation in research and innovation. 
- Smart integrated urban development. 
- Utilizing the spatial dimensions and processes of urban areas. 

These three elements will be integrated by transnational, forward-looking and comparative research and innovation projects focused on the following three priority call topics: 
- Concepts and strategies for smart urban transformation, growth and shrinkage
- New dynamics of public services
- Inclusive, vibrant and accessible urban communities

The ENSUF Cofund proposal responds to the Horizon 2020 work programme for 2014 call ‘EURO-5-2015: ERA–NET on Smart Urban Futures, Overcoming the Crisis: New Ideas, Strategies and Governance Structures for Europe’. The EURO-5 call scope is to analyse strengths and weaknesses of current models of urban development, in order to improve knowledge and to identify and shape urban needs. In response, ENSUF will deliver (a) knowledge (strengths and weaknesses of urban development); (b) methodologies (new methods, tools and network approaches) and (c) a validation/assessment of the co-creation model and (d) outline new pathways for urban development.</objective>
  <title>ERA-NET Cofund Smart Urban Futures</title>
<identifier>H2020EUROSOCIETY2015</identifier>
</project>
