<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211529</rcn>
  <acronym>TRANSVAC2</acronym>
  <objective>TRANSVAC2 is the follow-up project to its successful predecessor project TRANSVAC, the European Network of Vaccine Research and Development funded under FP7. The TRANSVAC2 consortium comprises a comprehensive collection of leading European institutions that propose to further advance with the previous initiative towards the establishment of a fully operational and sustainable European vaccine R&amp;D infrastructure. TRANSVAC2 will support innovation for both prophylactic and therapeutic vaccine development based on a disease-overarching and one-health approach, thereby optimising the knowledge and expertise gained during the development of both human and animal vaccines. This will be achieved by bridging the translational gap in biomedical research, and by supporting cooperation between public vaccine R&amp;D institutions of excellence, related initiatives and networks in Europe, and industrial partners. TRANSVAC2 will complement and integrate with existing European research infrastructures in both the public and private sectors. TRANSVAC2 will function as leverage and innovation catalyst between all stakeholders involved in vaccine R&amp;D in Europe and -by providing integrated and overarching vaccine R&amp;D services- will contribute to the development of effective products to address European and global health challenges, to controlling the burden and spread of infectious diseases, and reinforce the economic assets represented by vaccine developers in Europe.
The impact of TRANSVAC2 will be maximised by two external advisory bodies. An independent Scientific &amp; Ethics Advisory Committee will provide recommendations surrounding scientific-technical and ethical issues, whereas the coordination of TRANSVAC2 with other related initiatives and the further promotion of the long-term stability of a European vaccine R&amp;D infrastructure will be supported by a Board of Stakeholders comprising representatives of policy and decision makers, industry associations and European infrastructures.</objective>
  <title>European Vaccine Research and Development Infrastructure</title>
<identifier>H2020INFRAIA20161</identifier>
</project>
