<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211498</rcn>
  <acronym>ConCare</acronym>
  <objective>Intensive Care Units (ICUs), where critically ill patients are cared for by specialized care providers, paradoxically represent
a life-threatening environment for 100% of patients: while ICU stay usually lasts &lt;1 week, 90% of ICU survivors show
catastrophic, long-term consequences. This happens because dangerous complications are often addressed too late,
leading to increased mortality risk. In addition, noise and light levels in Intensive Care Units are too high and induce sleep
deprivation: a condition that often leads to delirium. Clinical evidence shows that ICU-acquired co-morbidities should be prevented and addressed by a multi-disciplinary team made of clinicians, families, nurses, therapists. The goal is to deliver seamless patient of care from the first hour in the ICU, up to the discharge in the ward and then at home. Current clinical practice, though, is not able, alone, to deliver an effective and scalable continuum of care.
   Thanks to years of research and clinical trials, Cognuse developed an IT platform capable of disrupting the patients’ care
with comprehensive interfaces for everyone in the care loop. By providing each ICU bed with one tablet, patients, clinicians
and families are empowered. The detection of complications is made quick and effective; an automatized system allows to
monitor and reduce environmental stressors; families are involved in the care loop and informed; patients themselves are
supported and challenged in exercising to recover better. After testing their solution in USA, the Estonian Company Cognuse
aims at disrupting now the critical care in Europe.
   During Phase 1 project the Company will assess software expansion and scale-up plan, will conduct clinical trials for
validation and software certification and will establish a sound go-to- market strategy to ensure a swift market uptake of the
proposed solution.</objective>
  <title>Leveraging the scalability of mobile devices to improve the outcome of all critically ill patients: a multi-faceted health platform to enable the continuum of care from ICU to home.</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
