<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>209458</rcn>
  <acronym>AMYPAD</acronym>
  <objective>Beta-amyloid (β-amyloid) deposition is considered to be a necessary - but not sufficient - step on the path towards Alzheimer’s disease (AD).  Depiction of brain β-amyloid in vivo can support an early diagnosis, and even provide an opportunity for consider secondary prevention of AD. Currently, however, the value of β-amyloid PET remains elusive, reason why this procedure is typically not reimbursed.
Understanding the value of imaging of β-amyloid using positron emission tomography (PET) provides a unique opportunity to achieve 3 major goals: 1) improve the diagnostic workup of patients suspected of AD and their management; 2) stratify risk for AD and select homogenous groups for intervention; and 3) quantify treatment effects more accurately.  
AMYPAD will address the above objectives by studying the onset, dynamics and clinical relevance of brain β-amyloid in the spectrum from normal aging to preclinical and prodromal AD. We will use β-amyloid-PET in an unprecedented large number of subjects (n=4000) from population studies, as well as memory clinics cohorts, with repeat imaging in up to 2000. In close collaboration with EPAD (www.ep-ad.org), the cohorts will be followed with to determine (surrogate) outcomes of cognitive decline and neurodegeneration. 
Lead from VU-VUmc, the Consortium brings together a word-class team of highly synergistic partners from across Europe constituting a highly experienced and efficient β-amyloid imaging network including the most active European PET sites, to ensure effective tracer delivery, access to patients and expertise to technical knowledge and disease modelling. 
AMYPAD will establish the true value of β-amyloid PET across the severity range of AD. Patients and clinicians will benefit from better and cost-effective diagnostic procedures and management, while academics and industry will benefit from better disease understanding, clear reimbursement strategy and more rationale and efficient clinical trial design.</objective>
  <title>Amyloid imaging to Prevent Alzheimer’s Disease</title>
<identifier>H2020JTIIMI2201505twostage</identifier>
</project>
