<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>213376</rcn>
  <acronym>ReIReS</acronym>
  <objective>ReIReS is a starting community whose aim is to create a unique and groundbreaking research infrastructure (RI) on religious studies within the European Research Area. It joints the major European research institutions working in the domain (universities, libraries, archives, academies, research institutions, and museums) to improve the access of scholars from all over the world to the data, information and sources concerning the study of the historical and cultural influence of the plural religious heritage in the European history. Furthermore, it joints research activities of the partners, integrating complementary scientific skills and capabilities, and it organizes networking activities for fostering a culture of co-operation between national research facilities, scientific communities, and other stakeholders including policy makers. ReIReS creates a synergy between the partners, offering a transnational and virtual access to the most significant tools and sources in the field of religious studies. This grants to the research communities the use of the major tools joint within a comprehensive infrastructure and gives to the EU a leading role in a domain, which is becoming more and more crucial for the understanding of inter-cultural dynamics and facing conflicts of our time. Dealing with the need for an appropriate comprehension of a complex and multicultural society, ReIReS consortium works towards the improvement of the integrated services of the partners. It aims to establish a distributed RI with a sustainable plan of activities, including offering access to a wide range of high-level data and tools for advancing knowledge and innovation in the understanding of inter-religious society.</objective>
  <title>Research Infrastructure on Religious Studies</title>
<identifier>H2020INFRAIA20171twostage</identifier>
</project>
