<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206010</rcn>
  <acronym>EMEurope</acronym>
  <objective>In collaboration with the European Commission and the European Green Vehicles Initiative Association, European countries and regions will set-up an ERA-NET Cofund to further promote electric mobility in Europe. Electric Mobility Europe builds on the experiences, networks and results of Electromobility+ and is designed to take transnational e-mobility research and policy exchange to the next level.

With a two-track approach, the initiative will link research and policy practice in support of electric mobility at the European level.

The first of two pillars of Electric Mobility Europe will fund innovation projects focussing on the application and demonstration of e-mobility with the objective of advancing the mainstreaming of the electrification of mobility in Europe. The initiative will bring together about 30 million EUR for supporting applied innovation projects, including up to 10 million EUR of co-funding provided by the European Commission under Horizon 2020.
In 2016, the initiative will issue a call for project proposals addressing the key areas of electric mobility:
1. System integration (transport, (sub)urban areas)
2. Integration of urban freight and city logistics in the e-mobility
3. Smart Mobility concepts and ICT applications
4. Public transport
5. Consumer behaviour and societal trends

In addition to funding innovation and demonstration projects, the ERA-NET Cofund Electric Mobility Europe will establish a second pillar of activity. The network will provide a platform for cooperation and exchange of information and experiences among participating countries and regions. In this context, know-how will be shared on setting conducive conditions for the development of electric mobility in Europe (e.g. on charging infrastructure). The network will support this by facilitating suitable means of cooperation such as workshops or seminars in order to exchange or coordinate required actions, in attunement with the European Green Vehicle Initiative Association.</objective>
  <title>ERA-NET Cofund Electric Mobility Europe</title>
<identifier>H2020GV2016RTD</identifier>
</project>
