<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>198925</rcn>
  <acronym>PSR94</acronym>
  <objective>This proposal presents a unique opportunity to commercialise ground-breaking radar technology, a 94GHz Phase Shifting Radar (PSR94). We will bring the PSR94 from the current TRL 6 (technology demonstrated in relevant environment) to TRL 8 (system complete and qualified), ready for TRL 9 (customer use in an operational environment).
This project will overcome the industrial problems, in the AeroSpace sector, associated with scanning beams at high frequency, namely the large physical size of the radar, the large power requirements and also reduced reliability due to the many moving parts. The PSR94 takes an extremely complex difficult method of antenna scanning and replaces it with a small light radar. 
The key advantages of our solution are:
• 94 GHz offers unparalleled radar resolution 
• Only electronically scanning antenna (with no moving parts, solid state) at 94GHz in the world
• Very small and compact (only 20cm diameter)
• Very wide scanning angles (up to 60 degrees)
• Can scan in both elevation and azimuth
• Can also track (monopulse) no need for two radar systems
• Less expensive to manufacture
• Very low power consumption
• Easy to control using near DC voltages 
The wider security radar market is estimated to be valued at $11.6 billion in 2014 (SDI, 2014). Our Target Addressable Market (millimetre wave radar) is growing at a CAGR of 45% and is expected to reach $2 Billion by 2020 (Markets &amp; Markets, 2014).
Arralis will manufacture a commercial demonstrator, which is market ready, for customers in Europe, the US &amp; China. We will engage with identified customers (e2v, Airbus Defence &amp; Space, COBHAM and Thales) to develop and design a system which meets the specific requirements of the end user. We will ensure that the customer market is fully prepared for the launch of the PSR94.
Arralis market strategy is to manufacture MMICs, Modules, Antennas and Sub- systems. The project requires MMICs, Modules and Antennas to be combined in a sub-system, PSR94.</objective>
  <title>Commercialisation of 94GHz Phase Shifting Radar (PSR94)</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST22015</identifier>
</project>
