<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>194915</rcn>
  <acronym>GREST</acronym>
  <objective>The present project is intended to take the European Solar Telescope (EST) to the next level of development by undertaking crucial activities to improve the performance of current state-of-the-art instrumentation. Legal, industrial and socio-economic issues will also be addressed, as key questions for the attainment of EST. The particular developments and strategic tasks proposed here can be summarised in the following specific objectives:
(i) Boosting new generation detectors, with the development of two prototype sensors, one for large-format imaging and a the other for high-precision polarimetry, the evaluation of an existing large format wavefront sensing camera is also addressed;
(ii) Development of a capacitance-stabilised Fabry-Perot prototype for a high quality control of the parallelism of the etalon plates;
(iii) new techniques for 2D solar spectro-polarimetry; with integral field units based on multi-slit image slicers or a microlens-fed spectrograph;
(iv) development of large format liquid-crystal modulators, required for the large-format sensors that will be needed for the new generation large aperture telescopes ;
(v) evaluation of the performance of the EST-MCAO deformable mirrors to improve the design and performance of this system; and
(vi) strategic work to covering industrial, financial and legal issues related the future construction and operation of EST. The following issues will be addressed:
• Elaboration of a census of the European solar physics community
• Analysis of the technological expertise of European companies in the different countries and their potential expertise related with the construction needs of EST
• Revision and update of the construction budget of EST
• Stimulation of a discussion of all these aspects within the consortium EAST
With all these elements in hand, the project will be in the condition to present a definite proposal for detailed design, construction, managing and operation of EST.</objective>
  <title>Getting Ready for EST</title>
<identifier>H2020INFRADEV120141</identifier>
</project>
