<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206179</rcn>
  <acronym>AEGIS</acronym>
  <objective>AEGIS, brings together the data, the network &amp; the technologies to create a curated, semantically enhanced, interlinked &amp; multilingual repository for public &amp; personal safety-related big data. It delivers a data-driven innovation that expands over multiple business sectors &amp; takes into consideration structured, unstructured &amp; multilingual datasets, rejuvenates existing models and facilitates organisations in the Public Safety &amp; Personal Security linked sectors to provide better &amp; personalised services to their users. AEGIS will introduce new business models through the breed of an open ecosystem of innovation &amp; data sharing principles. From the technology perspective, AEGIS targets to revolutionise semantic technologies in big data, big data analytics &amp; visualisations as well as security &amp; privacy frameworks by addressing current challenges &amp; requirements of cross-domain &amp; multilingual applications. The main benefits derived from AEGIS to data identification, collection, harmonisation, storage &amp; utilisation towards value generation for these sectors will be: Unified representation of knowledge; Accelerated, more effective &amp; value-packed cycles of intelligence extraction &amp; of services &amp; applications development; Introduction of novel business models for the data sharing economy &amp; establishment of AEGIS as a prominent big data hub, utilising cryptocurrency algorithms to validate transactions &amp; handle effectively IPRs, data quality &amp; data privacy issues though a business brokerage framework. Based on an early market analysis, the Total Addressable Market of AEGIS is up to $31bn (€27.1bn); AEGIS is able not only to capture a portion of the market size, but also to expand the pie through creating additional uncaptured value based on small data integration in typical big data repositories &amp; algorithms. Based on the same analysis, the project will break even &amp; will be viable from its launch (2020) &amp; will have a ROI investment of EU-commission in the first years.</objective>
  <title>Advanced Big Data Value Chain for Public Safety and Personal Security</title>
<identifier>H2020ICT20161</identifier>
</project>
