<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205673</rcn>
  <acronym>THOMSON</acronym>
  <objective>Mild Hybrid cOst effective solution for a fast Market penetratiON. THOMSON (Mild Hybrid cOst effective solutions for a fast Market penetration) project aims to the development of cost effective solutions, based on 48V architectures, answering the need in reducing the environmental impact of the transportation sector through a clever combination of advanced engines technologies, electrification and wider use of alternative/renewable fuels. 
The project addresses very precise and consistent objectives to support a quick transition towards high efficient, cleaner and affordable electrified powertrains focusing on the 48V architectures, intended as key element to increase fuel economy and reduce environmental impact and to support a quick penetration on the market of the hybrid powertrains.
Approaches developed in the THOMSON project will demonstrate how the right combination of advanced engine downsizing/turbocharging technologies, coupled with a 48V motor-generator system, can provide the most cost effective solution for a rapid electrification through conventional vehicles. 
The project will provide an exhaustive evaluation of this concept through the development of two different 48V architectures (one integrating the e-machine on the front engine belt drive, the other between the engine and the transmission) on two different engine families: on one side a mid-size 1.6 litre Diesel engine and, on the other one, a small downsized Spark Ignited CNG engine equipped with a Direct Injection system. This twin approach will allow to demonstrate how 48V architecture interacts with Diesel technologies (especially with regard to noxious pollutant reduction) and, on the other side, with Spark Ignited CNG ones, emphasizing the CO2 reduction already achieved through the use of a low carbon fuel such as CNG. Moreover, for both engine families, 48V architecture represent an important enabler to introduce electrically driven auxiliaries and sub-systems leading to a global better man</objective>
  <title>Mild Hybrid cOst effective solutions for a fast Market penetratiON</title>
<identifier>H2020GV2016INEA</identifier>
</project>
