<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196283</rcn>
  <acronym>GroundCLeaner</acronym>
  <objective>The business of our company, IEG Technologie GmbH is soil remediation by using our groundwater circulation technologies.
The GroundCLeaner proposal addresses to increase our competitiveness by developing a disruptive, rapid and costeffective
method to remediate soils contaminated by chlorinated volatile organic compounds (CVOC), representing major
threat to the quality of the European environment. The innovative method combines the state of the art ground water
recirculation well (GWC) technology, patented by us, and a recently developed electro-biological treatment. Our aim is to
further exploit the results of the novel technology proposed by providing a wider range of treatment. We aim at marketing this
new combined technology for removal of CVOCs from soil, our services will include design, manufacturing, assembly, startup,
maintenance and operation. The proposed technology targets to reduce the operational costs of remediation up to 70 %.
The success of our solution would strengthen our international position on the market and would make us grow by becoming
market leader for chlorinated compound remediation. During this phase 1 proposal we would like to carry out a technological
feasibility study, market assessment, risk assessment, a study on or freedom to operate, develop a detailed work plan for a
Phase 2 application and elaborate a business plan. After successful phase 1 application we intend do phase 2 proposal, in
which we develop the marketable GroundCleaner technology. The present proposal targets to make a pan-European impact
as it will reduce the estimated €17.3 billion spent by EU countries, and 2.2 billion spent by EU Structural Funds for reversing
the environmental consequences of soil and water pollution caused by industrial and other activities.</objective>
  <title>Fast and cost-effective combined remediation technology for the elimination of chlorinated and otherhydrocarbons from soil</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
