<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206845</rcn>
  <acronym>PJ04 TAM</acronym>
  <objective>Why?: Airport Operations Management in SESAR1 promoted enhanced situational awareness via the Airport Operations Plan (AOP) whilst reinforcing the collaborative decision making process through the Airport Operations Centre (APOC).  Validation activities stressed the need to further develop the Performance Monitoring and Management services promoting the evolution from a reactive ("firefighting") approach toward one of pro-active collaborative decision making.

Impact: Includes the evolution toward a "performance-driven" airport through holistic monitoring of demand and capacity.  Decision making will be based on more reliable information with enhanced decision impact assessment.  Expected is an increase in the predictability, flexibility and efficiency of airport operations as well as increased resilience through shorter recovery to normal operations. 

Focus: PJ04  is articulated around two ‘SESAR Solutions’, emphasising  all of the key airport processes. Integration of airports into the ATM network will be addressed through sharing information in a timely manner between the Network Operations Plan and the individual AOPs using SWIM technology. 

Who?: PJ04 unites key European aviation industry partners combining the right expertise to address these challenges and to drive deployment of  validated improvements.

Benefits: As clients of airport services, airlines will  benefit from enhanced operational efficiency. For passengers, benefits will be tangible. Information available will be of high quality and the more efficient use of airport resources will lead to enhanced service quality.

EU Strategic:  PJ04 will focus on  a range of different airport complexity levels developing scalable and cost-effective solutions, optimising both the local benefits and those for the European network. Societal concerns will be addressed by ensuring that environmental mitigation measures and impact are included in the airport performance "trade off".</objective>
  <title>Total Airport Management</title>
<identifier>H2020SESAR20152</identifier>
</project>
