<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>209464</rcn>
  <acronym>HARMONY</acronym>
  <objective>Despite significant recent progress in the field of hematological malignancies (HMs), with increasing survival rates and improvement in quality of life, many children and adults with HMs still die from these disorders or experience disabling complications. Therefore, improvement of health care of HMs is an unmet medical need. Thus, it is important to define and align standard and efficient sets of HMs outcomes to measure and evaluate HM data for clinical decisions, long term risk/benefit profile, reimbursement, value analysis, and clinical trials design. Improving outcome measures and endpoint definitions by taking into account "real-life" data and differences in cross-national healthcare practice will undoubtedly result in an optimized, sustainable and effective treatment delivery, as well as in desirable and innovative accelerated pathways for novel drug availability. All these challenges will be addressed within a pan-EU perspective by HARMONY (Healthcare Alliance for Resourceful Medicines Offensive against Neoplasms in HematologY), a comprehensive public-private European consortium of excellence.
HARMONY consortium is made up of 51 partners: 44 participants from 10 European countries and 7 pharmaceutical companies from the EFPIA. HARMONY aims to assemble, assess, connect, and analyze heterogeneous HM patient derived Big Data sets to define sets of outcome indicators that can be used for decision-making by key healthcare stakeholders. The consortium will orchestrate leading experts and working cooperative groups in HMs, European study alliances, pharmaceutical market leaders, patient advocacy groups, HTA and regulatory agencies, to: (i) optimize Europe-wide data collection and create a high-quality HM data repository for further explorative studies; (ii) establish a clinical data-sharing platform that empowers clinicians, patients and policy stakeholders to improve decision-making procedures and identify appropriate treatments to patients with HMs (iii) foster the design of innovative clinical and pre-clinical studies; (iv) define meaningful and harmonized clinical endpoints and outcomes in HMs in order to facilitate clinical decision-making; (v) identify specific biomarkers, which better define outcome parameters (vi) provide novel resources and algorithms to more rapidly advance innovative concepts of patient management in HMs; (vii) involve the patient perspective; (viii) provide a framework for legal, ethical and governance issues. Moreover, the consortium will integrate molecular markers to improve patient outcomes and personalized health management processes.
Regarding governance, HARMONY has a multi-level organizational structure, which includes representatives from all stakeholders, and which ensures efficient and effective management, decision-making, and control of work package (WP) activities. This will be accomplished by creating well-defined management and decision-making structures with clear accountabilities and decision rules. The Consortium Management Bodies will be the Executive Committee, the Steering Committee, and the General Assembly. The management of Big Data is one of the key-features in the consortium. Therefore a Data Quality Supervision Committee will define the quality criteria for "valid records" and perform the review of the quality of the patients’ data provided by different sources (beneficiaries, Associated Members and Co-operative Working Groups).
HARMONY is covering seven HMs (multiple myeloma, acute myeloid leukemia, acute lymphoblastic leukemia, chronic lymphocytic leukemia, non-Hodgkin’s lymphoma, myelodysplastic syndromes and pediatric HMs) structured in eight WPs, including: i) the most important key opinion leaders in each disease; ii) several European institutions involved in the study of HMs; iii) the EFPIA lead companies in HMs; iv) institutions experienced in studying "omics" data; v) a large panel of stakeholders (regulatory agencies, HTA, and patients organiza</objective>
  <title>Healthcare Alliance for Resourceful Medicines Offensive against Neoplasms in HematologY</title>
<identifier>H2020JTIIMI2201506twostage</identifier>
</project>
