<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>215954</rcn>
  <acronym>SMARTER</acronym>
  <objective>SMARTER will develop and deploy innovative strategies to improve Resilience and Efficiency (R&amp;E) related traits in sheep and goats. SMARTER will find these strategies by: i) generating and validating novel R&amp;E related traits at a phenotypic and genetic level ii) improving and developing new genome-based solutions and tools relevant for the data structure and size of small ruminant populations, iii) establishing new breeding and selection strategies for various breeds and environments that consider R&amp;E traits .
SMARTER with help from stakeholders chose several key R&amp;E traits including feed efficiency, health (resistance to disease, survival) and welfare. Experimental populations will be used to identify and dissect new predictors of these R&amp;E traits and the trade-off between animal ability to overcome external challenges. SMARTER will estimate the underlying genetic and genomic variability governing these R&amp;E related traits. This variability will be related to performance in different environments including genotype-by-environment interactions (conventional, agro-ecological and organic systems) in commercial populations. The outcome will be accurate genomic predictions for R&amp;E traits in different environments across different breeds and populations. SMARTER will also create a new cooperative European and international initiative that will use genomic selection across countries. This initiative will make selection for R&amp;E traits faster and more efficient. SMARTER will also characterize the phenotype and genome of traditional and underutilized breeds. Finally, SMARTER will propose new breeding strategies that utilise R&amp;E traits and trade-offs and balance economic, social and environmental challenges.
The overall impact of the multi-actor SMARTER project will be ready-to-use effective and efficient tools to make small ruminant production resilient through improved profitability and efficiency.</objective>
  <title>SMAll RuminanTs breeding for Efficiency and Resilience</title>
<identifier>H2020SFS20172</identifier>
</project>
