<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205538</rcn>
  <acronym>REVOLVE</acronym>
  <objective>Radio signals are core to space systems and services; they are the backbone of satellite broadcasting &amp; communications and further represent the primary underpinning technology of the nearly ubiquitous space-based radio navigation services as well as a large number of Earth observation instruments. Radio technologies are therefore central in defining the investment return for a wide range of missions and reflect to a significant fraction of the combined space and ground segment infrastructure. As the frightening rates of concurrent advances in space-related services, business models and technologies are driving the space ecosystem to a new age, the need to re-invent radio technologies for space is becoming increasingly urgent; while the sector is proactively looking for the next game changer, a whole new class of emerging and forecasted missions place urgent demands for drastic reduction in cost with a concurrent radical improvement in throughput, agility, volume/mass and power consumption. 
This paradigm shift dictates an acute need of highly trained researchers and engineers with a broad set of skills and abilities that extend across and beyond conventional boundaries, enabling them to re-think current approaches and pioneer fresh concepts and radio technologies for space. Recognising this urgent need, REVOLVE brings together a world-leading consortium of 4 industrial and 2 academic beneficiaries aiming to challenge conventional practice in a training network formed around the following five pillars; P1: excellent science &amp; engineering; P2: cross-fertilisation within and between sectors and technologies; P3: application-focused R&amp;D; P4: innovation-centred training, and; P5: promote career acceleration and fulfil personal potential.</objective>
  <title>Radio Technologies for Broadband Connectivity in a Rapidly Evolving Space Ecosystem: Innovating Agility, Throughput, Power, Size and Cost</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2016</identifier>
</project>
