<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211627</rcn>
  <acronym>FlowCamp</acronym>
  <objective>Renewable energy sources like wind turbines require large-scale, stationary energy storage systems to balance out fluctuations in energy generation. FlowCamp will advance the development of one of the most promising storage systems: redox-flow batteries (RFBs). The recruited fellows will develop materials (membranes, electrodes, electrolytes, catalysts, sealing materials) and macrohomogeneous models for three next generation RFBs (hydrogen-bromine, organic and zinc-air systems). They will then upscale the new systems to prototype level (TRL4/5), and validate them using the cutting-edge battery testing facilities available for the prestigious German-funded RedoxWind project at Fraunhofer ICT. The new RFB technologies can be combined in energy storage systems tailored to a wide variety of application scenarios, with lower cost, longer service life and higher efficiency than conventional (e.g. Li-ion) storage devices. 

Through FlowCamp, 15 ESRs will gain a unique skill-set comprising electrochemistry, material science and cell design/ engineering, as well as an overview of different RFB technologies and their implementation at prototype level. FlowCamp will consequently go far beyond existing electrochemical training, in a field with a high and growing research demand. The employability of the ESRs will be further enhanced by high-quality individualized training in scientific and complementary skills, and a structured network program of training units moving them from theoretical investigations towards industrial application and entrepreneurship. The active involvement of industrial partners, secondments in applied research and industry and a strong research and training emphasis on market requirements will furthermore provide them with the intersectoral experience needed for a career in electrochemical energy storage.</objective>
  <title>European Training Network to improve materials for high-performance, low-cost next- generation redox-flow batteries</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2017</identifier>
</project>
