<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>200248</rcn>
  <acronym>TeSeR</acronym>
  <objective>Orbital space is getting increasingly crowded and a few collision events could jeopardize activities in important orbits and
cause significant damage to the infrastructure in space. As a preventive measure to be included in future S/C, TeSeR
proposes a universal post mission disposal module to be carried into orbit by any S/C to ensure its proper disposal after
ending its service lifetime, be it planned or unscheduled due to S/C failure. This module shall be independent of the S/C.
Principal aims of TeSeR are to
1. develop a removal module beginning with the exploration of concepts, going for a functional design with the aim to
manufacture and test an on-ground prototype module which demonstrates the main functions
2. perform a thorough qualitative and quantitative mission analysis of existing removal concepts
3. develop a ground breaking new semi-controlled removal concept based on a passive removal concept which ensures the
deorbit of a large S/C (&gt;1 t) into the Pacific Ocean without a propulsion system but with an accuracy of a fraction of one orbit
4. advance and manufacture removal subsystems prototypes, for controlled, semi-controlled and uncontrolled disposal,
based on already existing technology with the focus on scalability and standardized implementation to the removal module via a common interface
5. analyse the feasibility and potential advantages of multi-purpose concepts of the module and its removal subsystems (e.g.
shielding by deployable structures)
6. perform a market study and define a business case for TeSeR
7. use TeSeR as leverage to propose changes in legal aspects and advanced state of the art licensing standard for
spacecraft including the improvement of international debris mitigation guidelines and standards</objective>
  <title>Technology for Self Removal of Spacecraft</title>
<identifier>H2020PROTEC2015</identifier>
</project>
