<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196468</rcn>
  <acronym>Naturhealth Food</acronym>
  <objective>Biofactoría Naturae et Salus is a biotechnological company created in 2011 which extracts healthy ingredients and additives from fungi and vegetables in order to produce high value foodstuffs. The company has 12 employees and an operational manufacturing biofactory of cutting edge technology.
One of the principal problems in food industry is food preservation. Most food products in the world add chemical preservatives into them (E-numbers). The presence of food preservatives of chemical origin, E-numbers, in food represents a worry for 66% of Europeans. There is international scientific research that concludes that chemical preservatives (E-numbers) can pose health-related problems and environmental problems.

The objective of our project consists on industrially producing a worldwide novelty: a new and natural biopreservative, Naturhealth Food® able to substitute the chemical preservatives in food (E-numbers) in most foodstuffs with similar efficacy and a competitive price. This biopreservative will be harmless for people and environment.

In Biofactoría Naturae et Salus S.A. we have achieved some milestones. Naturhealth Food® has already been successfully manufactured in our biofactory and tried in numerous foodstuffs without affecting their organoleptical properties.
In order to prepare Phase 2 of this project, where the scaling-up of the process and the extension of our facilities will be carried out, we need to conduct a feasibility study of the project (Phase 1). This feasibility study will comprise four main activities: a technical study, a market analysis and customer discovery, an economic study and Intellectual property rights and legal issues.
Our target market is the Food Industry in general. Given that this market is huge to begin with, Biofactoría Naturae et Salus proposes to focus on the high value foodstuffs market. 
Naturhealth Food® sales expectations will be of 35,000,000 € per year in 2022 with a net profit of 6,400,000€ during that year.</objective>
  <title>NATURHEALTH FOOD: NEW GENERATION OF NATURAL BIOPRESERVATIVE SUBSTITUTE OF CURRENT E-NUMBERS IN FOOD PRODUCTS</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
