<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210215</rcn>
  <acronym>IN-PREP</acronym>
  <objective>European countries confront the rising specter of transboundary crises, which cross national borders as well as policy boundaries with speed and ease, threatening the continuing functioning of critical infrastructures and the well-being of many citizens. Transboundary crises pose a specific set of complex challenges for which Europe is – despite recent policy initiatives (e.g. Decision No 1313/2013/EU) – still ill prepared. We recognize three challenges that need urgent attention. First, member states need to develop shared response planning. Second, countries need to share information in real time. This sense-making challenge requires a way to have multiple countries and agencies create a shared picture of an emerging crisis based on multiple sources (different countries, many agencies). Third, countries need to coordinate the use of critical resources to ensure a timely response and to avoid waste and misspending. These challenges are hard to meet in any type of crisis or disaster, but especially in a transboundary context that lacks a dominant actor. IN-PREP will establish and demonstrate a next generation programme by  enabling a reference implementation of coordination operations (Handbook of Transboundary Preparedness and Response Operations that synthesises the lessons learnt, recommendations, check-lists from past incidents) and a training platform (Mixed Reality Preparedness Platform a novel IT-based tool, which holistically integrates Information Systems (IS) and Situational Awareness (SA) modules over a decision support mechanism and the visualisation of assets and personnel) to the entirety of civil protection stakeholders (firefighting units, medical emergency services, police forces, civil protection units, control command centres, assessment experts) to meet these challenges. The proposed framework will not only improve preparedness and planning but can be also applied during joint interventions, thus improving the joint capacity to respond.</objective>
  <title>An INtegrated next generation PREParedness programme for improving effective inter-organisational response capacity in complex environments of disasters and causes of crises</title>
<identifier>H2020SEC201620171</identifier>
</project>
