<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210280</rcn>
  <acronym>OPTISOCHEM</acronym>
  <objective>OPTISOCHEM goal is to demonstrate the performances, reliability as well as environmental and socio-economic sustainability of the entire value chains, for the transformation of excess wheat straw into bio-Isobutene (bio-IBN) derivatives. To achieve these goals a team of 6 partners, leaders in their field, originating from 4 EU-member states, will join efforts.
OPTISOCHEM consists in showcasing the technical accessibility and economical sustainability of the value chains, from wheat straw to 2 different families of chemicals derived from bio-based IBN.
These compounds, oligomers (DIB, TIB, TeIB) and polyisobutylenes (PIBs) are currently used in a wide range of applications such as lubricants, adhesives, sealants, flavors &amp; fragrances and substituted phenols.
This large market is today supplied entirely by products derived from fossil-based isobutene. Products derived from bio-based IBN, using the same process as fossil-based IBN, and with at least as good performances, would provide a renewable supply.
OPTISOCHEM includes the development &amp; up-scaling of bio-IBN production from wheat straw, followed by the production and validation at relevant scale -representative of commercial, established processes- of the bio-based derivatives. To this end, four ambitious objectives were defined:
-Demonstrate the production of wheat straw hydrolysate (WSH) and establish a quality standard to feed the IBN fermentation unit,
-Demonstrate the production of bio-IBN from WSH at pre-commercial scale,
-Demonstrate the quality of end products obtained with bio-IBN as a feedstock and using traditional commercial processes designed for fossil based IBN,
-Determine and validate the targeted technical, economic as well as environmental/social sustainability performances to be achieved for a commercial plant project.
Related Work packages, tasks, milestones and risks are considered in order to achieve these objectives.
OPTISOCHEM project is fully aligned with the call topic.</objective>
  <title>OPTimized conversion of residual wheat straw to bio-ISObutene for bio based CHEMicals</title>
<identifier>H2020BBIJTI2016</identifier>
</project>
