<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>201703</rcn>
  <acronym>Hi-ThermCap</acronym>
  <objective>The Hi-ThermCap project offers a solution for the macro-encapsulation of phase-change materials (PCM) for use in gaseous and aqueous systems as a heat transfer medium. The expected outcome of this innovation project is to put at the market’s disposal a unique solution for thermal energy storage in heating and cooling systems in Europe.
The heating industry is recognized as the sector with the biggest energy-saving potential in Europe. In the low temperature range of -20 to +100°C, most of the thermal energy amounts are required and then discarded, in particular in our buildings and industries. PCM are recognized among the key materials to save these huge energy and – at the same time – CO2 amounts. They can run through a reproducible phase-change at a substance-specific temperature, during which the thermal energy is either stored in very large amounts or returned at a constant temperature. Since decades, an adequate method is being sought to transfer PCM into a user-friendly form. Both existing micro- and macro-encapsulation solutions for PCM storage have until now revealed not industrially and economically viable enough for a broad application. The most common solution in use in Europe is sensible heat storage (e.g. water storage tank) that has a low energy density and thermal storage capacity.
ESDA offers an affordable, easy-of-use, high-capacity and high-performance solution in the form of a PCM-filled capsule able to function in combination with all heat exchangers, including renewable energy technologies. The markets addressed are the high-volume heating and cooling market for residential and service sector buildings in Europe, but also the very promising industrial heating and cooling market. ESDA first calculations foresee a large impact in the application with solar thermal collectors and heat pumps, with a cumulated turnover of €2,256M and additional 75 job creations at strategic European locations within the first 6 years after project completion.</objective>
  <title>High-capacity and high-performance Thermal energy storage Capsule for low-carbon andenergy efficient heating and cooling systems</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12015</identifier>
</project>
