<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>204144</rcn>
  <acronym>DESTINATIONS</acronym>
  <objective>Within the EU, and particularly following the economic crisis; tourism will be, the ‘engine for economic growth’, particularly in the underperforming Mediterranean economies; where tourism has traditionally been a dominant economic sector. The world market of tourists continues to grow and Europe has unique selling points for further tourist growth from within and outside the EU (including China). The competitive market for tourism means that cities have to provide the high quality, sustainable environments desired by tourists, while providing local sustainable employment opportunities that overcome the seasonal and sometimes informal nature of tourist economies. Achieving sustainable mobility is a vital part of the growth equation for Europe’s tourist cities.DESTINATIONS will develop an innovative holistic approach to building sustainable urban mobility systems for both residents and tourists.  The project impacts will make a positive contribution to demonstrating how this can achieve growth and therefore provide a benchmark for other EU tourist cities.

DESTINATIONS will demonstrate and evaluate the effectiveness of innovative sustainable mobility solutions in 6 tourist cities with different characteristics but sharing common challenges. The solutions will address:
• Sustainable Urban Mobility Planning for residents and visitors
• Safe, attractive and accessible public spaces for all generations
• Shared mobility and e-infrastructures towards zero emissions transport
• Smart &amp; clean urban freight logistics at tourist destinations
• Mobility management &amp; awareness for sustainable mobility
• Attractive, clean, accessible and efficient public transport

Achieving the objectives will increase the attractiveness of the city, both for tourists and for businesses in the sector and multiplier impacts in the economy for goods and services. All of these will contribute to better social cohesion (which attracts further investment). So sustainable mobility grows the economy.</objective>
  <title>CIVITAS DESTINATIONS</title>
<identifier>H2020MG2015TwoStages</identifier>
</project>
