<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211081</rcn>
  <acronym>SLICENET</acronym>
  <objective>5G use cases are so diverse and challenging that the 5G networks must be customisable for the broad range of individual scenarios. 5G network providers are keen to offer “networks as a service” where logical network slices are created and allocated to use cases flexibly and efficiently in a multi-operator environment. SliceNet will create and demonstrate the tools and mechanisms to achieve this ambition. Specifically, SliceNet will design, prototype and demonstrate an innovative, verticals-oriented, QoE-driven 5G network slicing framework. It will use cognitive network management, control and orchestration techniques for the provision and operation of end-to-end slicing across multi-operator domains in 5G networks. SliceNet will systematically tackle a range of the involved outstanding issues and thus directly addresses the key challenges in Strand 3 “Software Network” in this call ICT-07-2017. The integrated SliceNet framework will be demonstrated in three representative vertical use cases:  Smart Grid, eHealth and Smart City, to highlight the achievements, innovations, and impacts. SliceNet support the unique perspectives and requirements on 5G networks of different players: For 5G verticals businesses, SliceNet offers an innovative one-stop shop solution to meet diverging and demanding service requirements. SliceNet enables the verticals to plug and play their use cases with bespoke control to employ 5G slices in a scalable, cost-efficient way via novel mySlice and Scalable Slicing as a Service functions and a one-stop API. For 5G service providers and users, SliceNet provides unprecedented guaranteed service quality by agile cognitive QoE-optimisation of service creation and delivery. For 5G network operators, SliceNet presents an integrated FCAPS (Fault, Configuration, Accounting, Performance, Security) framework for truly end-to-end management, control and orchestration of slices by secured, interoperable, and reliable operations across multi-operator domains.</objective>
  <title>End-to-End Cognitive Network Slicing and Slice Management Framework in Virtualised Multi-Domain, Multi-Tenant 5G Networks</title>
<identifier>H2020ICT20162</identifier>
</project>
