<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>199906</rcn>
  <acronym>IMPACTPapeRec</acronym>
  <objective>The European paper industry is at the core of the bioeconomy, using wood, a renewable material, and Paper for Recycling (PfR) as its main raw materials for producing paper products. This industry is a strategic sector in the EU economy, actively contributing to the re-industrialisation of Europe. Currently, the production of paper and board in the EU is 91 tonnes per year, while PfR represents 63%. The contribution of PfR has increased over the last few years (from 25 t to 40 t).
This increase in the availability of PfR has not taken place in all EU states, and this is especially true in Eastern European countries. Besides, although high collection rates are achieved, the quality of this material does not always meet the requirements of paper recycling. Both facts make difficult to keep up with the increases in PfR collection rates observed over the last few years if specific actions are not taken.
IMPACTPapeRec aims to put Europe at the forefront of PfR collection, ensuring raw material procurement from mainly European sources through an innovative approach based on the participation of the whole paper value chain including citizens and municipalities, which is also open to other sectors. Main objective is to provide an innovative and common knowledge platform, which will enable present and future cooperation. Analysis on best practices in PfR collection and assessment procedures are delivered, considering specific local conditions. They will encourage reliable decisions and make solutions available to decision-makers ensuring the procurement and supply of PfR in Europe through the improvement of municipal paper collection. Medium-long results are: increases in PfR collection (up to 75%); 1.57 Mt/year and raw material savings of €385 million.
This proposal has positive support from the EU of the commitment approved within the EIP on raw materials “IMPACT - Introduction and Improvement of Separate Paper Collection to avoid landfilling and incineration”.</objective>
  <title>Boosting the implementation of participatory strategies on separate paper collection for efficient recycling</title>
<identifier>H2020WASTE2015onestage</identifier>
</project>
