<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>208765</rcn>
  <acronym>CHINO</acronym>
  <objective>Digital health applications are disrupting the healthcare sector by bringing huge innovation and improving the quality of care.
However, this innovation brings also some risks since those apps collect and store extremely privacy sensitive data in cloud
and mobile environments.
According to analysis performed by 39 Data Protection Authorities worldwide in 2014, 85% of the 1.211 analyzed mobile
health apps do not comply with data protection laws and security requirements. This behavior puts at serious risk users’
privacy and trust in digital health.
Chino helps application developers and enterprises to solve security and privacy law compliance issues by offering a secure
platform to manage application users and how they access, store and share health sensitive data. Developers can easily
integrate the Chino platform (its API) into their apps to ensure compliance, increase security, speed up application
development, shorten time to market, at affordable pay-per-use cost.
To ensure security of data transfers and storage Chino applies security-by-design principles and state-of-the-art security
mechanisms. From compliance point of view, Chino terms of service define its liabilities and it ensures that the data
management is performed according to EU and Member States laws. In addition, Chino is working on ISO 9001 &amp; 27001
certifications, giving more guarantees to its customers.
Thanks to its innovative services, the market opportunity, and the EC support (which will speed up the adequate team
growth, marketing plan, technological roadmap implementation and international commercialization), the company expect to
create over 46 high qualified jobs and generate a turnover over 10M€ by 2020. Furthermore, the overall results of this project
will catapult Chino company as a global leader on the digital health &amp; cyber security market.</objective>
  <title>The Health Data Security Platform for EU Developers Enterprises</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
