<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210053</rcn>
  <acronym>SciShops.eu</acronym>
  <objective>Success of science shops is down to finding a topic that is of particular interest to a particular group of people because they need to engage throughout the science shops research process, participate in the brokering and challenge identification and take responsibility for the outcome of the process. SciShops aims at expanding and further building on the capacity of the science shops ecosystem in Europe and beyond. During the SciShops project timeframe, at least ten new university- and non-university-based science shops are being established in Europe by project partners. The non-university ones are affiliated to different types of organizations, such as SMEs, LEs, NGOs/NPOs and research institutes. 
The project partners have extensive networks of science shops which are included in the SciShops Expert and Advisory Board and thus they can uptake first the solutions developed within the project: the SciShops Knowledge Exchange Roadmap, the SciShops Strategy for Community-Based Participatory Research and Science Shops Further Development, SciShops Guide for Establishment and Running of a Science Shop or the SciShops Web platform with its novel twining, matchmaking and awareness features. Through the use of the platform, organizations willing to establish a science shop are able to find a research organization which can support them with research services or they can be twinned with an experienced similar science shop which will help with the establishment and development of the new one. 
The SciShops consortium has as a top priority to prove the benefits of starting a science shop for every type of organization, but also the advantages the civil society gains from collaborating with science shops in community-based participatory research. The participatory knowledge transfer and exchange events organized during the project timeline will raise awareness on this win-win concept.</objective>
  <title>Enhancing the Responsible and Sustainable Expansion of the Science Shops Ecosystem in Europe</title>
<identifier>H2020SwafS20161</identifier>
</project>
