<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211874</rcn>
  <acronym>PV-Prosumers4Grid</acronym>
  <objective>The aim of the PV-Prosumers4Grid project is to develop and implement innovative self-consumption and aggregation concepts and business models for PV prosumers that will help integrating sustainable and competitive electricity from PV in the electricity system. 
The benefits of the PV-Prosumers4Grid action will be therefore threefold:
•	To identify the necessary regulatory changes and the business opportunities for PV prosumers and grid operators
•	To further support the deployment PV systems for electricity generation with focus on physical and financial grid interactions
•	To provide PV Prosumers (households and industries) with competitive and sustainable electricity 
Innovative self-consumption and aggregation concepts and business models for PV generation are extremely needed nowadays. At the time being many EU Member States have drastically reduced measures to further support the development of the RES sector, even though several projects have clearly demonstrated the need to maintain the policies to support RES until when a consolidated competitiveness has been achieved. 
Such competetiveness for variable RES will depend on the ability of the existing or future electricity markets to provide them with adequate revenues, whatever the size of the plant.  
In addition, the variable aspect of PV doesn’t allow them by nature to bid on the market at chosen times, with a possible and already visible impact on the market prices. The consequence could be that under such conditions, their competitiveness will become more difficult to achieve unless the consumers could become more responsive to price signals and allow to displace the load. 
Moreover, the new state aid guidelines published in April 2014 by the European Commission are pushing for further integration of renewable sources into the electricity markets, which will require from RES to cope with market integration, more constraining grid codes and balancing regulations.</objective>
  <title>Development of innovative self-consumption and aggregation concepts for PV Prosumers to improve grid load and increase market value of PV</title>
<identifier>H2020LCE2017RESCSA</identifier>
</project>
