<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211180</rcn>
  <acronym>Andiamo</acronym>
  <objective>The number of Europeans with paralysis, deformity or orthopaedic impairments that use orthotics will reach 9.6 million by the
year 2020. Orthotics is a speciality involving the application of external devices to the body to support and improve posture,
function and mobility, and manage pain and deformity. The majority of people requiring orthotics are over 50 years old;
demand is expected to increase with the ageing population and the rising prevalence of obesity, cardiovascular disease,
diabetes and stroke, where foot complications and reduced mobility are commonplace.

Approaches to orthotics have not changed in over 50 years. The process takes up to 12 months, and requires technicians,
physiotherapists, orthotists and manufacturers. Often, by the time patient receives their orthotic their condition has
deteriorated or the orthotic no longer fits, resulting in ineffective treatment, repeat visits, poorer clinical outcomes, and higher
risk of surgery.

Families all over Europe are being failed by this service. In order to tackle this challenge, we have developed a streamlined
orthotic 3D scanning, design and printing service. Our orthotic service is the only service in the world capable of delivering
an effective custom orthotic within 1 week of consultation. Our pathway is faster and more cost effective than traditional
methods.

We use a multidisciplinary team, CAD and FEA to optimise design, add strength and flexibility and reduce unwanted
movement, resulting in better patient reported outcomes and quality of life. Our key innovation is the overarching technology
and software that links together the entire service pathway, from consultation to delivery in under a week.</objective>
  <title>A revolutionary new orthotics service—consultation to delivery in less than a week.</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
