<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211496</rcn>
  <acronym>BP24</acronym>
  <objective>Human body tries to keep blood pressure as stable and constant as possible, so its instabilities are indicators of systemic
problems. Among 1 B people affected by hypertension, however, blood pressure monitoring is ineffective at least in 47% of
them, leading to 9 M deaths/year globally. Current monitors for self blood pressure monitoring show main drawbacks: they
interfere with daily activities, often lack of reliability and standards, and only allow to measure the blood pressure
intermittently, so information on the blood pressure trend is not available. BP24 is a wearable medical device for
noninvasive, continuous and highly accurate blood pressure monitoring, specifically targeting patients with hypertension and
inpatients. Vita Sentry’s proprietary core technology enables a unique approach that takes into account the vascular tone to
compute the value of BP, instead of simply estimating it from the measure of the blood flow. By detecting the diameter of
arteries and arterioles with an accuracy of 0.5 μm over a measurement range, BP24 is the unique wearable intended for
highly accurate -golden-standard comparable- BP monitoring. Therefore, not only it can be used by patients with
hypertension, but in the future it will be used in patients undergoing surgeries – and the company’s efforts are directed
towards that objective. Vita Sentry’s technology is enabling: being vasodilation and vasoconstriction in a number of
physiological processes, knowing the arteries and arteriole diameters will allow to measure the metabolic rate and the stress
level of a person. While this is a long-term objective, going to the market with BP24 for self-monitoring of people with
hypertension is the goal of the innovation project. During Phase 1 project the Company will assess the scale-up
industrialization plan, the trials needed to demonstrate the validity of the proposed solution and will evaluate a sound go-tomarket
strategy to ensure successful commercialization of the device.</objective>
  <title>A unique life-saving smart-watch for high quality, not-invasive, continuous blood pressure monitoring.</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
