<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>200230</rcn>
  <acronym>POWER2INNO</acronym>
  <objective>Problem to solve: 
Considerable number of innovation support programmes were developed in the EU that tackled SME (for example SME Instrument, COSME…), however very few programmes and methodologies were developed for specific challenges that face small and micro companies (SMC). This fact is especially relevant for all three project partners’ regions, which have all well over national averages of micro and small companies: 93,7 % in Primorsko-notranjska region (Slovenia), more that 95% in Puglia region (Italy) and 96,4% in Malaga region (Spain). Micro and small companies (much more than middle and large sized companies) are critically bound to the traditional ways of doing business and lack competences needed for modern successful innovative entrepreneurship. One of the reasons for that is also lack of competences and available methodologies of innovation support agencies to tackle this specific problem. 

General objective of the project:
The general objective of the project is to engage in peer learning activities between three project partners to raise our competences for empowerment of small and micro companies’ for innovative entrepreneurship - for transition from production-oriented mentality to scouting for opportunities on global market and creating value for customers. In addition to that, we will disseminate project results across EU.

Specific objectives for the project:
- Transfer from traditional “I offer what I do” to advanced scouting of “opportunity on the market” 
- Bottom-up work with  entrepreneurs, methodologies for ideas creation, innovation management 
Inclusion of partners for realisation of ideas, value added chain, micro clustering 
- Lean approach, market feed-back and use of IT tools
- Advanced financial instruments 
- Internationalisation of business 
- Implementation of three pilot projects
- Preparation of best practice materials and spill-over effects</objective>
  <title>Building competences for empowerment of small and micro companies’ for innovative entrepreneurship</title>
<identifier>H2020INNOSUP20145</identifier>
</project>
