<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210309</rcn>
  <acronym>3D-SMoHC</acronym>
  <objective>In today’s society, three-dimensional models of the tangible heritage present the greatest potential for heritage conservation efforts, due to advances in display devices, capabilities, and infrastructure costs, etc. However, in reality, these models do not always provide the necessary accuracy; they require an arduous process of managing and transforming; and they are not set up for reuse and long-term archiving. Without such capabilities we are left with inadequate knowledge that leads to higher expenses and time costs during documentation of fieldwork, disconnected bodies of geospatial data, and over-dimensioned and disorganised information. These problems further limit the scope and efficiency of the use of digital heritage resources for professionals, and restrict the accessibility of these resources to a wider audience without technical literacy, therefore constraining conservation and reuse practices throughout society. 

Current 3D models are not enough to overcome these limitations unless they become smart. Therefore, 3D-SMoHC aims to remedy this gap through the creation of 3D Smart Models for Heritage Conservation. With these models, 3D representations of built heritage can be organised according to their semantic features and adapted to management and visualisation multi-platforms. To achieve such digital products and improve the way we address the conservation of our cultural heritage, we need more than technological development: technical advancements must be combined with in-depth knowledge of today’s uses and needs, sharing a common language, and integrated into the proper legal framework for the new data structures. To accomplish developments with such dimensions and scope, 3D-SMoHC is conceived within an Open Notebook Science strategy. It is intended that greater transparency should characterise the whole project and should impact not only on data sharing and dissemination of results, but also on the production process of the research itself.</objective>
  <title>3D SMART MODELS FOR HERITAGE CONSERVATION An Open Science project for documentation, management and representation of Cultural Heritage</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAIF2016</identifier>
</project>
