<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205666</rcn>
  <acronym>P2Endure</acronym>
  <objective>P2Endure aims to provide scalable, adaptable and ready-to-implement prefabricated Plug-and-Play (PnP) systems for deep renovation of building envelopes and technical systems. These innovative solutions will be used to transform non-functioning or sub-optimal public and historic buildings into dwellings, and applicable for the widest range of building typologies, i.e. public buildings, residential buildings, and transformation projects.  
The main innovation of P2Endure comprises PnP prefab systems enabled by 3D printing, laser and thermal scanning integrated with Building Information Model (BIM). The promoted solutions are SME-driven and geared to rapid and low-disturbance on-site assembly processes for deep renovation.
P2Endure presents a proof-of-performance of the optimised PnP renovation techniques by implementing 10 large-scale and live demonstration projects that represent the main deep renovation typologies and real market demand in 4 EU geo-clusters. This will be done through progressive steps known as “4M: Mapping – Modelling – Making – Monitoring” throughout a 4-year project duration. These demonstration cases give evidence of the achieved 60% energy saving after deep renovation along with 15% cost saving and 50% time saving at renovation, and high indoor environmental quality. The P2Endure project leverage in total primary energy saved is: 19.121 GWh/y.
Wider impacts on replication and market upscaling are guaranteed by a Technology Commercialization Platform (TCP). On this platform P2Endure builds up a critical mass of building owners and their projects, local authorities, supply-chain actors, including leading industrial players in prefab building and technical systems that provide the necessary vehicle for innovative SMEs to enlarge their EU and global market shares through P2Endure solutions.</objective>
  <title>Plug-and-Play product and process innovation for Energy-efficient building deep renovation</title>
<identifier>H2020EE2016PPP</identifier>
</project>
