<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196414</rcn>
  <acronym>SCALEPHA</acronym>
  <objective>The objective of the SCALEPHA Project is to contribute to the protection and sustainable management of natural resources and ecosystems through a sustainable supply and use of raw materials in the industrial production of 100% biodegradable bio-plastic, in order to meet the needs of a growing global population within the sustainable limits of the planet's natural resources and eco-systems.
SCALEPHA activities will contribute to increasing European competitiveness, raw materials security and improving well-being, whilst assuring environmental integrity, resilience through an innovative integrated technology: Polyhydroxyalkanoate (PHAs).
European Factories of the Future will have to be SMART (high performance, reconfigurable, adaptive and evolving factories based on new technologies) and GREEN (reduced ecological footprint through a more efficient use, at factory level, of material and energy resources): SCALEPHA project will demonstrate that Biotechnologies, such PHAs production, are the strategic technologies needed to keep the European Manufacturing leading edge.
Side Objectives:
-	penetrate significantly the existing bioplastic market through PHAs (in particular Biomedical, Food Packaging and Design sectors); 
-	diffusion and uptake of PHA innovation on a broad scale, maximising its economic and environmental benefits;
-	create or enlarge new markets for related PHAs products providing opportunities for growth and jobs at Local, National and European levels.
-	deploy a key environmental product obtained with smarter and greener processes addressing the challenge of resource scarcity, water and soil pollution.</objective>
  <title>Industrial and commercial SCALE-up of Bio-on technology for the production of PHA polymers from sugar industries waste, co- and by-products</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
