<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>194075</rcn>
  <acronym>m-RESIST</acronym>
  <objective>In European Union approximately 5 million people suffer from psychotic disorders. Between 30-50% can be considered resistant to treatment, and 10-20% ultra-resistant. These patients present persistent positive symptomatology, require extensive periods of hospital care, and have a greater risk of excess mortality and multi-morbidity. In addition, a high proportion of the total cost for treating schizophrenia is spent on this population (Kennedy et al., 2013).
Intervention strategies based on mHealth have demonstrated their ability to support and promote self-management-based strategies. Evidence from studies point to the importance of engaging patients actively in their own treatment. This active role helps to improve adherence to treatment, and to reduce persistent symptoms severity, relapses and hospitalizations (Mueser et al., 2002).
m-RESIST aims to develop an intervention programme based on mHealth to allow patients suffering from resistant schizophrenia to self-manage their condition (resistant schizophrenia and its associated comorbidities, e.g. somatic disorders and addictions). This may facilitate acceptance and involvement of patients with their own treatment, as well as of caregivers. Moreover this programme could provide a new tool to the psychiatrist, psychologists working together with other health care professionals, to better monitor patients, through a personalised and optimised therapeutic process.
m-resist will (1) develop and validate an mHealth solution aimed to reduce the severity of episodes and further complications; (2) involve and promote participation of patients and caregivers in the therapeutic process increasing the awareness of patient and caregiver about the nature of the illness and its consequences, benefits of treatment and needs for healthy habits and promoting an active and collaborative role with the medical team in the treatment decision-making procedure.</objective>
  <title>Mobile Therapeutic Attention for Patients with Treatment Resistant Schizophrenia</title>
<identifier>H2020PHC2014singlestage</identifier>
</project>
