<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211313</rcn>
  <acronym>REZBUILD</acronym>
  <objective>Nowadays, the European construction market has to tackle the refurbishment of existing building stock. NZEB renovation methodologies are required as a key enabler through energy-efficient buildings. REZBUILD will address this challenge by opening the construction sector through the integration of innovative technologies such as leaves in a tree in order to pave the way towards an annual renovation rate of 2,5% instead of current rates lower than 1%.

The aim is to develop one refurbishment ecosystem based on the integration of cost-effective technologies, business models and life cycle interaction for deep NZEB renovation to diverse residential renovation typologies and interconnecting both, building renovation stages and stakeholders. This innovation will establish a multi-collaborative framework within a refurbishment methodology managed by an Agile Project Management tool capable to interconnect in real-time the key steps of a tailored retrofitting plan among all stakeholders involved within the building renovation value chain. This ecosystem will ensure the fulfilment of three KPIs: 

1)A deep renovation rate at least 60% of primary energy reduction as a result, the application of a decision tree strategy created from the combination of united principles of the novel sustainable architecture and NZEB design concepts; 
2)A reduced installation time at least a 30% of time saving in comparison with a traditional refurbishment works,and; 
3)A rapid payback period maximum 12 years of the best retrofitting technology package installed in the residential building. 

The environment will provide an ad-hoc amalgam of methodologies, cost-effective technologies and tools applicable within the main residential building typologies in EU, with the aim of achieving a large-scale penetration and deep impact within the rehabilitation of the current residential building stock after its optimization in 3 multi-scale demo buildings located in the most representative climates in EU.</objective>
  <title>REfurbishment decision making platform through advanced technologies for near Zero energy BUILDing renovation</title>
<identifier>H2020EEB2017</identifier>
</project>
