<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207700</rcn>
  <acronym>ERICENA</acronym>
  <objective>Europe actively engages internationally to strengthen its leadership in the field of Science, Technology and Innovation (STI) in the global scene and improve synergies between Member States. Europe aims to foster international cooperation and strengthen its STI presence in China due to its growing importance and STI opportunities for European actors. 
ERICENA (European Research Innovation Centre of Excellence in China), a 48 month initiative implemented by 8 European and 5 Chinese partners, proposes to set up a Centre and its networks in China to promote European STI interests in China, creating synergies with existing STI structures. ERICENA will connect and support European researchers, entrepreneurs and other STI stakeholders, while providing and facilitating provision of STI services (e.g. networking, advice and support, training, among others) to private and public clients. 
The Centre will be implemented along 4 stages (initial set-up, pilot, full operational and self-sustainable stages), in which all mechanisms will be structured and established to ensure the Centre’s long-term sustainable operation in China. The Centre will be established through the implementation of 6 strategic WPs, which are structured along 4 key pillars – strategy, operational, financial and implementation – as well as two cross-cutting supporting WPs. 
ERICENA will effectively contribute to improve cooperation between European STI organisations and researchers and their Chinese counterparts, strengthen the presence of European STI excellence in the Chinese market, maximize the impact of European STI actors in China, improve the framework conditions for EU-China cooperation, and expand the impact of results from existing European STI projects and initiatives in China. This vision will be closely supported and empowered through the wide involvement of stakeholders, including the consortium and more than 100 STI stakeholders in the EU and China involved as Associated Partners.</objective>
  <title>European Research and Innovation Centre of Excellence in ChiNA</title>
<identifier>H2020SC6ENGGLOBALLY20161</identifier>
</project>
