<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196928</rcn>
  <acronym>LineVu</acronym>
  <objective>Pipelines have formed an integral part of our Natural Gas transportation critical infrastructure for decades and their importance is growing, as resources reduce and new markets and demand open up. Liquid contamination in pipelines is a serious issue for safety, security, reliability of supply and commercially for gas supply and transportation companies. Existing technology is designed only to analyse dry gas. Liquid contamination damages the analysers and sample systems and there is no indication of the quantity of liquid present. Early detection of contamination is key and will result in the issue being dealt with before it becomes a commercial problem and most importantly an urgent safety or security issue.

The Linevu system introduces a non-intruding vision system at various points in the pipeline in order to determine if a liquid is present in the pipeline, so that the correct course of action can be decided upon before it becomes a serious issue.

Our goal is to embark on a phase 2 project in order to bring to market a novel pressurised window, containment system and vision system which can confirm the presence of liquid, while not interfering with routine “pigging” maintenance in the pipeline. The safety, economic and social benefits are numerous and the system would be retro-fitted onto any existing pipelines in the global supply network.

At a time of great change in the global energy industry in terms of changing sources of gas and security of energy supply, we believe that this innovative technology will provide the EU with a real competitive advantage in the global energy supply market and oil &amp; gas multinationals such as Exxon, Statoil, BP and Shell have already shown great interest in the concept.</objective>
  <title>A novel optical sensor platform for detection and measurement of contaminants in gas pipelines to protect critical infrastructure from disruption and damage - Linevu</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
