<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>194756</rcn>
  <acronym>Toor-IG-ICT37-2014</acronym>
  <objective>A new universe of video game tournament (called e-sports) has transformed dramatically the video game industry over the last two years. However, organising and participating in e-sports tournaments remain complicated for players and publishers. OXENT wants to support and amplify this massive growth of e-sports by integrating an e-sports platform directly in top selling video games (so-called in-game approach). 

The current state-of-the-art reveals that no in-game tournament solution exists. With its innovation, OXENT wants to change the way video games are played, with a massive shift towards tournaments among the average player. OXENT aims to become the world leader of e-sports tournament technology with € 34 million income in 2017 and 20 employees.

Our BtoBtoC solution meets the needs of both players and of publishers. Direct integration into video games democratises the use for players, by giving access to the platform automatically and intuitively. Publishers will easily shift from single sales business model to subscription. Therefore, client retention will increase, and the games life cycle will be extended. In addition, new sources of revenue will be created through tournament fees. 

The feasibility study will assess three key levels:
1. Technical: Test in-game performance and improve design and ergonomics.
2. Economic: Define the business model through meetings with global publishers and potential business partners
3. Legal: Identify data collection legal issues and the opportunity to protect our knowledge.
For global commercialisation of our innovation, total funding requirement during 2 years for Phase 2 is estimated at € 2 800 000.

The dissemination of the innovation will be global. For cultural and market size reasons, target geographies for video game players include the major European markets in France, Germany, UK and the Scandinavian countries, as well as in North America. These countries, combined, comprise 60% of the global market.</objective>
  <title>Enabling mass access to the social phenomenon of e-sports tournaments by integrating In-Game Platform in world’s leading video games</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
