<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206821</rcn>
  <acronym>NEOSURANCE</acronym>
  <objective>"Neosurance is a 50/50 joint venture between Neosperience, specialized in Digital Customer Experience, and Digital Tech International, operating in InsurTech sector. The objective of Neosurance is to propose a new insurance product, the ""micro-insurance on the spot"" (""Snap Insurance"").
The Snap Insurances are short-term insurance policies, proposed to the client a few hours before an event he is going to participate (a trip, a sport, a concert) through push notifications that he receives on his smartphone, with which it’s possible to finalize the purchase of Snap Insurance in a few minutes from the mobile.

Neosurance works with the ambition to create a new insurance market with a completely new and innovative insurance product. Its positioning is unique in the field of ""one-time insurance"": its technology platform is an advanced machine learning engine, based on proprietary algorithm, matches insurance coverages to customer needs in milliseconds.

Neosurance also followed a pilot project, installing the SDK of its platform on the app used by a community consisting of more than 500,000 five-a-side soccer players, by connecting the community platform with the Neosurance one and performing the first test by sending push notifications to a defined category of users.

Neosurance is applying for Phase 1 of the SME Instrument to develop a feasibility study in order to confirm and define its strategies into its global project, with technical, business and financial objectives. Then Neosurance will apply for Phase 2, to organize a business development program which start selling Snap Insurance first in Europe and then worldwide.

Neosurance will bring a sharp breaking in the EU insurance market and, we expect, also on global scale. The company is positioned within the insurance market in the segment of ""Connected Insurance"" as one of the best-in-class player, winning the AXA Insurance Lab contest at VIVA Technology 2016 in Paris and the Insurance IoT Europe 2016 in London."</objective>
  <title>Neosurance's objective is to propose innovative  short-term insurance policies,proposed to the client a few hours before an event he is going to participate,through an advanced machine learning engine</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
