<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211057</rcn>
  <acronym>To-Euro-5G</acronym>
  <objective>The To-Euro-5G project has a clear objective to support the activities of the European 5G Initiative as outlined in the 5G contractual Public Private Partnership (cPPP) during the second phase of the 5G-PPP from June 2017 to June 2019, with the intention of maximising the return on this investment for Europe.
.    
The objectives of To-Euro-5G include: 
•	Progressing the 5G-PPP high level goal of maintaining and enhancing the competitiveness of the European ICT industry, and seeking European leadership in the 5G domain. 
•	Supporting activities where the 5G-PPP can contribute to the implementation of the European 5G Action Plan . 
•	Assembling an overview of the 5G-PPP projects trial/demo/showcase potential and encouraging any organisation performing such an activity to identify the “European 5G” basis of their public showcases.
•	Responsibility for orchestrating the cross project activities of the 5G-PPP projects selected for Phase 2 of the 5G-PPP, as foreseen by Article 41.4 of their respective grant agreements, for example, in the areas of Standards, Spectrum, Architecture, management, Security and a number of other key strategic aspects of 5G. 
•	Developing and implementing a strategic communications plan, including technical and social media channels, to ensure the best possible impact is achieved with the results of the 5G-PPP projects and the horizontal activities of the 5G-PPP programme. 
•	Stimulating, organising and hosting strategic events and workshops where the European 5G achievements will be promoted on a global level.
•	Orchestrating an open, transparent and flexible 5G-PPP programme governance structure that facilitates good co-operation between the projects, the commission and the 5G Infrastructure Association.
.
The To-Euro-5G project also has the underlying ambition to ensure that European society, via the Vertical sectors uptake of 5G, can enjoy the economic and societal benefits these future 5G networks can provide.</objective>
  <title>To-Euro-5G:  Supporting the European 5G Initiative</title>
<identifier>H2020ICT20162</identifier>
</project>
