<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212908</rcn>
  <acronym>HATCH</acronym>
  <objective>"The project consortium for HATCH comprises 4 SMEs and 1 high-profile technology centre. The aim of HATCH is to develop a scalable, contemporary, interactive and user-driven platform for promoting European space projects and related activities to professionals and citizens. It aims to overcome obstacles enabling researchers, innovators and other stakeholders to focus on achieving their objectives.
This proposal answers the call requirements through 6 objectives, split into 8 Work Packages.
HATCH will use modern solutions: comprehensive data analysis, proven methods and high standards for development and validation.
The HATCH consortium has completed a preparatory study to identify groups of ""User Persona"" through sample surveys, interviews and secondary data analysis. As a result, the consortium has gained insight into stakeholders’ goals, needs and behaviour patterns to underpin the user-driven solution.
The Portal’s visual layout will appeal to a wide range of users to showcase European research, encourage collaboration, form partnerships, analyse funding, commercialise results and generate interest in space exploration and science for all.
Elastic search and bundle retrieval are some of the techniques to be used by an experienced team to deliver the best search functionality. Individuals will be able to create their own filters and save results to create research networks.
Search engine optimisation tactics and an extensive communication/dissemination strategy will give visibility and awareness to all stakeholders making a strong base for the future.
Consortium members are focused on maximising the impact of the project. 2 partners manage space-related online resources (on a smaller, regional/national scale). Another partner understands user requirements and the translation into solid activities within a webpage. 1 partner provides expertise on features such as user experience or data mining. 2 partners have experience in conducting projects in the space sector."</objective>
  <title>SME-led Space Portal for Europe</title>
<identifier>H2020COMPET2017</identifier>
</project>
