<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>193508</rcn>
  <acronym>C3PO</acronym>
  <objective>C3PO: advanced Concept for laser uplink/ downlink CommuniCation with sPace Objects represents a radical improvement in performance of existing ground to low earth orbit communication systems in terms of weight reduction, on-board power consumption, data rate and communication security &amp; confidentiality. C3PO in figures:
- Mass reduction by a factor 14
- On-board power consumption reduction by a factor 100
- Data rate increase by a factor 2

The project's objectives are to
- Design a solution to improve actual downlink and uplink communication systems based on a non-space disruptive technology
- Improve enabling Space Surveillance &amp; Tracking technologies performances to meet the final system needs
- Increase the Multiple Quantum Well Technology Readiness Level from 2 to 4
- Improve the overall perfromance of space communication systems
- Identify the C3PO system market and Business Model 
- Increase the system safety (including regulation and governance issues)

This is achieved through an operational analysis of the final system, the validation of major system parameters through 2 experiments, the consolidation of the system  architecturen the elaboration of the associated development roadmap and the definition of the system Business Model. 

The Multiple Quantum Well retro-reflector technology, derived from non-space domain, is incorporated into the current state of the art as a high-rate lightweight communication device. Its development in the space sector has a disruptive impact on the satellites and satellite imagery markets, enabling new missions such as CubeSat earth observations.

The proposed project serve the Union's Common Security &amp; Defence Policy by increasing the satellite communications security.

C3PO mobilises traditional space actors and non-space actors such as TEMATYS (SME) and ACREO (Research).</objective>
  <title>advanced Concept for laser uplink/ downlink CommuniCation with sPace Objects</title>
<identifier>H2020COMPET2014</identifier>
</project>
