<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205103</rcn>
  <acronym>NANOMAN</acronym>
  <objective>NANOLIKE uses an innovative variant of Convective Self-Assembly (CSA) which allows the assembly of nano-objects on a large variety of supports with a high flexibility. With this unique process worldwide, NANOLIKE has developed a new generation of nanosensors which are 100x smaller, 50x more sensitive and 10 000x less energy consuming than other sensors. 
This innovation is interesting for three worldwide markets. The Internet of Things market lacks of strain sensors suitable for their specific requirements (low-cost, low-energy, high sensitivity, small size, easy to integrate). The tests &amp; measurements and sensors markets need low-cost, low-energy sensors, a high reliability and the possibility to build networks of sensors. 
NANOLIKE’s strategic plan is to conquest the emerging IoT market by achieving large enough production volumes to propose attractive costs. When the long-term performance and robustness of the nanosensors will be demonstrated, NANOLIKE will be able to penetrate the sensors market and to increase its market share on the tests &amp; measurements market by substituting the existing solutions by its disruptive nanomaterials based solutions.
In the feasibility assessment, NANOLIKE will refine its knowledge of the competitive environment, improve the initial business offer, protect the innovation project, prepare the scaling-up phase, update its first commercialization strategy and adapt its business plan. Then, in the Phase 2, NANOLIKE will set-up the industrial facility capable to manufacture nanosensors with a total yielding capacity of 1 million units per year with a cost lower than €5 per unit and undertake demonstrations with major customers. This is the aim of the NANOMAN project.
The company, a spin-off of the Nanotech team from the Lab. of Physics and Chemistry of Nano-Objects, illustrates the potential of the nanotechnology that the EU has recognized as a KET. NANOLIKE will bridge the gap from lab to market, grow and create highly skilled jobs.</objective>
  <title>Nanosensors manufacturing</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
