<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205698</rcn>
  <acronym>X2Rail-1</acronym>
  <objective>X2Rail-1 addresses the S2R-CFM-IP2-01-2015 “Start-up activities for Advanced Signalling and Automation System” call issued by the Shift2Rail Joint Undertaking as part of the Innovation Programme 2 “Advanced Traffic Management &amp; Control Systems”.
The X2Rail-1 project aims to research and develop six selected key technologies to foster innovations in the field of railway signalling and automation systems towards a flexible, real-time, intelligent traffic management and decision support system.
The actions to be undertaken in the scope of X2Rail-1 are related to the following specific objectives:
 To overcome the limitations of the existing communication systems by adapting radio communication systems which establish the backbone for the next generation advanced rail automation systems.
 To improve the usable track capacity by introducing more Automatic Train Operation (ATO) systems and Moving Block systems.
 To innovate the signalling architectures towards more decentralized and less cost intensive systems by incorporating Moving Block systems and Smart Wayside Objects. 
 To minimize energy consumption and to improve train punctuality through more extensive use of Automatic Train Operation (ATO) systems.
 To increase innovation in the field of lab testing by developing architectures for new lab test systems and simulations for control, command and communication systems in order to reduce costs. 
 To ensure security among all connected signalling and control systems by developing new cyber security systems dedicated to railways.
 To ensure the backward compatibility of ERMTS/ETCS technologies, notwithstanding of the required functional enrichment of the future signalling and control systems.</objective>
  <title>Start-up activities for Advanced Signalling and Automation Systems</title>
<identifier>H2020S2RJUCFM2015011</identifier>
</project>
