<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205593</rcn>
  <acronym>COMPOSITION</acronym>
  <objective>Data and services have become the key factor in manufacturing processes. The need to react on dynamically changing market demands is dramatically rising. One of the most imperative problems so far is to connect supply chain data and services between enterprises and to connect value chain data within a factory, so that it can meaningfully support decision-making. COMPOSITION will create a digital automation framework (the COMPOSITION IIMS) that optimizes the manufacturing processes by exploiting existing data, knowledge and tools to increase productivity and dynamically adapt to changing market requirements. This technology acts as the technical operating system for business connections between factories and their suppliers. Furthermore, it opens a new space for third party entities to actively interact in the supply chain, e.g., by providing services to improve cycle time, cost, flexibility or resource usage. In addition to the supply chain improvements, also the processes inside the company will be addressed and optimized. Data across the (multi sided) company internal value chain is integrated by an Integrated Information Management System (IIMS) with optimisation and modelling tools for resource management including innovative, multi-level, real-time cross-domain analytics including a Decision Support System. The technology will be based on extending existing FI-WARE and FITMAN catalogues and LINKSmart® Middleware and adapt the concept of Industrial Data Space. COMPOSITION will implement, demonstrate and validate the system in two multi-sided pilots that show the modularity, scalability and re-configurability of the platform across multiple application domains. The first pilot in the biomedical device domain focuses on the integrated information management system in a multi-sided manufacturing process. The second pilot concentrates on the interaction between different companies using the COMPOSITION ecosystem with the agent-based marketplace for collaboration.</objective>
  <title>Ecosystem for Collaborative Manufacturing Processes – Intra- and Interfactory Integration and Automation</title>
<identifier>H2020FOF2016</identifier>
</project>
