<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207463</rcn>
  <acronym>trans-making</acronym>
  <objective>The project trans-making aims to establish a multilateral network of research and innovation staff active in the fields of placemaking/place-based art activities as a space to create alternative narratives for social, economic and democratic renewal.
It will investigate and experiment with placemaking to contribute actively to the democratization/well-being of society, educating and empowering individuals and disadvantaged minorities through research and production in the connection between art and new technologies.
The objective is to strengthen research capacities, through exchange of knowledge and expertise between academic and non-academic partners from Europe and Third Countries in a shared research programme focused on: collecting, documenting / Exploring, experimenting / Performing / Designing. Trough those work programme of Research and Innovation, the consortium, academic and non-academics partners, aims to foster links between art and culture, economy, democracy and innovation at EU level and beyond. To foster entrepreneurial skills, risk taking adaptability, innovation capacity (economic, social and democratic). And it will contribute actively to education and empowerment of individuals and disadvantaged minorities trough research and production between art and new technologies.
The project through its consortium will be to foster a better understanding and knowledge sharing between scientific community, stakeholders and policy-makers. Which will be achieved with the respective networks of the involved partners. The final aim of trans-making will be to establish a long term collaboration among the partners in order to have a scientific and innovative worldwide community devoted to the research, (including art-based research), innovation, education activity in the matters concerned by the project. Moreover, the proposed measures of the project will be conceived in order to have the widest possible impact of the society.</objective>
  <title>Art / culture / economy to democratize society. Research in placemaking for alternative narratives</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCARISE2016</identifier>
</project>
