<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>194688</rcn>
  <acronym>EUROCATED</acronym>
  <objective>Eurocated project main objective consists of taking advantage of the opportunity presented in the market by the necessity of saving costs and reduce emissions in terms of fuel combustion in the operation of all kind of road transport professional fleets. 
Based on the principle of efficient driving, the solutions, products and services, proposed by this project, will fit a market all around Europe of more than 200 million € per year. Only Spanish market is ranged over 10 million € per year. Thousands of vehicles from public and private fleets will save billions € and tones of emissions, and fleet operators interest is growing as they become aware of the benefits of efficient driving technology supported systems over traditional training courses. Only a medium size city urban bus operator could save 375 thousand € per year and reduce emissions in 750 Tn per year.
ADN Mobile Solutions distinguishes by its excellence in R&amp;D activities  that have permitted the firm to currently count with the most specialized, competitive and market oriented tech-powered efficient driving solution. After 4 years of developments, and with the support of public and private investors, the product has already achieved a TRL of 7, with operation on course of real trials and pilots in a number of early-adopters of the product: It is worth mentioning bus urban fleets operating in Valencia (Spain) and Oslo (Norway) cities as well as the already shown interest of Istanbul (Turkey) city .
The feasibility study aims to prepare completed full operation plan that will fill the gap between the current product and the version to be widely disseminated and introduced at European level. ADN expectations consist of reaching an annual turnover of 10 million € by the end of 2019 with a phase II funding requirement estimated 1 million €.</objective>
  <title>Innovative services and platform for sustainable transport based on ecodriving techniques</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
