<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206099</rcn>
  <acronym>Trillium II</acronym>
  <objective>Trillium-II steps forward with an outstanding consortium to further advance global Electronic Health Record (EHR) interoperability. Activities surrounding the International Patient Summary (IPS) standards can nurture digital health innovation, lower trade barriers, and advance patient safety &amp; trust, bridging the gap between strategic intent and capability for action by Standards Development Organization (SDOs) striving for interoperability, quality, and safety through standards adoption.
Trillium-II builds on the vibrant community of Trillium Bridge to: (a) Improve international interoperability of eHealth Systems in US, in Europe and globally (b) Accelerate establishment of interoperability standards in eHealth with validated open source interoperability assets and sharing lessons learned with SDOs (c) Facilitate secure, seamless patient summary sharing  offering clarity and oversight.
Trillium-II aims to bridge, harmonize, evaluate existing patient summary initiatives and guide emerging ones, leading the way toward one IPS standard by establishing a global community fostering the practice of digital health innovation with robust widely-used interoperability standards and joint pilots. 
Trillium-II objectives are measurable, realistic and achievable objectives:
• Highlight the social value of IPS standards.
• Bridge IPS initiatives with validated interoperability assets, sharing lessons learned with SDOs  
• Contribute to IPS Standards Governance under the JIC 
•  Develop, Collect and Assess IPS Learning resources
• Engage mobile Health companies and app developers with IPS standards 
• Foster innovation &amp; inform health policy sharing IPS. 
Trillium-II will work with the workforce action, EU and US SDO platforms, large scale eHealth deployments, and emergency readiness exercises, to increase actionable interoperability of health systems in Europe the US and globally, nurturing innovation and fuelling creativity with effective use of standards and interoperability</objective>
  <title>Trillium Bridge II - Reinforcing the Bridges and Scaling up EU/US Cooperation on Patient Summary</title>
<identifier>H2020SC12016CNECT</identifier>
</project>
