<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210183</rcn>
  <acronym>CALIPSOplus</acronym>
  <objective>In the present project, CALIPSOplus, the relevant synchrotrons and free electron lasers in Europe and the Middle East join forces to contribute to the completion of ERA and to tackle the new challenges arising from the commitment of the EU to Open science, Open innovation and Open to the world. Integration with respect to user access, support, instrumentation, data analysis and data management is strongly pushed forward by this advanced community, looking back at a long tradition of integrated activities funded under FP6 and FP7, and largely profiting from the experiences already gained. The European Synchrotron and FEL User Organisation will be consolidated and the performance and use of the wayforlight portal as pivotal platform of the light sources community will be boosted. Data management of the different facilities will be harmonised and a data management plan for the CALIPSOplus consortium be defined. Particular focus will be on leveraging scientific excellence in EU-13 countries and on widening the use of light sources by users from these regions. This will be achieved by visits to universities in these countries, by dedicated schools and by an especially set-up Twinning programme. As a pilot action a specific Trans-national Access programme will be offered for users from SMEs, closely related to an awareness raising campaign for light sources use and the role of light sources as customers among local industry around the facilities. 
Joint Research Activities will focus on metrology of diffraction limited optics in collaboration with the manufacturing industry, of particular importance for the new hard X-ray free electron lasers as well as for the next generation synchrotrons, and on software tools for remote data analysis. Focusing on the horizon beyond 2020, established programmes and activities of the light source community will be evaluated with respect to their future importance and corresponding sustainability and business plans will be developed.</objective>
  <title>Convenient Access to Light Sources Open to Innovation, Science and to the World</title>
<identifier>H2020INFRAIA20161</identifier>
</project>
