<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206502</rcn>
  <acronym>CareSTOR</acronym>
  <objective>CareSTOR project will provide evidence (TRL8), at techno-economic perspectiveical and financial perspectives, and validate
a business case based on a ground-breaking solution for ultra-cheap Capacitive Energy Storage (CES). The solution is
enabled by an innovative intensified (hydrothermal) technology for the low-cost production of Advanced Nanoporous
Carbons (Figure 1).
Supercapacitor manufacturers (NSC &amp; APC) will access to a UNIQUE COMPETITIVE ADVANTAGE through 30-40%
decrease in technology price (KEY VALUE PROPOSITION-KVP) that will materialized into measurable benefits and
sustainable business. The project ambitions to boost deployment of Energy Storage Systems (ESS) in Green Vehicles and
usage of Renewable Energy Sources for Electricity (RES-E powered Grids) currently limited by cost barriers, with deep
implications for H2020 challenges and European competitiveness and employment.
CareSTOR consortia brings together the capacities and niche SUPERCAPACITOR market access to be the first EU-Selfsufficient
value chain with unprecedented KVPs addressing a niche market of € 50 million by 2018. To tackle market
opportunities, CareSTOR develops business-oriented Implementation including Scale-up (ENV), Prototype validation at
operational level and automated production tasks for Supercapacitor cells (CareCAP).
Key stakeholders are identified, pre_agreemets addressed including KPIs and deployed actions in place to assure
agreements to force and accelerate market uptake for NCP &amp; APC partners.
Final 12 months devoted to Product validation in operational environment (CARESS stage) as a result assessing business
success cases of the reliability and profitability of new ESS (4 Demo activities, Cost-Benefit assessment with scale-up data
for each one of the Demo actions) to validate, at commercial and technical perspectives market access after project
finalization.</objective>
  <title>Market Uptake of Sustainable and Competitive Carbons for Energy Storage</title>
<identifier>H2020FTIPilot20161</identifier>
</project>
