<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>204344</rcn>
  <acronym>CYPRESS</acronym>
  <objective>The proposal “CYPRESS”, standing for “CYprus Promotes RESearch and Science”, aims at organising two Researchers’ Night events, one in 2016 in Nicosia, celebrating the 10 years of the events in Cyprus and one in 2017 in Limassol, focusing on Cultural Heritage Research, on the occasion of Pafos being the European Capital of Culture. 

CYPRESS’ Coordinator, the Research Promotion Foundation (RPF), as the National Agency for supporting Research and Innovation (R&amp;I), has within its remit gained a long experience in organising activities for the promotion of R&amp;I towards the public and especially the younger generation, with the Researchers’ Night events being an integral part of its philosophy since 2006, with or without EC support, but always with vivid support from the National Research System.

RPF has secured the collaboration of all Universities in Cyprus, the major Research Institutes and Centres, R&amp;I-intensive Enterprises (mainly SMEs), Public Authorities, End Users and the Civil Society and for the first time Industrialist and Employers’ Associations, covering the Quadruple Helix of Innovation in a complementary way. As a novelty, RPF will also utilise a bottom up approach to attract new partners and will establish links with international partners.

Building on past experiences, CYPRESS will bring together researchers from all sectors and disciplines, along with the public, increasing appreciation of the researchers’ work, raising awareness on the importance of R&amp;I for society and the economy and motivating children to take up a career in research. Through a balanced mix of educational and entertaining, interactive activities, aiming at people of all ages, genders and educational backgrounds, and with the contribution of volunteers from the partners and RPF, the events will celebrate R&amp;I achievements, especially EU funded and will ultimately remove stereotypes about the researchers’ profession, creating a much needed R&amp;I culture among the Cypriot population.</objective>
  <title>CYprus Promotes RESearch and Science</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCANIGHT2016</identifier>
</project>
