<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211372</rcn>
  <acronym>WE4AHA</acronym>
  <objective>WE4AHA will advance the effective, large-scale uptake and impact of Digital Innovation for Active and Healthy Ageing (AHA), building on a comprehensive set of support and promotion services. Through WE4AHA’s centralised administration, coordination and external communication, the relevant stakeholders will be mobilised to help develop and implement three EU guided activities: Innovation to Market (I2M), Blueprint Digital Transformation of Health and Care for the Ageing Society, and EIP on AHA. 
WE4AHA will support the definition and execution of an I2M plan, further development of the Blueprint to drive the policy vision on digital innovation, and the consolidation of EIP on AHA Action Groups and Reference Sites. It will connect demand- and supply-side stakeholders through matchmaking, twinning, assessing innovative interventions using MAFEIP, and fostering engagement and many other support activities. It will leverage additional private and public investments by mobilising a growing number of stakeholders in Europe’s digital health and care and silver economy sectors - industry, public authorities, end users, financial institutions, investors, insurers, and research communities committed to innovate on a large-scale. 
WE4AHA will draw on its numerous, strong synergies and links to relevant H2020 R&amp;I actions and other EU and international programmes. The highly interdisciplinary consortium will ensure the proper execution of the work plan by leveraging the partners’ access to expertise and evidence. The consortium composition is an unparalleled matching of partners with strategic competences in health and active ageing and leading experts in policy analysis, research and innovation oriented to business, ICT enabling technologies, stakeholder engagement, communication, dissemination and the multiplier effect. Additional support is provided through a pool of experts and an Advisory Board of key stakeholder organisations with high-level competences in relevant fields.</objective>
  <title>Widening the support  for large scale uptake of Digital Innovation for Active and Healthy Ageing</title>
<identifier>H2020SC12017CNECT1</identifier>
</project>
