<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207003</rcn>
  <acronym>INTERFUTURE</acronym>
  <objective>The Directive 2009/128/EC sets rules in EU for the sustainable use of pesticides to reduce the risks and impacts of pesticide
use on people's health and the environment. Among the listed actions there is the promotion of low pesticide-input
management including non-chemical methods. In parallel several chemical active ingredients have been banned because of
toxicity concerns. The result is that growers are left with few control tools against pests. On the other hand most of the
available alternative control methods have several limitations, especially in term of efficacy. Several new ideas are not
reaching the industry and are confined in the academic would. The concept behind this EIT is to explore new approaches to
identify new cutting edge solutions for pest control based on new non classical approaches in strict collaboration with
industrial partner and to train 10 highly skilled early stage researchers (ESR) through a doctoral programme that integrates 5
academic research with concept-driven product development in 5 EU companies with a strong curriculum in development
and innovation within a large interdisciplinary environment. Microorganisms are often used so far as replacement of chemical
active ingredients. The innovative aspect of this EID is to base the new pest control solutions on interactions of
microorganisms with plants and insects rather than using them as plant protection products. Microorganisms’ unsurpassed
inclination towards the association with eukaryotic macro-organisms determines traits and qualities in the host that harbours
them. Microbial symbionts’ ability to profoundly transform their living habitat paves the way for unexplored outlooks in the
ability to use microbial symbioses as sustainable and renewable tools to improve production and quality in agriculture.
Microorganisms are key players in shaping several insect’s semiochemicals, in particular kairomones indicating a food
source or oviposition site for some insect species.</objective>
  <title>From microbial interactions to new-concept biopesticides and biofertilizers</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2016</identifier>
</project>
