<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>197246</rcn>
  <acronym>EJD-FunMat</acronym>
  <objective>EJD-FunMat is a European Joint Doctoral programme in the field of functional materials research. 
EJD-FunMat is embedded in an existing research network, with previous experience in co-tutelle doctorates , but the project will add new major elements, with the strategic aim of becoming a permanent reference European Joint Doctoral School in Materials Science and beyond.
The key innovative aspects of the programme are:
- Research in PhD clusters: The 15 PhD projects are grouped into 6 thematic clusters: Photocatalysis, Transparent Conductors, Lead-Free Piezoelectrics, Photonics, Cellulose-based Polymers, Bone Tissue Engineering. Each cluster has 3-4 academic, and several industry partners, thus forming a small-scale collaborative project. This concept will (i) will be a practical training in interdisciplinary teamwork for the PhD candidates and (ii) provide a critical mass of researchers with the potential to achieve breakthrough research and innovation, compared to individual PhD projects. Additional, locally funded PhD projects will be added to the clusters.
- Industry partner for each PhD: All PhD candidates will spend time in industry research laboratories, and will interact with industry throughout their project.
- Joint supervision rules centered on a series of common Deliverables for all PhD candidates, to be achieved during the PhD project
- Training in eco-design and life-cycle analysis of materials: topics such as critical raw materials and materials recycling have become crucial issues 
- Training in project and risk management
- Training in industrial intelligence, entrepreneurship and innovation skills
- Development of a sustainable framework for a joint PhD School. This strategic goal is based on 4 components:
  - scientific excellence
  - development of a legal framework for exploiting the research results
  - joint rules for co-tutelle PhDs, and joint PhD diplomas
  - attracting additional funding for PhD scholarships, during and after the project</objective>
  <title>European Joint Doctorate in Functional Materials Research</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2014</identifier>
</project>
