<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196180</rcn>
  <acronym>RemoteControl Device</acronym>
  <objective>The project is to commercialize Remote Controllable Trawl doors that will support Europe’s environmental and economic competitiveness by: 
1. Improved catch performance resulting in higher efficiency in food production. 
2. Lesser discards. 
3. Reduced fuel consumption of vessels. 
4. Less environmental side-damage and impact to the seabed.
5. Improved accuracy in seismic survey operations.
With remote controlled spreading devices the crew doesn’t need to pull trawl doors and vanes on board to change their position underwater. They will improve the performance of the fishing gear and seismic survey with a remote controllable system on the spreading device for the benefit of improved operation, greater catching ability for fishing, more economical for both operations in terms of reduced fuel consumption, less time consuming, and less environmental side damage and impact to the seabed. The convenient remote control is what we envisage as a key market application. The identified business opportunities are based on the revolutionary solution for the benefit of improved operation performance and reduced cost. 
Owners of fishing vessels of 30 meters and longer are the potential customers. The worldwide market for traditional trawl doors is estimated close to € 100 million yearly. The potential “reachable” market for our solution is estimated close to € 70 million. The market for pelagic doors is approximately half of the total market, or € 35 million. The market for vanes on a yearly base is evaluated close to € 40 million. The solution will address both European and global markets.
The specific objective for the feasibility study is to obtain a solid analysis of the potential market for the ‘Remote Controllable Spreading Devices’, in order to design an adequate market penetration strategy and ultimately to direct new investments. Phase 2 will include a 0,3 sqm model for Flume Tank tests and 5,0 to 6,0 sqm scaled prototype of ‘Remote Controllable Seismic Vanes’.</objective>
  <title>Remote Controllable Devices</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
