<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210202</rcn>
  <acronym>cyberwatching.eu</acronym>
  <objective>"cyberwatching,eu addresses the DS-05 call by defining and promoting a pragmatic approach to implement and maintain an EU Observatory to monitor R&amp;I initiatives on cybersecurity &amp; privacy, throughout EU &amp; Associated Countries. These initiatives will be clustered, with a cluster tool, and themes identified, leading to an online catalogue of services for cybersecurity &amp; privacy, showcasing market uptake and advancing EU sustainable competitiveness. A supply &amp; demand marketplace of EU cybersecurity products &amp; services, as well as the inclusion of an end-users’ club, ensures that perspectives of SMEs as well as other relevant stakeholders are properly taken account of. Ultimately, a cybersecurity &amp; privacy ecosystem will be created, offering prime and guided access to the cyberwatching.eu catalogue of services &amp; marketplace &amp; ensuring feedback in terms of effectiveness &amp; usability of research results.
The cyberwatching.eu consortium is domain-skilled &amp; complementary. Trust-IT: Expert SME in communicating ICT innovation, developing cybersecurity tools &amp; go-to-market strategies. The University of Oxford: Academic Centre of Excellence in CyberSecurity Research. ICT Legal: Legal expert in the field, Advisor Member &amp; Scientific Director of the European Privacy Association (EPA). DigitalSMEAlliance: An association representing the interests of ICT SMEs in EU. CONCEPTIVITY: SME experts in fighting cyber-crime and cyber-terrorism. AEI Ciberseguridad: A CyberSecurity Innovation Cluster. AON: #1 rated risk services firm, insurance broker, experienced in cyber risk management. An influential External Advisory Group passionate about cybersecurity &amp; privacy supports the consortia.
Main Outputs: Continuously updated observatory &amp; R&amp;I online catalogue, cluster tool, 4 concertation meetings, 4 annual workshops, 10 regional SME workshops, 10 webinars, 4 cluster reports, 2 white papers, 2 roadmaps, sustainability through cybersecurity &amp; privacy marketplace."</objective>
  <title>The European watch on cybersecurity  privacy</title>
<identifier>H2020DSSC72016</identifier>
</project>
