<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211599</rcn>
  <acronym>EASITrain</acronym>
  <objective>The two greatest obstacles to a wide spread adoption of superconductivity remain the limited understanding of its fundamental principles and the yet insufficient capability for large-scale, cost-effective deployment of the technology. Science rather than serendipity is the key to unlock the potentials of this alluring natural phenomenon. The proposed ITN integrates sound research projects aimed at learning to predict the behaviour of superconducting materials, at introducing innovative manufacturing techniques, at developing efficient cryogenic refrigeration techniques as key enablers for future applications and establishing these technologies as the new state of the art. The ambitious goals of this consortium are (1) making advanced superconductors fitter for the market, (2) assessing their innovation capacities and (3) equipping a new generation of researchers with the unique skills required to convert knowledge into products: Efficient grid power management, 21st century medical imaging, leaps in effectiveness of wind power generators, efficient electric propulsion systems and sustainable refrigeration for industry give an impression of the potential societal benefits that superconductor-based technologies can catalyze. This initiative under European leadership federates leading universities, research centres and industries, embracing a variety of science sectors, such as physics and mathematics, material sciences, process and mechanical engineering, refrigeration, cryogenics and innovation management. The intriguing blend of science and engineering, compounded by visionary application opportunities in companies, creates a fertile environment for innovative training of early-stage researchers. Significant training lead-times call for a dedicated action. This ITN will provide its fellows with a sound knowledge in the relevant fields along with business competences and prepare them for a broad spectrum of career opportunities in research and industry.</objective>
  <title>European Advanced Superconductivity Innovation and Training</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2017</identifier>
</project>
