<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205801</rcn>
  <acronym>VOPSA2.0</acronym>
  <objective>Omega-3 is an essential oil required by the body for proper functioning. It protects from cardiovascular diseases and
improves the development and functioning of the skin as well nervous and visual system. Astaxanthin is a carotenoid
pigment and is one of the most effective antioxidants to support human health.

The global demand for Omega-3 and Astaxanthin for human consumption will require large quantities of both products:
260.000 tonnes of Omega-3 and 670 tonnes of Astaxanthin per year. This growing demand comes mainly from health
conscious customer segment. This segment is also very interested in buying natural and eco-friendly products. However,
their traditional extraction process from marine organisms (mainly fish and krill) is not sustainable: over fishing, high energy,
raw materials consumption and a low efficiency. The majority of the marine resources are fully exploited or overexploited.

The SME Neoalgae has designed an eco-innovative and sustainable industrial bioprocess for obtaining Omega-3 and
Astaxanthin using marine microalgae as a natural source. This system is the answer to the growing demand in Omega-3 and
Astaxanthin, especially in nutraceutical, cosmetic and pharmaceutical applications. With the new process, production of
Omega-3 and Astaxanthin will not affect marine resources. Both products will be free of pollutants, without fishy aftertaste
and odour free, apt for vegans, and with competitive and stable production costs.

After the feasibility of the new products has been proved at a technical and market level, this SME-2 project will scale-up the
production of both compounds and will demonstrate their effectiveness through their inclusion in nutraceuticals and in new
ecological products for the treatment of 3 skin diseases: acne, atopic skin and aging skin produced by the SME Bicosome.
Both companies will benefit from a dramatic boost in their sales and improve their market positions, as well as
internationalising their businesses.</objective>
  <title>Value Omega 3 and Astaxanthin products from SeaAlgae</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST220162017</identifier>
</project>
