<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>213552</rcn>
  <acronym>YAKSHA</acronym>
  <objective>YAKSHA aims at reinforcing EU-ASEAN cooperation &amp; building partnerships in the cybersecurity domain by developing a solution tailored to specific user and national needs, leveraging EU Know-How and local expertise. YAKSHA will develop and introduce the innovative concept of honeypots-as-a-service which will greatly enhance the process of gathering threat intelligence. It will enhance cybersecurity readiness levels for end users, help prevent cyber-attacks, mitigate cyber risks and better govern the whole cybersecurity process. YAKSHA is ideally positioned to secure global manufacturing supply chains, given its planned focus on IoT Security.
YAKSHA will develop innovative methods for malware detection, collection and analysis, as well as design a specialised ontology to be used for long-term storage and analysis of the information, and deploy standard information formats and interfaces to facilitate interoperability. The YAKSHA software solution will be validated in real-world pilot projects in both regions, focusing on Vietnam &amp; Greece, but with plans to expand the deployments to other countries. The test cases will be represented by complex end-users with articulated cybersecurity risks and will allow the consortium to gather feedback to be used later to bring the solution to the market. YAKSHA will develop a comprehensive business plan for the transition of the solution and complementary services to TRL9, leveraging the very strong ASEAN partners that are members of the consortium - including governmental organisations and leading end-users communities and associations with regional scope. As part of this effort, YAKSHA will build a whole ecosystem of partners around its solutions. This will contribute to enhancing cybersecurity skills in Europe and creating new positions for cybersecurity specialists in ASEAN. Moreover, the direct access to the all-important ASEAN market provided to partners will positively impact the competitiveness of European security industry.</objective>
  <title>Cybersecurity Awareness and Knowledge Systemic High-level Application</title>
<identifier>H2020ICT20171</identifier>
</project>
