<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>213067</rcn>
  <acronym>REMOTE</acronym>
  <objective>REMOTE will demonstrate technical and economic feasibility of two fuel cells-based H2 energy storage solutions (integrated P2P system; non-integrated P2G+G2P system), deployed in 4 DEMOs, based on renewables, in isolated micro-grid or off grid remote areas. 
DEMO 1: Ginostra (South Italy): off-grid configuration (island); RES based on hybrid system with PV- generators; residential loads on-site; almost complete substitution of fossil fuels. End-user: ENEL Green Power utility;
DEMO 2: (Greece): isolated micro-grid application; RES based on hydro generators; industrial (SME) loads onsite; complete substitution of fossil fuels; avoid costs for new transmission line. End-user: Horizon SA owner of hydro plant; 
DEMO 3: Ambornetti (North Italy): off-grid configuration (remote Alps); RES based on hybrid system with PV-biomass CHP generators; residential loads on-site; complete substitution of fossil fuels. End-user: IRIS stakeholder of the hamlet;
DEMO 4: Froan Island (Norway): isolated micro-grid application; RES based on hybrid system with PV-wind generators; residential loads+ fish industry on-site; complete substitution of fossil fuels; avoid costs for new transmission line. End-user: Trønder Energi utility. VALIDATE the 4 DEMO units, to enable suppliers, end-users and general stakeholders to gain experience throughout the value chain of the energy storage; DEMOSTRATE the added value of the fuel cell-based H2 energy storage solutions with respect to alternative technologies in terms of economics, technical and environmental benefits; VALIDATE EU-based sub-MW P2P manufacturing solutions to fill the gap in the European energy storage sector while utilising the existing EU know-how already developed in previous consortium among partners; EXPLOITATION and BUSINESS scenarios for the replication of P2P solutions, considering different typologies of micro-grids (isolated or not); DISSEMINATION, build up confidence among stakeholders and raise public interest.</objective>
  <title>Remote area Energy supply with Multiple Options for integrated hydrogen-based TEchnologies</title>
<identifier>H2020JTIFCH20171</identifier>
</project>
