<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>202632</rcn>
  <acronym>WATERSPOUTT</acronym>
  <objective>The WHO estimates that in 2015 in Africa ~156 million people relied on untreated sources for their drinking water. WATERSPOUTT will design, develop, pilot and field-test a range of, sustainable point-of-use solar disinfection (SODIS) technologies that will provide affordable access to safe water to remote and vulnerable communities in Africa and elsewhere. These novel large-volume water treatment SODIS technologies will be developed in collaboration and consultation with the end-users, and include:
1. HARVESTED RAINWATER SODIS SYSTEMS for domestic and community use. (South Africa, Uganda). 
2. TRANSPARENT 20L SODIS JERRYCANS. (Ethiopia)
3. COMBINED 20L SODIS/CERAMIC POT FILTRATION SYSTEMS. (Malawi)
These are novel technologies that will create employment and economic benefits for citizens in both the EU and resource-poor nations. WATERSPOUTT will use social science strategies to: 
a. Build integrated understanding of the social, political &amp; economic context of water use &amp; needs of specific communities.
b. Examine the effect of gender relations on uptake of SODIS technologies.
c. Explore the relevant governance practices and decision-making capacity at local, national and international level that impact upon the use of integrated solar technologies for point-of-use drinking water treatment.
d. Determine the feasibility &amp; challenges faced at household, community, regional and national level for the adoption of integrated solar technologies for point-of-use drinking water treatment.
WATERSPOUTT will transform access to safe drinking water through integrated social sciences, education &amp; solar technologies, thus improving health, survival, societal well-being &amp; economic growth in African developing countries. These goals will be achieved by completing health impact studies of these technologies among end-user communities in Africa.  Many of the consortium team have worked for more than 15 years on SODIS research in collaboration with African partners.</objective>
  <title>Water - Sustainable Point-Of-Use Treatment Technologies</title>
<identifier>H2020WATER2015twostage</identifier>
</project>
