<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206396</rcn>
  <acronym>LysoMod</acronym>
  <objective>LysoMod will innovate in the area of personalized medicine for disorders linked to lysosomal dysfunction. This will be achieved by implementing a collaborative staff-exchange program between highly complementary and multidisciplinary academic and non-academic partners with expertise in pharmacology, medicinal chemistry, cell biology, biochemistry, mouse and human genetics, transcriptomics, proteomics and lipidomics. Based on the critical role that lysosomes play in cells, a better understanding of lysosomal function will have a major impact on human health, fostering the development of new strategies to improve quality of life for people affected by a variety of diseases, ranging from lysosomal storage diseases (LSDs) to age-related neurodegenerative disorders. LysoMod’s specific objectives are: 1) to develop and further optimize existing therapies for LSDs; 2) to identify new targets for personalized therapies for LSDs; and 3) to investigate the cross-talk between lysosomal function, signalling pathways and gene expression regulation. The pioneer work of a participant in the consortium led to the development of a drug that is approved for clinical use. LysoMod will i) investigate the mechanisms of action of this and other drugs in lysosome-related disorder; ii) identify modifier genes involved in LSD pathology and test their potential as new targets for personalized therapeutic approaches; iii) identify candidate RNAs that can be targeted to enhance lysosomal function. The companies in the consortium will ensure a rapid transfer of new knowledge into applications for diagnostics and clinical trials. Prioritising lysosomal dysfunction as a highly relevant biomedical problem, the LysoMod consortium will implement a mentored staff-exchange program to provide young researchers with high-level training in innovative approaches for exploring biological systems, preparing the next generation of researchers for careers either in the private or public health sectors.</objective>
  <title>Genetic and Small Molecule Modifiers of Lysosomal Function</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCARISE2016</identifier>
</project>
