<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207483</rcn>
  <acronym>BioDie2020</acronym>
  <objective>BioDie2020 will recover unconventional, degraded waste oils &amp; fats, notably from Water Company infrastructures, and demonstrate the conversion of these wastes as a sustainable feedstock for biodiesel production. This break-through &amp; beneficial pathway will maximise the use of waste oils &amp; fats on a large scale for the 1st time on the biodiesel market, leading to lower transport carbon emissions. BioDie2020 FTI combines 5 top EU players in an agile &amp; direct value-chain, working on this industry-wide milestone which will improve costs &amp; conversion, achieving high fuel quality. Project coordinator Argent (UK, INDUS), a forward-thinking biofuel leader, will thus demonstrate biodiesel production in a closed-loop business model. 2 key process improvements will go from TRL6 to 7 at Argent’s biodiesel plant (site at Stanlow, UK): i) biofuel technology provider BDI (Austria, SME) will deliver Sulphur reduction in the biodiesel process; ii) microwave technology provider LJMU (UK, Uni) will integrate their bespoke microwave unit to improve pre-treatment of challenging feedstocks. Stagecoach (UK, INDUS), a leading EU captive bus fleet service provider, will perform field trials of final biodiesel. Quantis (France, SME), an ambitious EU SME will perform LCA &amp; LCC analysis of the overall process, ensuring sustainability objectives are achieved. BioDie2020 partners own IP on each technical brick, giving pathways to market &amp; business opportunities. Argent will save ~€5 million/year on feedstock costs, improving ROIC from 12% to 18% by 2019. Demo of BDI’s new process will confer a competitive edge on the retrofit market, giving them a ~25% sales increase by 2020. BioDie2020 will deliver 17 direct jobs and ~100 indirect jobs created or sustained in the EU by 2020. Argent’s ultimate aim is to invest in biofuel deployment via this reproducible waste-to-biodiesel plant (embedded in a closed-loop business model) with market replication by 2020 via commissioning or acquisition &amp; retrofit.</objective>
  <title>Demonstration of new, challenging and high FFA waste oil and fat feedstock in biodiesel process with improved costs, conversion and high fuel quality</title>
<identifier>H2020FTIPilot20161</identifier>
</project>
