<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205557</rcn>
  <acronym>FUNGUSCHAIN</acronym>
  <objective>The project aims at the valorization of agricultural residues coming from mushroom (Agaricus Bisporus) farming residues as a case to set up new cascading possibilities using innovative procedures to extract high value bio-based additives (antioxidants, antimicrobials, proteins), convert lipids into bioplasticizers and polysaccharides (glucans and fermentable sugars) into biopolymers using remaining side streams in substrates to close the agricultural cycle by composting and/or biogas synthesis. The funguschain project will demonstrate its industrial viability by building a new biorefinery that will use cost-effective extraction technologies (MAE and HWPE) revalorizing more than 65% of waste into valuable additives.

These additives will be incorporated into high added value products and industrially validated towards 3 key value chains in the European economy (food, cleaning and plastic sectors). Industrial lines from end-users will be modified and adapted to the developed products. These products are: food supplements for elderlies, cleaning products, novel biobased thermoplastic masterbatches, bioplasticizers and industrial film products (thin bags and gloves &lt;15 microns, partially recycled thick bags &gt;50 microns and mulching).

A business strategy to valorise the products in a collaborative manner will be designed, leading to safe, sustainable, economically viable and attractive products acceptable to consumers. Partners will ensure that products meet legal and market requirements. The project will forge and propel industries growing within the frame of the European bioeconomy, boosting the community network.

The consortium involves 16 partners (4 RTDs, 4 Large industry and 8 SMEs) accounting with 5 BBI full members and 3 associate members. Funguschain project has a duration of 48 months and a total estimated budget of 8,143,661 M€ plus 3,500,000M€ in additional activities dedicated to the construction of the DEMO biorefinery plant.</objective>
  <title>Valorisation of mushroom agrowastes to obtain high value products</title>
<identifier>H2020BBIPPP201521</identifier>
</project>
