<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>193617</rcn>
  <acronym>NCP_WIDE.NET</acronym>
  <objective>The objective of the NCP_WIDE.NET is to create a transnational network of National Contact Points (NCPs) for Spreading Excellence and Widening Participation under Horizon 2020 in order to facilitate trans-national co-operation between NCPs, with a view to identifying and sharing good practices and raising the general standards of support to applicants, taking into account the diversity of actors, including newcomers, that make up the constituency of WIDESPREAD part. Project is targeted towards the Widespread NCP Forum - officially nominated WIDESPREAD NCPs in EU Member States and Associated Countries - including experienced and less experienced NCPs. Expected impacts of the proposal aiming at ensuring quality standards of services, lowering entry barriers and increased applications to Horizon 2020 will be reached through a portfolio of dedicated meassures. The overall logic of the proposal is based on the improving  and leveling of the NCPs capacities to deliver services of high quality standards, enhancing transnational collaboration between  applicants, delivering complex information on WIDESPREAD activities and promoting the Network itself. The implementation of the proposal includes following tailored actions:  internal trainings and mentoring based on benchmarking, support to WIDESPREAD expertise through development of guides and reports, transnational collaborative events for stakeholders such s brokerage events and joint workshops, actions dedicated to newcomers, networking activates, dissemination actions, complex source of information (Project Portal one-stop-shop) and promotion activities. Proposal addresses the work programme in terms of supporting and leveling NCPs capacity in delivering services of high quality standards. The project will contribute to more balanced development of ERA, spreading of excellence in research in all European regions and widening participation of research centers and stakeholders from weaker regions in H2020.</objective>
  <title>Transnational Network of cooperation for WIDESPREAD NCPs</title>
<identifier>H2020WIDESPREAD20143</identifier>
</project>
