<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>193441</rcn>
  <acronym>MEMAN</acronym>
  <objective>Present approaches to increasing resource efficiency in manufacturing companies are mainly focused on single process optimisation. A wider and integrated optimisation is assumed to have significantly higher savings potential.In fact, a pilot study has been performed by Greenovate!Europe, showing resource saving potentials of 70%.
Such a strategy should include optimisation across the interfaces between different steps in complex production chains and different companies involved in the overall value chain.
In that sense, MEMAN consortium brings together 15 partners from 6 countries represented by industrial enterprises, SMEs mainly, and service companies experts in eco-innovative models, working on improving the competitiveness of the metal mechanic sector, through the full validation of new business models that allow the collaboration of companies in the whole value chain in order to reduce global impacts in terms of energy and other resources.
MEMAN project will implement an approach to optimise resource efficiency across 3 manufacturing value chains cases, integrating an analytical toolbox based on MEFA and LCA and providing practical decision-making support. Furthermore, new business models will be developed to support the implementation of global energy and resources efficiency along the 3 value chains. Energy characterisations considering the whole value chain, will be also developed within MEMAN.
The consortium has the capacity and ambition of exploiting and reaching the market with the results of the project, at an international level, in terms of technology and business models. Hence, the technologies developed and the synergies created in the project would have the impact estimated bellow:
- Energy consumption and CO2 emission reduction for the final product between 20-30% from cradle to gate and between 30-35% from cradle to grave.
- Product's LCC reduction between 10-20% from cradle to grave.
The budget and the final requested EC contribution reaches 5.998.686€.</objective>
  <title>Integral Material and Energy flow MANagement in MANufacturing metal mechanic sector</title>
<identifier>H2020FoF2014</identifier>
</project>
