<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212912</rcn>
  <acronym>SINCERE</acronym>
  <objective>SINCERE, consistent with the EU research and innovation policy, will strengthen open international climate change research and innovation cooperation involving European partners in support of the implementation of the Paris Climate Agreement, including in the broader context of the Sendai Framework for Disaster reduction and the UN Sustainable Development Goals. SINCERE aims to strengthen the delivery of the JPI Climate Strategic Research and Innovation Agenda (SRIA), building on existing collaborations, such as with other JPIs, the business sector and global financial institutions, and other key international research, policy and societal actors. Expanding JPI Climate to include member countries in Eastern Europe is a particular goal. Two Flagship Actions, focused on the design of research and innovation collaborations in Africa and Latin America, aim to expand and deepen knowledge to support the uptake of climate change adaptation and mitigation policies, climate services and resilience to disasters linked to climate change. Targeted activities supported by an innovative outreach programme will enhance the international impact of JPI Climate research and innovation activities supporting both global science programmes and policy processes. 
SINCERE is uniquely positioned to internationalise European climate change research and innovation collaboration, bringing together major national European research funding organizations represented in JPI Climate and a number of research performing organisations mandated by JPI Climate Governing Board members, along with new partners, including two international partners. SINCERE partners have contributed to setting up and implementing the JPI Climate SRIA. This brings the advantages of trust and ease of communication between SINCERE and the governance of JPI Climate, notably the Governing Board and its Executive Committee, as well as the Central Secretariat, which is based at the same institution as the SINCERE coordinator.</objective>
  <title>Strengthening INternational Cooperation on climatE change REsearch</title>
<identifier>H2020SC52017OneStageB</identifier>
</project>
