<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>209950</rcn>
  <acronym>FIRE-IN</acronym>
  <objective>FIRE-IN has been designed to raise the security level of EU citizens by improving the national and European Fire &amp; Rescue (F&amp;R) capability development process. FIRE-IN addresses the concern that capability-driven research and innovation in this area needs much stronger guidance from practitioners and better exploitation of the technology potentially available for the discipline. We argue that this is to be achieved by practitioners more effectively coordinating on operational needs, on available research and innovation, on standardisation, and on test &amp; demonstration and training.  Further, we claim the need for the development of a common research culture that is to be achieved by better cooperation between practitioner and research/industry organisations. FIRE-IN addresses these objectives through four main areas of activity: (i) the identification and harmonisation of operational capability gaps based on the contribution provided by a significant and heterogeneous practitioner network, (ii) the identification of promising solutions to address those gaps through monitoring and screening of research outcomes and the continuous involvement of research and industry representatives, (iii) the definition of a F&amp;R Strategic Research and Standardisation Agenda (SRSA) based on the previous  elements as well as (iv) the development of a concept for more efficient use of test &amp; demonstration and training facilities to support innovation and joint skill development. 
The overarching result of the project will be a proven process for organising F&amp;R capability-driven research based on a wide practitioner and research and innovation network. The network will be linked at cross-domain and cross-border level and will feed harmonised operational requirements (or challenges) into national and EU capability development, i.e. research, innovation, procurement and standardisation programmes.</objective>
  <title>FIRE-IN - Fire and Rescue Innovation Network</title>
<identifier>H2020SEC201620171</identifier>
</project>
