<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>213529</rcn>
  <acronym>Mat4Rail</acronym>
  <objective>Europe’s railway industries require a step change in technologies and design for the next generation of rail vehicles in order to remain competitive globally. Innovative materials and modular design for rolling stock are considered to become key to success. Composite materials with their unique properties (lightness, repairabillity, corrosion resistance…) have demonstrated a high potential for lighter, more energy- and cost-efficient structural components in relevant sectors such aeronautic or automotive industries. However, currently available structural composites do not meet Fire, Smoke &amp; Toxicity requirements of the railway sector, and thus cannot be used for the manufacturing of carbodyshell parts.
Mat4Rail will face these challenges through a two-tier approach: In work stream I, our materials team (including resin producers, composite manufacturers, and experts on joining technologies and testing) will: i) synthesize novel fire retardant resins (epoxy, benzoxazine or hybrids) and manufacture composite batches; ii) modify fatigue and static load cases according to new requirements for polymeric materials; iii) further develop structural adhesive bonding combined with riveting and bolting for permanent and non-permanent joints and the repair of the new composites; and iV) assess novel design concepts for access door systems using new materials and joining technologies. In work stream II, our specialised design and engineering teams will develop new concepts for interior design of rolling stock including: i) plug and play systems which function like a limbic technical and power system for new electric utilities; ii) innovative lightweight seats and iii) a compact and ergonomic driver’s desk. Together, our multi-disciplinary consortium of 7 SMEs, 3 large industries, 5 RTDs and 1 UNI clearly has the experience and skills required to deliver innovations for uptake by the Shift2Rail JU members and the European railway industries.</objective>
  <title>Designing the railway of the future: Fire resistant composite materials and smart modular design</title>
<identifier>H2020S2RJUOC2017</identifier>
</project>
