<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196291</rcn>
  <acronym>WATLY</acronym>
  <objective>Water and energy are highly interdependent and are both crucial to human well-being and sustainable socio-economic development. In 2014, the UN reports that 768 million people worldwide still do not have access to a safe source of drinking water, and more than 1.3 billion lack access to electricity.
We have developed the Watly® unit with the goal of providing a solution for fast, simple and efficient wastewater treatment and energy supply in developing and/or remote regions. Watly combines cutting-edge technologies to offer i) complete sanitation for well, surface ground, sea or recycled rain water, ii) off-grid electricity from solar energy and iii) Wi-Fi internet connectivity, all in one portable autonomous unit.
Watly embodies the ambition of a European company to address a global market. The wide range of customers worldwide that could benefit from this all-in-one solution include diverse market segments such as: Governments and public institutions, Non-Governmental Organizations (NGO) and foundations, mobile hospitals, military organizations, hotels/resorts/businesses in remote destinations, massive open-air events, oil platforms, gas/oil &amp; construction sites, etc.
Scale-up beyond our current prototypes and industrialization of the production process is the key to growth and expansion of our company taking advantage of a new market opportunity. In order to do so, we are applying for SME Instrument Phase 1 funds to: (i) elaborate an exhaustive technical feasibility study focused on scale-up beyond our current prototypes, design and industrialization of the final commercial unit of Watly-L; (ii) elaborate a detailed business plan for the commercialization of Watly-L at the conclusion of the envisaged Phase 2 project. If the results of the feasibility study, both from the technical and commercial point of view, are positive, we will proceed to apply for Phase 2 funds in order to carry out the abovementioned scale-up, product refinement and industrialization tasks.</objective>
  <title>An autonomous and mobile water treatment plant powered by solar energy</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
