<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>198301</rcn>
  <acronym>BlueBRIDGE</acronym>
  <objective>BlueBRIDGE responds to the Juncker Investment Plan opening funding opportunities for e-Infrastructures, innovating current practices in producing &amp; delivering scientific knowledge advice to competent authorities &amp; enlarges the spectrum of growth opportunities in distinctive Blue Growth areas. 
BlueBRIDGE builds on existing EU and International e-Infrastructures providing capacity building in interdisciplinary research communities of scientists, data managers &amp; educators in academic institutions &amp; industries focusing on 4 major challenges: 1) stock assessment 2) socio-economic performance analysis in aquaculture 3) fisheries &amp; habitat degradation monitoring 4) education &amp; knowledge bridging on protection &amp; management of marine resources.
BlueBRIDGE capitalizes on past investments and uses a proven e-Infrastructure connecting 1500+ scientists, integrating +50 repositories, executing +13,000 models &amp; algorithms/month; providing access to over a billion quality records in repositories worldwide, with 99,7% service availability.
BlueBRIDGE focuses on user needs, opening services &amp; data to actors &amp; liaising with competent agencies &amp; SME Innovation Clusters. Major results include service-driven research environments addressing concrete challenges, data and a wide range of user defined Blue Growth indicators.
BlueBRIDGE leverages a set of common services that together foster the realization of an innovative infrastructure-based approach for collaborative knowledge and data sharing, publishing, citation, traceability &amp; trust concretely contributing to the e-Infrastructure Commons.
BlueBRIDGE will be deployed in 30 months by an authoritative &amp; complementary consortium with expertise in multiple scientific domains. It bundles forces from International Government Organizations, research institutes, industry, SMEs, education and computer science domains, establishing a network with a proven track in VREs &amp; e-Infrastructures, marine, environmental &amp; fisheries science &amp; economy.</objective>
  <title>Building Research environments for fostering Innovation, Decision making, Governance and Education to support Blue growth</title>
<identifier>H2020EINFRA20151</identifier>
</project>
