<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206254</rcn>
  <acronym>PJ20 AMPLE</acronym>
  <objective>Within the Single European Sky technological pillar, the European ATM Master Plan (ATM MP) is the roadmap to the horizon 2035+ to guide and connect ATM Research and Innovation and Deployment in building the future European ATM System.  The European ATM Master Plan Edition 2015 approved by the SESAR Joint Undertaking (SJU) Administrative Board and the European Commission and recently published, sets out Performance Ambitions and a Vision for European ATM, in full alignment with ICAO Global Air Navigation Plan.

The ATM MP is composed of three Levels; it can be consulted in the ATM MP Public Portal www.atmmasterplan.eu.

By EU Regulation 409/2013, the ATM MP is the essential instrument allowing all European ATM key civil and military stakeholders - Airspace users, Air Navigation Service providers, Airports, Network Manager, Airborne and Ground industry, Standardisation bodies and Professional Staff organisations - to share and further develop this common vision for the future European ATM and setting forth the SESAR solutions which following successful research are likely to be elicited to compose future Common Projects for operationally seamless and cost effective deployment.

The ATM MP needs to be a living plan, kept abreast of evolutions of the European ATM performance, progresses of the SESAR solutions research results and of deployment.  The duty of SESAR PJ20 AMPLE (ATM Master PLan for Europe) is to ensure the maintenance, update and alignment of the ATM MP three Levels and its associated Portal as a Common Support Activity of the SESAR 2020 Programme.

Under the leadership of EUROCONTROL through facilitated access to information rich performance based civil-military ATM data, PJ20 will bring together contributions of 15 (of 19) SESAR2020 members, ensuring the broad ATM representativeness required from air navigation service providers, airports, airborne and ground industry and network manager; all having a keen interest in future ATM evolution.</objective>
  <title>Master Plan Maintenance</title>
<identifier>H2020SESAR20152</identifier>
</project>
