<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>209911</rcn>
  <acronym>SAFER-LC</acronym>
  <objective>Over the past few years, there is one person killed and close to one seriously injured every day on level crossings. Therefore SAFER-LC aims to improve safety and minimize risk by developing a fully-integrated cross-modal set of innovative solutions and tools for the proactive management and design of level-crossing infrastructure.

These tools will enable road and rail decision makers to find even more effective ways to detect potentially dangerous situations leading to collisions at level crossings, prevent incidents at level crossing by innovative design and predictive maintenance methods, and mitigate the consequences of incidents/disruptions due to accidents or other critical events.

The project will focus both on technical solutions, such as smart detection services and advanced infrastructure-to-vehicle communication systems and on human processes to adapt infrastructure design to end-users and to enhance coordination and cooperation between different stakeholders from different transportation modes.

The project will first identify the needs and requirements of rail-road infrastructure managers and LC users and then seek to develop innovative smart detection and communication systems and adapt them for use by all types of level crossing users.

A series of pilot tests across Europe will be rolled out to demonstrate how these new technological and non-technological solutions can be integrated, validate their feasibility and evaluate their performance.

The project will deliver a bundle of recommended technical specifications (for standardisation), human processes and organizational and legal frameworks for implementation.

SAFER-LC will also develop a toolbox accessible through a user-friendly interface which will integrate all the project results and solutions to help both rail and road managers to improve safety at level crossings.</objective>
  <title>SAFER Level Crossing by integrating and optimizing road-rail infrastructure management and design</title>
<identifier>H2020MG2016TwoStages</identifier>
</project>
