<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>193735</rcn>
  <acronym>Net4Mobility</acronym>
  <objective>The objective of the Net4Mobility project is to facilitate the transnational cooperation between the National Contact Points (NCPs) of the Marie Sklodowska-Curie Actions (MSCA). The project aims to achieve the following two goals: 1) mutual support and thus raising the general standard of applicants (taking into account the diversity of the different actors) 2) to better inform the research and innovation stakeholders on funding possibilities in the MSCA and help them to improve their  performance. Thus, ultimately our goal is to support research and innovation. As a synergy effect, the work processes of REA, EC and NCPs will be optimized and more effective. 
The project will help less experienced NCPs to improve their service so that their beneficiaries become more competitive. Less experienced NCPs shall be able to rapidly acquire knowledge from the community of MSCA NCPs. Net4Mobility has to raise awareness of MSCA funding possibilities in the non-academic and the academic sectors, especially for the new funding schemes or new modes in existing ones. 
The project will achieve these goals by the implementation of a wide array of measures, e.g.: 
- Trainings based on the needs of MSCA NCPs in particular with regards to the challenges of Horizion2020 
- 'Twinning' visits and Best Practice Meetings to tap into the already existing knowledge of MSCA NCPs 
- Communication platforms for the constant exchange and transfer of knowledge 
A number of public engagement activities and networking events with relevant stakeholders round up the project's activities. 
Net4Mobility relates to the Work Programme for MSCA 2014-2015 ‘Call for Transnational cooperation among Marie Skłodowska-Curie National Contact Points (NCP)’. The activities are tailored according to the nature of the area and the priorities of the involved NCPs according to the EC Guide on the NCPs principles for H2020</objective>
  <title>Net4Mobility: Network of the Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions National Contact Points</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCANCP2014</identifier>
</project>
