<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196624</rcn>
  <acronym>ROLL-OUT</acronym>
  <objective>This R&amp;I action will focus on optimally combining traditional roll-to-roll (R2R) compatible fabrication technologies such as printing with unique R2R sputtering, ALD and heterogeneous integration for flexible, thin, large-area electronics applications. It is seen that the different R2R fabrication methods all have their strengths and weaknesses such that using a cost-performance-optimized combination of them for a single production will enable new levels of applicability for TOLAE devices for mass markets. The goal of the ROLL-OUT project is to create a multi-purpose technology for, thin, large-area, high-performance, smart, and autonomous systems comprising of integrated circuits (based on metal-oxide thin-film transistors), sensors, and electronics. They will be utilized in advancing the packaging, automotive interiors and textile industries beyond their traditional scope. The key features are high-performance circuits and components. To fabricate high-performance circuits, the project intends to use novel, hybrid, moderate-temperature, roll-to-roll processes, namely sputtering, Atomic Layer Deposition (ALD) and screen-printing on thin, flexible, large-area substrates. This will enable enormous value addition to the products of European industries without adding any significant extra cost. 

ROLL-OUT has 5 research organizations (RO) and 5 industrial partners (IND). The action has 6 work-packages (WPs) of which 3 are led by ROs and 3 by INDs. The technology development WPs are led by ROs and demonstration and exploitation WPs are led by INDs. The action intends to create 3 tangible industrial smart, autonomous system demonstrators that will be validated by the industrial partners in accordance with standard testing protocols.

The action seeks EU funding of 3.66M€ for a period of 36 months. 356,5 person-months will be dedicated to the work. The consortium consists of partners from 7 EU member states with complimentary expertise essential for the action.</objective>
  <title>High-performance, Flexible, AUTOnomous Systems manufactured with Unique, Industrial ROLL-to-roll equipments</title>
<identifier>H2020ICT20141</identifier>
</project>
