<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>201741</rcn>
  <acronym>Smart Library</acronym>
  <objective>Children spend many hours using technology. Parents are concerned about having their children using new technologies without adequate educational resources. To resolve this need, Smile and Learn places technology at the service of education with the mission of helping children 2 to 12 years old learn while having fun using technology. We use games, interactive stories and technology to help educate children in universal values, learn curriculum contents and reinforce their multiple intelligences.
We are developing one single Smart Digital Library of Edutainment that gives access to +100 individual proprietary apps, offering clients a smart recommendation model based on children’s performance and that is already a reality with 18 apps on the market with great acceptance (+200,000 downloads). It is based on:
• 100% proprietary customized content based on S&amp;L’s educational framework.
• Smart recommendation model based on children’s interaction, leveraging big data analysis, machine learning and collaborative filtering. 
• Mobile, multi-device, multi-platform and child-safe.
Global mobile market for education and entertainment for children will grow from €12B to €26B from 2014 to 2020. The market is currently highly fragmented and has no global winners. The opportunity for an approach that truly combines entertainment and education is clear. Our goal is to lead this white space worldwide. 
Our goals for the coming months through the H2020 program are to finish the Smart Library’s integration and testing, run on site market studies focusing on Spain as our pilot market and adapt the business model’s development to the pilot’s results.
Our project is framed within the global education challenge. We will finish phase I before June 2016. Once all tasks are finished, we will update the prototype with all the components newly tested and market them in the major EU and American markets. We will begin phase II of the SME instrument to support the growth process.</objective>
  <title>The Smart Digital Library of Edutainment by Smile and Learn</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12015</identifier>
</project>
