<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212930</rcn>
  <acronym>CLIC</acronym>
  <objective>"The characteristics of cultural heritage and landscape pose significant challenges for its governance. Long since cultural heritage is considered as a resource for local development strategies. But there are some contradictions. The sites recognized as cultural heritage are increasing; the costs for functional reuse are growing, while public resources available are becoming scarcer, and private actors are increasingly focused on the short time for payback. The consequence is that there is a growing risk that the decay of heritage will increase year by year because of lack of financial support. Cultural heritage is a non-renewable capital and it is linked to the economy because economics refers to the management of scarce and non-renewable resources; for these reasons, heritage conservation is also an economic choice. 
The CLIC project addresses significant challenges of cultural heritage and landscape adaptive reuse. It progresses the agenda on heritage-led local sustainable development by developing flexible, transparent, integrated and inclusive tools to manage the change of cultural landscape, which are required to leverage the potential of cultural heritage for Europe. The investment gap in cultural heritage and landscape regeneration will be addressed by CLIC through careful evaluation of all costs, of ""complex values"" and impacts of adaptive reuse, selecting function(s) not only linked to tourism attractiveness, but also for the well-being improvement, providing critical evidence of wealth, jobs, social, cultural, environmental and economic returns on the investment.
The overarching goal of the CLIC trans-disciplinary research project is to identify evaluation tools to test, implement, validate and share innovative ""circular"" financing, business and governance models for systemic adaptive reuse of cultural heritage and landscape, demonstrating the economic, social, environmental convenience, in terms of long lasting economic, cultural and environmental wealth."</objective>
  <title>CLIC - Circular models Leveraging Investments in Cultural heritage adaptive reuse</title>
<identifier>H2020SC52017OneStageB</identifier>
</project>
