<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>213099</rcn>
  <acronym>RobotUnion</acronym>
  <objective>S4R will discover, support and fund 20 European Superstar Scaleups confirmed by top VC investors and global corporates of 4 new market domains for robotics: manufacturing, agriculture, healthcare and civil infrastructure.

40 companies developing research will be selected out of a pan-European deal flow of 300 Scaleups through 2 Open Calls. The top 20 will join an acceleration programme that will help them progress from TRL4 to TRL7 onwards. This 6 to 12-months programme will provide them with technical and non-technical support services:
• Ph-D in residence type of service (the so called Researchers-in-Residence  will provide access to knowledge in abilities such as configurability, adaptability, motion, manipulation, decisional autonomy, dependability, interaction, perception and cognitive ability)
• Entrepreneur-in-residence type of support (provided by a pool of world class training and high level business mentoring complemented by fundraising mentors)
• A voucher scheme to provide access to facilities and technical services across Europe
• Up to €200K of free-equity funding for the best-in-class companies.

8 best-in-class companies will start a fundraising campaign led by the VCs and platforms in the consortium leveraging the €8M of public funding with additional €8M of private investment.

To this end S4R counts on 5 premier-class RTOs specialized in Robotics at European Level to provide technical support;  4 corporates enabling access to new markets: MADE in Manufacturing, ARLA food in Agri-food, FENIN in Healthcare and FERROVIAL in Infrastructure; CHRYSALIX and ODENSE S&amp;V,  as VCs of references in robotics, to lead the fundraising campaigns.
Business support partners are FMWC (dissemination), FBA (open call management), ISDI (business acceleration) and BLM (fundraising and access to corporates).

S4R will help demonstrate how Europe can lead disruption around Robotics and turn the EU into the EU of entrepreneurial states</objective>
  <title>Stimulate ScaleUps  to develop novel and challenging TEchnology and systems applicable to new Markets for ROBOtic soLUTIONs</title>
<identifier>H2020ICT20171</identifier>
</project>
