<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>199360</rcn>
  <acronym>ORZEL</acronym>
  <objective>The overall aim of the ORZEL project is to boost the scientific excellence and technology-transfer capacity in organic electronics of the Silesian University of Technology (SUT) by creating a network with the high-quality Twinning partners: University of Durham (UDUR), Institute of Nanoscience and Cryogenics, Commissariat à l’Energie Atomique et aux Energies Alternatives (INAC) and Eindhoven University of Technology (TUE). To achieve this aim, the 3 year project will build upon the existing strong research and innovation base of SUT and its Twinning partners. 

To boost their scientific excellence and technology transfer capacity in organic electronics, the partners will implement a science and innovation strategy focused on three sub-topics: 

1. Innovative organic light emitting diodes (OLEDs) – SUT with UDUR
2. Advanced characterisation of charge transport in organic electronics - SUT with INAC
3. Advances in organic solar cells (OSCs) – SUT with TUE

The science and innovation strategy takes into account the recent SWOT analysis of SUT and has the following objectives: 

• Objective 1: Strengthen SUT’s research excellence in organic electronics
• Objective 2: Enhance the research and innovation capacity of SUT and the Twinning partners 
• Objective 3: Raise the research profile of SUT and the Twinning Partners 
• Objective 4: Contribute to the SMART Specialisation Strategy of the Poland
• Objective 5: Support research and innovation on a European level 

In order to achieve these objectives, the consortium partners will implement a comprehensive set of measures via the project’s work packages: 

• Short term staff exchanges (WP1); 
• Training workshops, conferences and summer schools (WP2); 
• Dissemination and outreach (WP3).</objective>
  <title>Boosting the scientific excellence and innovation capacity in organic electronics of the Silesian University of Technology</title>
<identifier>H2020TWINN2015</identifier>
</project>
