<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212366</rcn>
  <acronym>PARE</acronym>
  <objective>The overall objective of PARE (Perspectives for the Aeronautical Research in Europe) is to trigger collaboration between European stakeholders to support the achievement of the Flightpath 2050 goals, by providing yearly reports (and respective methodology) that assess the progress, gaps and barriers and propose suitable measures to close the remaining gap. The main outputs of PARE are three yearly reports on the “Perspectives for Aerospace Research in Europe” that use specific benchmarks to assess the progress towards each of the 23 Flightpath goals and the gap remaining. The assessment includes EU projects (Clean Sky, SESAR and others), national projects, academic and industrial research reports. Aspects like long-distance travelling and relevant emerging technologies from non-aeronautical sectors are focused, as well as greater participation from recent EU member states (e.g. in Eastern Europe) and associated countries (e.g Ukraine). The activities of Europe’s competitors (e.g. the U.S.) are also considered in PARE to assess: areas of EU leadership to be exploited; areas requiring specific effort in the EU to catch-up; areas of common interest for cooperation. 
PARE will contribute to fulfil the “Mobility for Growth” workprogramme with an assessment of progress in aerospace research, gaps and bottlenecks. The comprehensive yearly report (RC), can originate a public version (RP) and specific versions for academy and research (RA), industry, airlines and airports (RB) and certification authorities, international and professional associations (RC). The wide dissemination of each report will allow to collect feedback to improve the next one thus establishing the final reporting procedure that could be extended beyond the end of the project. Also addressed is the attraction of young talent and the increase in the participation of woman in aerospace including the preparation of a newsletter on exciting and attractive developments in aeronautics.</objective>
  <title>Perspectives for the Aeronautical Research in Europe</title>
<identifier>H2020MG2017SingleStageRTDMOVE</identifier>
</project>
