<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206101</rcn>
  <acronym>GoSAFE RAIL</acronym>
  <objective>The GoSAFE RAIL project will be transformative for asset safety in the rail sector. It will bring together inter-disciplinary experts from Risk based asset assessment of infrastructure, Artificial Intelligence (AI), object detection and data management sectors with leaders in network micro-simulation modelling to deliver a Decision Support Tool that will allow a step change for infrastructure safety. The involvement of Infrastructure Managers and Railway Undertakings will ensure the R&amp;D performers have access to data and through collaboration with the Shift2Rail initiative and complementary H2020 projects, access to demonstration sites (a number of preferred tunnel and bridge monitoring locations have already been selected) necessary to develop the tool and a ready market to commercialise it. Through the development of a Network Decision Support Tool the project will provide integrated solutions to issues related to infrastructure safety and planning considering a number of common problems faced by EU infrastructure managers. 

The project aligns directly with the Shift2Rail (S2R) masterplan and the three technology demonstrator projects in the Intelligent Asset Maintenance pillar (TD 3.6, 3.7 and 3.8). In particular it will  address (i) Integration of Open-Linked Data from a range of sources and transformation to allow for direct use in a safety framework incorporating network modeling, (ii) Real-time methods for object detection will be developed and demonstrated, (iii) Analytical models incorporating Artificial Intelligence (AI) algorithms will be developed to predict asset degradation and (iv) The safety framework can be used to plan maintenance and intervention strategies with the lowest whole life cycle cost.</objective>
  <title>GoSAFE RAIL – Global Safety Management Framework for RAIL Operations</title>
<identifier>H2020S2RJUOC2015012</identifier>
</project>
