<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>213227</rcn>
  <acronym>BIRAN</acronym>
  <objective>The BIRAN project targets the environmental and competitiveness challenge of the European aeronautics sector, by addressing the topic of experimental validation rig testing to develop aerodynamic and acoustic technologies for the rear stages of VHBR IP turbines.
The advancement of IP Turbine technologies, as an important contributor to the VHBR engine concept, will participate significantly to the global objectives from Clean Sky2, which aim towards achievement of ACARE flight-path 2050 ambitious goals about CO2, NOx and Noise emissions.
The global objectives of this proposal are aligned with the targets marked by Rolls-Royce for the Middle of Market Technology configuration. This proposal will deliver individual improvements in sub-system technology developments, to support the overall development of system level technologies capable of delivering substantial reductions in emissions.
The specific objectives of CTA, as applicant partner, include all the tasks to permit the experimental validation of relevant technologies (i.e. design, instrumentation, manufacturing, assembly, testing and supply of all test data). 
First four work packages are focused on the activities to develop and test a multistage rig of the rear stages, comprising all the aerodynamic and acoustic technologies individually developed in ORBIT project, in order to characterize how these technologies interacts, and therefore to validate them in a further TRL.
The fifth WP is committed for the comparison of the former results with relevant reference rig test, as an opportunity to integrate the new knowledge and enable the application of the innovations.
To guarantee the success of this proposal, it is required to develop European world-class test capability that includes the acquisition of testing and measurement technologies. Experience from the participation in previous R&amp;T European programmes is key to minimize program risks and deliver successfully rig testing in the required time scales.</objective>
  <title>IP TurBIne Rear Stage Aero/Noise Rigs</title>
<identifier>H2020CS2CFP06201701</identifier>
</project>
