<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>194835</rcn>
  <acronym>EU-LIVE</acronym>
  <objective>EU-LIVE will provide a comprehensive European solution for the next generation of electrified, cost- and energy-efficient light urban vehicles to cope with the challenges of future personal urban mobility, based on both user needs and acceptance.

EU-LIVE will establish the "EU-LIVE modular platform", a systematic approach for efficiently designing, developing and building a wide range of L-category vehicles from more close-to-the-market to radically new ones. This comprises a set of modular electrified powertrain components and subsystems for PHEVs and BEVs, modular bodies (within the same L-vehicle class), and an integrated modular co-simulation platform to guarantee re-usability, flexibility and sharing of components as well as subsystems for L-category vehicles.

EU-LIVE will provide innovative solutions regarding cost-efficient, energy-efficient, low-emission and low-noise powertrains (in-wheel motors, novel highly efficient transmission for PHEV, 48V batteries + electric board net …) and future-proof, flexible and scalable vehicle architectures. To leverage expertise beyond the consortium, an open innovation contest for a radically new light vehicle based on the EU-LIVE modular platform will be carried out. Eventually, both real and virtual full-vehicle demonstrators (L5e PHEV 3-wheeler beyond EURO 5, L3e BEV 2-wheeler, L6 BEV 4-wheeler) will be shown.

By its modular approach and the efficient transfer of expertise from high-volume automotive to low-to-medium-volume light vehicle industry, EU-LIVE will enable economies of scale, therefore overcoming a major barrier to affordable light urban vehicles. Through its excellent partner consortium - including 2 OEMs and several key suppliers - EU-LIVE is able to credibly provide a clear route to market for a range of different L-category vehicles which feature series producibility, attractive cost-of-ownership, full comfort, safety and connectivity, for both European and non-European markets.</objective>
  <title>Efficient Urban LIght VEhicles</title>
<identifier>H2020GV2014</identifier>
</project>
