<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>204355</rcn>
  <acronym>EnviroALARM</acronym>
  <objective>EnviroALARM is an eco-innovative online monitoring system specially developed to significantly improve the existing technologies for groundwater (GW) pollution surveillance, contributing to radically reduce the potential environmental impact of contaminant leakages from hydrocarbon and/or chemical storage sites. 
There are over 1 million sites with high potential to contaminate GW worldwide (petrol stations, refineries, storage centres, etc.). At present, there is not an affordable and reliable system to daily detect hydrocarbon leakages to groundwater.  EnviroALARM fits within the European priorities to prevent and minimize environmental impacts, developing an eco-innovative product to continuously monitor the potential presence of hydrocarbons in the GW. The global environmental monitoring market is poised to grow at a Compound Annual Growth Rate (CAGR) of 7.5% during 2015-2020, and is expected to reach a value of ~$20.5 Billion in 2020.
The main advantages of EnviroALARM over current competitors are: i) Daily monitoring, promoting the early detection and hence the measures to mitigate the contamination; ii) High sensitivity to the presence of contaminants, detecting leaks below 0.4 l/h. iii) Reliable without false alarm based on a proprietary sensor technology; iv) Wireless system not requiring civil work installation; v) Significant cost reduction (up to 80%) over current market competitive solutions. EnviroALARM innovative sensor based on a physicochemical reactions is unique in the world. This solution present a huge market opportunity, since it applies to a worldwide problem offering an easily replicable and transferable technology that fulfils the increasing regulations at EU and international level.
The main objective of the present proposal is the determination of EnviroALARM technological and economic feasibility. After checking its feasibility, an upgraded EnviroALARM prototype will be developed in order to conduct several demonstration activities.</objective>
  <title>Early alarm system for groundwater contamination monitoring</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
