<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>198908</rcn>
  <acronym>ANGEO2</acronym>
  <objective>The objective of ANGEO2 is to develop an orientation aid that is both adapted and directly useful for persons suffering from
spatial disorientation, whether they be cognitively-impaired or visually-impaired persons. The product will provide easy
access to urban areas and include multimodal guidance functions mixing walking with real time bus, tram and metro public
transportation information.

ANGEO2 is an incremental innovation in the niche market of urban mobility for sufferers of visually-disorientation, epilepsy, Parkinson's and Huntington. Reliable information is the key to reassuring the user and therefore providing autonomous mobility. The need for these devices is getting stronger everyday, however the market for orientation aids has not yet taken off. Why is this? The reason is that the services offered up to now are simply not reliable enough in terms of continuous service availability and accurate guidance. The unique selling proposition of ANGEO2 is the full availability of reliable navigation information in difficult urban environments.

A summary of the different types of product and service offerings from the business model is shown below:
• ANGEO-Mobile kits running without a smartphone
• ANGEO-Pos high performance positioning modules linked to a smartphone
• ANGEO-Nav, freemium navigation software running on a smartphone
• ANGEO-Help, a payable helpline using an externalised, remote-assistance platform

For a requested EU grant 713K€, an estimated 46 M€ of cumulated sales will create up to 80 jobs over a 5 year period. An
open development platform for the European healthcare industry to create derivative offerings will also be made available.</objective>
  <title>For cognitively-impaired or visually-impaired persons suffering from spatial disorientation, a smartphone-based navigation aid that is both reliable and safe for urban pedestrian mobility.</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST22015</identifier>
</project>
