<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211490</rcn>
  <acronym>DeviceHub</acronym>
  <objective>The Internet of Things – a vast network of smart objects which work together – is becoming a reality. The number of connected devices is forecasted to reach 50 billion units worldwide by 2020. A wide range of industries – auto makers, healthcare, airlines, banks, smart homes, public institutions or retail giants - are making their products available on various digital platforms. Estimated total IoT market size across all horizontal markets to reach €4.59 trillion by 2018.

Today, upon creating an IoT development strategy companies either assemble an internal team that will develop the solution and applications platforms, or outsource the development of a custom built IoT platform to fragmented 3rd party development houses. The process is expensive and fragmented by lacks of standardization or a universal and scalable solution encompassing all aspects of the IoT ecosystem. SoA solutions inhibit IoT development for SMEs and inventors with high entry barrier, prolonged time-to-market and high developmental risks. 

DeviceHub.net is the first universal, open source ecosystem management platform (EMP) for IoT. We bridge the gap between hardware devices and mobile/web developers by providing a collection of straightforward tools to both ends. DeviceHub is scalable platform that allows SMEs or even single users with little coding or app development experience to create end-to-end IoT solutions with provided hardware, apps for iOS/Android/web and integrated data analytics, i.e. business intelligence (BI) tools, all under one umbrella of DeviceHub, at a fraction of the cost and time of currently available, fragmented solutions.

The proposed project addresses the topic SMEInst-01-2016-2017, with the first commercially available, ‘end-to-end’ IoT ecosystem management platform. As a catalyst for innovation, our innovative scheme will disrupt the IoT industry with a unique product that will bridge the technological gap for IoT developers in both the public and private domains.</objective>
  <title>The next generation of internet-of-thing (IoT) connectivity.</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
