<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210706</rcn>
  <acronym>SWaT</acronym>
  <objective>The needs in the water drinking water quality monitoring and treatment are related to:
1) Detection and quantification of chemical contaminants  as well as to detect and eliminate biological contaminants ensuring the water quality required by legislation
2) Implementation of drinking water systems to detect and kill Legionella.
3) Reduction of  the use of chemical additives for environmental purpose and quality water purpose. 
SWaT(Safe Water Treatment System) will be a system for sanitizing water that will combine innovative technologies based on nanomaterials and new screen-printed bio(sensors), and a sustainable water ultraviolet treatment system, creating an unique equipment for on-site monitoring and removing of chemical pollutants (Cadmium, lead, arsenic and mercury, and Bisphenol A) and biological (Legionella and amoebae) pollutants in water. The novelty of SWaT lays in its capacity to monitor in real time pollutants (15 minutes vs. 1 day of current technologies), and moreover to remove these contaminants by a UV ray in combination with a filtering nanostructure (below the regulation threshold limits (1μg/l)) in an environmentally friendly way (avoiding the emission of 866.629 gCO2e for each kilogram of chemical additive reduced). Additionally SWaT will be the first technology monitoring of Amoebae, which have been recently demonstrated to host Legionella, and increased its resistance to the sanitation treatment. Currently SWaT have reached a TRL 6 in the scale from idea to application. To reach the TRL 9 will carry out a Feasibility Study in which we will analyse its technical feasibility, the commercial feasibility and the financial feasibility. SWaT will address the EU challenges  of reduce the Legionella diseases in hotels and hospitals, and improving the water quality by reducing the chlorite in water. Our target users are the hospitals and hotels requiring water monitoring and treatment technologies to ensure healthy water to patients and hostages.</objective>
  <title>An innovative system capable of monitoring and removing heavy metals, phenolic compounds and biological pollutants in drinking water</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
