<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211720</rcn>
  <acronym>PHOTO-EMULSION</acronym>
  <objective>The polymer industry is going through one of the most significant periods of change in its history. Driven by new environmental regulations, the development of eco-efficient processes and zero-VOC products has become an absolute necessity. In this field, 2 technologies stand out: Polymerisation in dispersed media and Photopolymerisation. To maintain EU leadership in this sector, PHOTO-EMULSION aims at training a creative, entrepreneurial &amp; innovative next-generation of 8 Early-Stage Researchers (ESRs) who can push towards new eco-friendly polymerisation processes. Our primary strength is a demanding technical knowledge base bringing together, for the first time, all disciplines related to these 2 strategic fields. Secondly, we will broaden traditional doctoral training by targeting transferable and specialized skills sought after by the employers, and learned through innovative methods: tandem ESRs, distance language learning, ESR as itinerant science educator, online courses, ESR-led subproject, highly interactive meetings, and industrial secondments. In research, we will develop a “hybrid” next-generation technology based on thiol-ene photopolymerisation in dispersed media. Advanced manufacturing based on photoreactor promises a wave of high sulfur content dispersed products (films, nanoparticles, porous network). Their outstanding properties open the door to applications responding to current Industral needs such as non-leaching materials, O2 barrier and biobased waterborne coatings, biologically-active particles, hybrid nanosensors and monolithic chromatography column. PHOTO-EMULSION involves a high-quality research network including 8 internationally reputed academic institutions, 4 leading companies and 2 non-profit organisations. Balanced &amp; EU-wide, our diversity expresses through the participation of 8 countries (Austria, France, Germany, Ireland, Poland, Slovenia, Sweden &amp; Spain), 50% female scientists-in-charge, and structures supporting gender equality.</objective>
  <title>Towards Next-generation Eco-efficient PHOTO and EMULSION PolymerisationsImparting Synergy to Process, Products and Applications</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2017</identifier>
</project>
