<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>200068</rcn>
  <acronym>SIMPLA</acronym>
  <objective>SIMPLA responds to topic EE 7 ‘Enhancing the capacity of public authorities to plan and implement sustainable energy policies and measures’ and its ultimate goal is empowering public authorities to develop, implement and finance sustainable energy policies and actions by creating the conditions for a smart integration between SEAPs (Sustainable Energy Action Plans) and SUMPs (Sustainable Urban Mobility Plans) - or similar plans - in cities, towns and their aggregations with a population between 50.000 and 350.000 inhabitants. 
SIMPLA’s work-plan focuses on the establishment of a network of National Focal Points (NFPs) in 6 countries (expanding to further 12 through replication actions) merging technical expertise, methodological know-how and institutional capacity of technical partners and public authorities. 
The NFPs realize an ambitious, innovative work-plan, encompassing  capacity building and coaching (on-site and via the web), enhancement of multi-level governance looking for synergies and economies of scale, extensive involvement of public authorities and stakeholders, promotion of mutual learning and best practices.
EU added value (involving countries and areas with different levels of tradition in integrated mutli-sector planning) and capitalization of previous EU-funded initiatives are among the project's guiding principles.
SIMPLA thus contributes to the EU’s energy and climate targets for 2020 and beyond, reducing GHG emissions, increasing the share from RES and improving energy efficiency, focusing upon sectors with high energy-saving potential (primarily  buildings, renewables for electricity production, urban freight transport and passengers’ mobility).
The intensive exploitation of existing networks to promote and support the implementation of project activities in the framework of a sound and comprehensive promotion and dissemination plan helps guarantee a consistent and significant impact on a wide, relevant and varied audience.</objective>
  <title>SIMPLA - Sustainable Integrated Multi-sector PLAnning</title>
<identifier>H2020EE20153MarketUptake</identifier>
</project>
