<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212409</rcn>
  <acronym>FIT4FOOD2030</acronym>
  <objective>To support the European Commission in the development and implementation of the FOOD 2030 policy framework and its action plan, FIT4FOOD2030 aims to establish a sustainable multi-stakeholder, multi-level platform, mobilizing a wide variety of stakeholders at the level of cities, regions, countries, and Europe. Recognising the evolving nature of FOOD 2030, this Coordination and Support Action and its project structure should be flexible, responsive, inclusive, efficient, innovative, value-adding and supportive to the European Commission DG RTD FOOD 2030 initiative which is led by DG RTD Unit F3 Agri-Food Chain. The project will support the urgently needed transformation of research and innovation (R&amp;I) on food and nutrition security (FNS) by providing a network and instruments for the adoption of a food system and Responsible Research and Innovation approach to R&amp;I. For this purpose, FIT4FOOD2030 builds the 'FOOD2030 Platform' by developing three interlinked structures: 1) ‘EU think tank’ to act as linking pin between EC and Member States &amp; Associated Countries; 2) ‘Policy Labs’ to increase and align public/private R&amp;I policies/programs on FNS, building on and expanding existing national/regional networks; and 3) ‘City Labs’ to develop/pilot action-oriented trainings for students, consumers, researchers and professionals linking Science Centres/Science Shops to networks of Milan Urban Food Policy Pact cities. These structures interact regularly, exchanging information (e.g. on food system trends, R&amp;I policy frameworks, best practices, breakthroughs) and plan and execute actions to support FOOD 2030. A sustainable network is achieved by using a Community of Practice (CoP) approach to network governance. FIT4FOOD2030’s activities comprise four phases: 1) actor identification/mobilization and visioning/system analysis; 2) pathways development; 3) action planning and training; and 4) scaling up and continuity. Cross-cutting components are: methodology development and transformative learning. The activities will result in the following outcomes: 1) mobilizing a diversity of actors &amp; experts; 2) structuring and aligning R&amp;I policies and programs; 3) raising awareness; and 4) building competencies of students, researchers, entrepreneurs, policy-makers and society at large.</objective>
  <title>Fostering Integration and Transformation for FOOD 2030</title>
<identifier>H2020SFS20171</identifier>
</project>
