<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>199087</rcn>
  <acronym>TUTORIAL</acronym>
  <objective>The overall aim of the TUTORIAL project is to boost the scientific excellence and technology-transfer capacity in nanoelectronics based dependable cyber-physical systems (NBDCPS) of Tallinn University of Technology (TUT) by creating a network with the high-quality Twinning partners: Delft University of Technology (TU Delft), Politecnico di Torino (POLITO) and Deutsches Zentrum für Luft- und Raumfahrt (DLR). To achieve this aim, the 3 year project will build upon the existing strong research and innovation base of TUT and its Twinning partners. 

To boost their scientific excellence and technology transfer capacity in NBDCPS, the partners will implement a research and innovation strategy focused on three sub-topics: 

1. Reliable nanoelectronics technologies – TUT with TU Delft,
2. In-field test for safety-critical systems – TUT with POLITO, and
3. Dependable cyber-physical systems for space applications – TUT with DLR

The research and innovation strategy takes into account the recent SWOT analysis of TUT and has the following objectives: 

• Objective 1: Strengthen TUT’s research excellence in NBDCPS
• Objective 2: Enhance the research and innovation capacity of TUT and the Twinning partners 
• Objective 3: Raise the research profile of TUT and the Twinning Partners 
• Objective 4: Contribute to the SMART Specialisation Strategy of Estonia
• Objective 5: Support research and innovation on a European level 

In order to achieve these objectives, the consortium partners will implement a comprehensive set of measures via the project’s work packages: 

• Short term staff exchanges (WP1); 
• Training workshops, conferences and summer schools (WP2); 
• Dissemination and outreach (WP3).</objective>
  <title>Twinning to Strengthen Tallinn University of Technology’s Research and Innovation Capacity in Nanoelectronics Based Dependable Cyber-Physical Systems</title>
<identifier>H2020TWINN2015</identifier>
</project>
