<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>194909</rcn>
  <acronym>WEEVIL</acronym>
  <objective>L category vehicles should answer the demands for less energy consumption and affordability and represent an attractive solution in congested cities with scarce parking space. WEEVIL aims to develop a new L category 3-wheeler that is quiet, clean, energy efficient and safe, as well as attractive to the public so that the barriers for adopting it are minimized. 
The new vehicle concept is an ultralight and ultrasafe adaptable 3-wheeler, with a composite structure using new manufacturing processes for an affordable introduction of these materials in new vehicles. Modularity of elements (including battery packs), system integration and innovative vehicle architecture is considered in the vehicle design. The vehicle has a wheel width varying mechanism in order to allow adaptation to different speeds (wider at high speeds for stability, narrower at low speeds for space optimization and parking). 
WEEVIL will provide a new electric vehicle concept with innovative design to allow the user to adapt the vehicle to higher speeds or lower speeds and/or parking. Its characteristics will be lightness and safety, with a strong use of composite materials through new and affordable processing methods. A new drive-train with improved energy efficiency will be incorporated, as well as new solutions on system integration such as modular battery packs. 
WEEVIL solution will break the barriers for extended EV adoption in urban areas, i.e. vehicle capabilities and cost trade-off. A car-like comfort and driving experience in a reduced space (2-3 wheeler vehicle) is pursued. 
By providing a feasible concept adapted to the users’ expectations, the European EV car pool would be significantly enlarged, providing the pursued benefits on air quality, noise and environmental protection and also bringing traffic congestion reductions and a potential dominance of the European industry in this market.</objective>
  <title>Ultralight and ultrasafe adaptable 3-wheeler</title>
<identifier>H2020GV2014</identifier>
</project>
