<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>199211</rcn>
  <acronym>iSIM</acronym>
  <objective>The Space industry is on the verge a major revolution due to the advent of large constellations of small satellites (1-100 kg) providing fast, and low-cost access to space. However the traditional components &amp; systems suppliers are not being able to cope with these fast changes:
-	High Resolution Earth Observation cameras are still considered turn-key projects with prices and delivery times that are out of reach for most small satellites developers. 
-	In the last three years the number of small satellites launched has multiplied by 4. This has triggered a shortage of components and subsystems, and some suppliers have their production booked for years. 

iSIM is a patent pending high-resolution compact camera for Earth-Observation microsatellites, that provides very flexible sensing capabilities and on-board processing, for a fraction of the cost of today’s Earth Observation instruments. 
This novel product, result of a 3 year R&amp;D project started at the University of Florida, combines a straightforward design (patent pending), with advanced electronics, software, and advanced manufacturing standards from its conception.

SATLANTIS aims to capture around 10% of the micro and nanosatellite market with an expected turnover of 27 M€, becoming a leading player in the 50kg micro-satellite segment. It is a Spanish start-up technology company that designs, builds and operates microsatellites and payloads for Earth Observation. The founding team was completed by a group of high profile individuals with wide experience in the Science, Innovation and Engineering fields and a minority participation (5%) of Elecnor Deimos, a 3 B€ industrial group with a Space division that has developed and operated 2 Earth Observation satellites. The team is working on a 2 M€ financing round of which 1/3 is already committed.</objective>
  <title>Integrated Standard Imager for Earth Observation Microsatellites</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12015</identifier>
</project>
