<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>214779</rcn>
  <acronym>VIDA</acronym>
  <objective>Value-added Innovation in fooD chAins (VIDA) will nurture and harness the growth and innovation potential of SMEs working across European food chains, bringing together four complementary and mutually dependant sectors; food, energy, water and key enabling technologies (KET). VIDA will strengthen current and develop new cross-sectoral industrial value chains within the food production and processing industries through a combination of direct and indirect innovation actions, as well as support and capacity building measures. These will include open-innovation and virtual collaboration tools, mentoring and knowledge-sharing activities and a 'twin-track' innovation voucher scheme which will support the realisation of high-TRL, large-scale, demonstration and commercialisation projects across Europe. We will effect change among more than 6200 organisations, primarily SMEs.
VIDA combines expertise from four complementary European Strategic Cluster Partnerships (ESCPs): FoodPackLab, EU4Food, Energy in Water and AdPack, with a direct reach of over 700 SMEs across the partner clusters (and 2100 SMEs across the collaborating ESCPs). The collaborating partners have been carefully selected to ensure a complementary balance of geographies, knowledge, experience and expertise within VIDA's four sectors, and maximise the potential for cross-sectoral and cross-disciplinary exchanges to create new industrial value chains.
VIDA will operate for 3 years and has a total budget of €5.031.141, €4,044,776 of which will directly and benefit SMEs (&gt;81% of the total budget). €3,275,000 of the budget is targeted to provide specialist innovation vouchers, and catalyse large-scale demonstration with commercialisation innovation projects, with &gt;100 beneficiaries.</objective>
  <title>Value-added Innovation in fooD chAins</title>
<identifier>H2020INNOSUP012017twoStage</identifier>
</project>
