<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>204777</rcn>
  <acronym>ACTTiVAte</acronym>
  <objective>The overall concept of the project consist of supporting innovation in SMEs and fostering the smart reindustrialization of Europe by enabling the emergence of new cross-border and cross-sectoral value chains  resulting from the translation of advanced technologies among selected sectors with strong synergies. These new value chains will be created from the interaction of the following sectors: aerospace,agro-food sector, Health &amp; medical devices and ICT.
The project will take of 36Months. The development of the new value chains will be facilitated setting up geographical poles of activitiy in different regions across ES, PT,NL, IL and PL, comprising: Cluster/ SME intermediaries, which help create an appropriate innovation ecosystems;RTD centres. which are able to assess the potential and viability of the proposed new value chains for SMEs innovative services or products. Besides, a third kind of entity, theinnovation facilitatorswill operate at a cross-cluster level, organizing funding rounds to complement with private funds EU public support and establishing networks for collaboration. More than 50 letters of support signed by different type of stakeholders.
ACTTiVAte will undertake 2 kind of activities to optimize the benefits to SMEs:a)Direct funding of SMEs innovative projects. Competitive calls will be launched in the proposed technology areas.Thewining projects (50) will be selected and an overall amount of up to 46.000€/each SME from a total of a 1,5M€ from the project budget. The selection criteria will consider both the technical feasibility and viability and the socioeconomic impact. b)Activities aimed at creating a favourable environment for the innovation in those SMEs participating in projects selected in call for proposal processes, such as brokerage events, innovation services, open collaboration platforms, investor readiness trainings or guidance to set up coaching, training, mentoring, peer sharing, internationalization solutions, B2B matchmaking. The demonstration of the project at large scale will also be carried out during the project.</objective>
  <title>PAn-European Clusters for Technology Transfer and new VAlue chains</title>
<identifier>H2020INNOSUP20151</identifier>
</project>
