<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>193204</rcn>
  <acronym>DiscoverResearch</acronym>
  <objective>Ireland’s leading university, Trinity College Dublin (TCD), in partnership with the Royal College of Surgeons in Ireland (RCSI), is seeking funding to plan, promote and host Discover Research Night as part of European Researchers’ Night in 2014 and 2015. On Discover Research Night 26 September 2014 and 25 September 2015, TCD and RCSI will offer the general public a wide range of interactive and hands-on activities, providing direct contact with researchers and allowing for discovery, questions and participation. The objectives of the project are to challenge perceptions held by the general public about researchers, to promote research as an exciting career option, to demonstrate creativity and innovation in research across all disciplines and to show that researchers are dynamic contributors to society. Interaction with researchers during EU Researchers’ Night will challenge stereotypes which have created barriers between the general public and researchers. Specific career-focused events will identify and promote arrays of opportunities for research careers. Diverse activities which will help to show the public how research benefits the community. Events will showcase exciting innovative research from several academic strands at TCD and RCSI, will invite the public to interact with the vibrant research communities from both participating institutes, aiming to delight and stimulate the imagination of all participants from school children and their families, to visitors to Dublin and the local community. Activities hosted on the night will be grouped under four broad themes – Body Parts including ‘Discover the Brain!’, ‘Mending Broken Hearts, ‘Attack of the Heart’; Language, Thought &amp; Knowledge Transfer including ‘Identities in Transformation’, ‘Living Thought/Thinking Life’, ‘Tower of Babel’, Creativity in Research featuring ‘Biodiversity in our Lives’ and Meet the Researchers including ‘Thesis-in-3’, ‘Innovation Café’, ‘Women in Science’ and ‘Career Clinic’.</objective>
  <title>Discover Research Dublin - European Researchers' Night 2014/2015</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCANIGHT2014</identifier>
</project>
