<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>203571</rcn>
  <acronym>ProGeo</acronym>
  <objective>PLC System is an Italian medium company acting as a EPC and/or supplier for electrical plants/substations engineering and construction and as a IPP (independent power producer). The high technical and managerial capacity allowed to PLC to reach a consolidated position in the European energy sector, with a 2015 turnover of 35 M€ and a 85 figures staff, mainly composed by engineers and high level technicians. PLC is very active in the energy R&amp;D, with the clear scope to fabricate and install its own products to be offered in the very competitive energy market. Within this framework, PLC developed ProGeo, a 500 kW Power-to-Gas modular unit able to store electricity by converting carbon dioxide (CO2) into synthetic methane (CH4) with high flexibility thanks to fast start-ups and shut-downs. The patented product will be offered to owners and managers of small Thermoelectric Generation (s-TEG, &lt; 50 MWth) plants, who will have the possibility to store energy and avoid the sale of low-price electricity during low peak requirements (electricity market price &lt; 20-30 €/MWh) and to reduce the CO2 emissions and the consequent carbon tax amount (5 ÷ 20 €/ton of CO2), producing an additional revenue source from the synthetic-CH4 generation. 
ProGeo will provide customers with the following benefits:
• increasing of average electricity sale price = +25%
• reduction of CO2 emission and tax = -10%
• increasing of TEG plant EBITDA = up to 1 M€/y for a 20 MWel natural gas fuelled power plant
• ProGeo pay-back time = 3 ÷ 4.5 years
• reduced start-ups / shut-downs of the TEG
PLC has developed a pilot prototype of 30 kWel, by which the technology potentialities have been demonstrated, has identified a strategic partner (LAMEP, a company operating in the field of precision engineering) and has defined a business plan with the assessment of the minimum viable product (MVP), the production cost and market price, a preliminary industrialization and commercialization plan.</objective>
  <title>ProGeo</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST22015</identifier>
</project>
