<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211030</rcn>
  <acronym>MEET-CINCH</acronym>
  <objective>In order to maintain European nuclear operations, expertise in nuclear and radiochemistry (NRC) is of strategic relevance. Besides the obvious needs of NRC skills in the context of nuclear power and assessment of disposal options for nuclear waste there are many other applications. This includes radiologic diagnostics and therapy, unthinkable without radiopharmaceutical chemistry, dating in geology and archaeology, (nuclear) forensics and safeguard operations, radiation protection including radioecological assessments of releases and legacies and last but not least basic research e.g. on super heavy elements. The MEET-CINCH project will counteract the massive lack of NRC expertise by three actions. A teaching package for high schools and a MOOC on NRC for general public are built in order to attract young persons to the NRC field and convey them its fascination and relevance.  Two additional actions focus on vocational training and (university) education. MEET-CINCH will develop completely new education and training approaches based on remote teaching and the flipped classroom concept including and further developing material generated in the CINCH I and CINCH II projects, such as the NucWik platform and the remote controlled RoboLab experiments. MEET-CINCH will provide ECVET course modules in an e-Shop adapted to the needs of end-users which have been surveyed in the previous projects. After the end of MEET-CINCH the e-shop will be continuously operated by the NRC-network as part of a sustainable European Fission Training Scheme (EFTS). 
The consortium includes 13 partners from ten European member states; both academia and nuclear laboratories are represented. All partners are experienced in conducting training and education. Networking on national and European level will be an important part of the project, facilitated by having ENEN as one of the partners and by having structural links with other Euratom projects, the EuCheMS DNRC and the NRC-network.</objective>
  <title>A Modular European Education and Training Concept In Nuclear and RadioCHemistry</title>
<identifier>NFRP201620171</identifier>
</project>
