<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211623</rcn>
  <acronym>FibreNet</acronym>
  <objective>FibreNet will train young fibre-professionals having multidisciplinary view to develop sustainable bio-based fibre products with tailored properties for different application fields in both academic and non-academic sectors. Bio-based fibre products are one of the corner-stones in the European bio-based industry corresponding to 12% of the employment in manufacturing. The industry, including such sectors as packaging, paper, biocomposites and biomedical and hygienic textiles, is currently undergoing a fundamental transformation in order to respond to the competition raised i) by low-wage countries and ii) by fossil-based materials. A common consensus in Europe is that to remain competitive and sustain the bio-based fibre industries in Europe, we should focus on developing new high added value products that have specific functionalities but reduced environmental impacts.

In fibre-based products, developing new properties and improving the performance are, however, typically long and time-consuming processes. They usually involve massive and expensive laboratory and pilot-scale trials, which are followed by statistical analyses. There is a particular knowledge gap in understanding the influence of fibre and fibre interface properties on the mechanical properties of the end-product especially when developing products with tailored performance and functionalities. In addition to the research gap, there is a training gap in Europe, as we do not currently have a training programme which would educate professionals having a skill set needed for the fibre-centered approach that we propose in FibreNet.

To fill the research and training gaps, we propose here a unique training and research network which provides and further develops knowhow, methods and tools in functionalization, characterization, numerical modelling and production of bio-based fibre products at multiple length scales. The network covers expertise on packaging, paper, biocomposites and biomedical textiles.</objective>
  <title>A Training Network on Designing Novel Bio-based Fibre Products for Targeted Advanced Properties and New Applications</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAITN2017</identifier>
</project>
