<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>198533</rcn>
  <acronym>THUNDHUB</acronym>
  <objective>The objective of ThunderMaps’ HomeHub Horizon 2020 project is to develop a city-level communication platform that enables all public authorities in a city to make geo-targeted (personalized) mobile communication with citizens - making information &amp; services easier to access &amp; use.
Our technology sits at the intersection of GIS (mapping) software, process improvement software (smart process apps), and the dual forces of mobile and social communication.
This project takes synergies between these technologies and uses them to solve significant challenges which exist today for public authorities, including: presenting a unified ‘one face of government’ to citizens; offering a personalized user experience; increasing citizen engagement; increasing transparency, reducing communication costs &amp; environmental impact.
The HomeHub solution is a scalable - easily replicable &amp; easily deployed – SaaS solution, and it is globally relevant. The market for ‘smart city solutions’ like ours is strong. Independent analysts project it to grow to US$27.5 billion annually by 2023.
The expected impact of our project is significant in numerous dimensions, including: direct and downstream benefits for public authorities, businesses, and citizens; growth of the company and new job opportunities; strong likelihood of private investment to scale the business further; and the growth of this project beyond Europe.
Our experienced and passionate team, along with our project partners – who include eGovLab, Sweden’s Technical Research Institute (SP), Microsoft, and Smart Cities Council, will ensure the maximum success in the development and launch of this solution.
The end result of ThunderMaps’ HomeHub Horizon 2020 project will be a world-leading mobile-focused communication platform for cities, and a fast-growing, globally-scalable company with a sustainable, recurring revenue-based business. We’ll be well on the way to improving the relationship between citizens, business &amp; public administrations</objective>
  <title>ThunderMaps HomeHub</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST22015</identifier>
</project>
