<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211939</rcn>
  <acronym>STEVE</acronym>
  <objective>Movement is at the heart of any city. Urban mobility faces significant challenges from two global megatrends: growing urbanisation and ageing population. Light electric vehicles (EL-Vs) could represent a viable solution to traffic congestion and pollution in cities. However, their successful integration into the urban transport system requires a clear understanding of the individual consumer needs.
By involving human science and transportation specialists, the STEVE partners have developed a framework to interpret these forces. Focus will be on mature cities of medium size (Torino: 800.000 inhabitants, Villach 60.000, Calvià 60.000, Venaria 35.000), where STEVE will generate data to support the design of next generation EL Vs, and provoke the mind-shift necessary for swift market penetration of them.

The primary idea of STEVE is to implement and test a human-centric approach to electro-Mobility-as-a-Service (eMaaS), according to the “Move2Me” vision of the consortium. This will provide low-cost and financially sustainable EL V solutions and “gamified” services, to enhance users’ awareness, engagement and vehicle energy efficiency.
A core item of STEVE is a low-cost electric quadricycle developed by a worldwide OEM in Turin, with start-of-production expected in 2018 at a market price of €8000. The quadricycle will integrate high-technology contents with respect to the current competitors, and will be pilot-tested, together with many other EL-Vs, during extensive demonstration phases in the four STEVE cities
STEVE will guarantee a strong impact in terms of business development and jobs, and enhance the European competitiveness in the eMaaS sector while also leveraging Manufacturing.

The consortium will also give a primary role to SMEs: while large enterprises will provide the underlying technologies, the services will be mainly designed and operated by SMEs, deeply involved in the local supply chains and adaptable to the specific customers’ needs.</objective>
  <title>Smart-Taylored L-category Electric Vehicle demonstration in hEtherogeneous urbanuse-cases</title>
<identifier>H2020GV2017</identifier>
</project>
