<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>202616</rcn>
  <acronym>EMS UHPE</acronym>
  <objective>Our consortium is applying for the Engine Mounts System (EMS) of the Ultra High Propulsive Efficiency. Our 3 objectives are:
1. Assist the Engine Manufacturer &amp; the Airframer in the evaluation &amp; selection of the most promising &amp; suitable Engine Mounts System (EMS) configuration. Criteria for evaluation: weight, cost, dynamic performance, certification, impact on engine &amp; aircraft assembly.
2. Design, build, &amp; test the selected concept for the Ground Test (GT) that is planned to validate study predictions &amp; performances. Our intent is to develop solutions &amp; technologies to minimize weight, reduce manufacturing process complexity, improve system dynamic performance, increase reliability, &amp; provide continuous monitoring of system health &amp; usage &amp; measure in-flight EMS conditions &amp; loads. The plan includes new solutions &amp; technologies with a min. TRL 4 at CDR in order to advance to TRL 5, 6 at GT incl. EMS overall configuration validation &amp; component optimization.
3. To develop &amp; insert new solutions for ground test with lower TRL’s than 4 at CDR as parallel activities. These lower TRL solutions selected on their potential to provide a significant leap in the performance, manufacturing, &amp; assembly.
Our consortium consists of
1. international company with global reach &amp; renown experience in the EMS industry, LORD Corp
2. a German SME, excelling in manufacturing of aerospace structures, HEGGEMANN
3. an Italian consulting SME in the field of structural mechanics, Vicoter
4. an Italian University, one of the leading science &amp; technology universities in Europe, Politecnico di Milano
This consortium set up a Work Plan starting in 3Q 2015 for a duration of 72 months, which is divided into 7 Work Packages, :
• WP1: Management &amp; reporting 
• WP2: Concept Studies &amp; EMS Specification definition 
• WP3: GT Design &amp; Development 
• WP4: GT Manufacturing &amp; Delivery 
• WP5: GT Qualification &amp; Testing 
• WP6: Support for Engine GT 
• WP7: Innovation &amp; new Technologies development</objective>
  <title>Engine Mount System for Ultra High Pass Engine</title>
<identifier>H2020CS2CFP01201401</identifier>
</project>
