<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210426</rcn>
  <acronym>UNIGEM</acronym>
  <objective>The proposed innovation project aims to deploy HSTech’s next generation disruptive ‘Unified Guest Engagement System’ (UNIGEM) that relies on the company’s proven and award winning cloud-based guest engagement platform: ‘m-hospitality’ which demonstrates outstanding results by generating increased revenue for hotels, improved guest satisfaction, optimized operations, enhanced brand image and loyalty, and improved quality of customer service. As such, UNIGEM introduces a new paradigm in the travel sector by expanding and automating the operation of local business ecosystems in hospitality and tourism sector. Ultimately, the proposed solution challenges the dominance of Online Travel Agents (OTAs) by interconnecting hotels and Tourism Service Providers (TSPs) under a federated loyalty programme, creating this way a single point of access for guest bookings. UNIGEM uses big data technology to integrate hotel and TSPs data, and data from their interaction with guests. Through its advanced analytics engine it extrapolates on personal tastes and needs and through real-time data evaluation, it enables guests to enjoy individualized experiences leading this way the hospitality industry from personalization to individualization. UNIGEM will stimulate an ecosystem-oriented symbiotic business culture between hotels &amp; TSPs, driven by quantified economic benefits. Guests will also enjoy fulfilling experiences through effortless interaction with service providers, while winning rewards from service consumption. In addition, UNIGEM will increase employment opportunities in local communities and promote the cultural uniqueness of each destination. By investing in UNIGEM HSTech expects an NPV ranging from 15M€ to 35M€ &amp; IRR from 31% to 85% (worst-case and baseline scenario respectively) over a 5 year period. Phase 1 will last 6 months to address 5 specific aspects of the overall feasibility. A leading research institute &amp; a specialized consultancy participate in P1 as subcontractors.</objective>
  <title>Next Generation ‘Unified Guest Engagement System’ for Smart Hospitality Services and Unparalleled Guest Loyalty.</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
