<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206408</rcn>
  <acronym>PJ19 CI</acronym>
  <objective>SESAR 2020 Programme aims to modernise and harmonise the European ATM System from operational and technological perspective. It will develop and validate different ATM solutions that will contribute to achieving its high level performance objectives. In this complex context, it is crucial to have a transversal activity that generates a consolidated big picture of the future European ATM System – the SESAR 2020 Concept of Operations, the High Level Architecture options, Services and the associated performance results. In SESAR2020 this important task will be under the responsibility of PJ19 – Content Integration.
The other main task of the PJ19 will be to provide steering guidance, principles and frameworks to support and facilitate the production and the integration of the content produced by SESAR2020 Solution and Enabling projects. It will enable the assessment of the overall performance of the SESAR Solutions brought together against the performance improvements expectations. It will provide the main input for the future updates of the European ATM Master Plan.
PJ19 will bring together 16 partners. The broad representation of experts from the European Air Navigation Service Providers, Airports, Airborne and Ground industries and Network Manager will provide the necessary skills to successfully and efficiently carry out the project tasks and to meet the expectations of the SJU.
PJ19 will produce a set of deliverables that consolidate the SESAR2020 Programme outcomes and provide an integrated reference material on a yearly basis. All these tasks will be performed in collaboration with all SESAR 2020 projects throughout an interactive, continuous and iterative process on all aspects of content integration.
PJ19 deliverables will support the SJU to assess the maturity of the SESAR Solutions for delivery to the SESAR Deployment Manager, to monitor the SESAR2020 Programme execution and to support the SJU decision making.</objective>
  <title>Content Integration</title>
<identifier>H2020SESAR20152</identifier>
</project>
