<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>197415</rcn>
  <acronym>VISUM</acronym>
  <objective>VISUM is applying to NMP 25 – 2014/2015: Accelerating the uptake of nanotechnologies, advanced materials or advanced manufacturing and processing technologies by SMEs, to develop and take to market by 2017 an IR-spectroscopy-based platform for the rapid, easy integration and customisation of real-time monitoring systems for the food and pharmaceutical industries for improved process control, product quality and safety.

NIR is a non-destructive, reliable and accurate technique for monitoring chemical and physical parameters during food and pharmaceutical processing. At present, NIR is widely accepted as one of the most promising on/in-line process control techniques. Moreover, the appearance of fiberoptic probes significantly improves the ability of NIR techniques to monitor and control processes especially using remote on/in line detection. However, there are currently gaps preventing the mainstreaming of NIR in the industry: 1) typical NIR lab analysers are expensive; 2) they often require time-consuming, costly and complex predictive models development and their further recalibration; 3) Generic systems do not properly fit to each particular product line or monitoring challenge and these mismatches are the source of major errors; 4) on-line NIR optical interfaces are prone to biofouling and contamination which is a major limitation for accurate measurements and leads to high maintenance requirements. 

The VISUM platform is designed to overcome each of these limitations and thereby contribute to the mainstreaming of NIR-based technology in the European and global food and pharmaceutical industries as an enabler for improved product quality and safety, as well as improved process understanding and control for a first tier Process Analytical Technology (PAT) tool. The VISUM platform will developing the necessary flexible hardware and software to allow for a rapid, easy, and cost-effective integration that can be performed by non-specialised engineers.</objective>
  <title>An IR-spectroscopy-based platform for the rapid integration and customisation of affordable, real-time monitoring solutions for the food and pharmaceutical industry</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12015</identifier>
</project>
