<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>195886</rcn>
  <acronym>MWGRAV</acronym>
  <objective>After  more  than  20  years  of  fundamental  research,  atom  interferometers  have  reached  sensitivity  and 
accuracy  levels  competing  with  or  beating  inertial  sensors  based  on  different  technologies.  Atom 
interferometers  offer  interesting  applications  in  geophysics,  inertial  sensing,  metrology  and  tests  of 
fundamental physics. Recently,  a growing interest of the application of atom interferometry to gravitational 
wave detection and geophysics has  been drawn. These applications beyond the pure scope of atomic physics 
require the development of more performant  atomic  inertial  sensors, particularly for the use of  matter-wave 
interferometers  in gravitational wave detectors,  where  sensitivity  levels  far beyond the  state of the art must 
be demonstrated. The proposed project aims at contributing filling this gap by studying new atom and optical 
interferometry  techniques,  in  order  to  significantly  improve  the  performances  of  matter -wave  gravitation 
sensors. 
The  proposed  MSC  action  will  significantly  impact  the  design  of  a  new  class  of  matter-wave  gravitation 
sensors, which are under study in several countries in the world. In the excellence metrology environment of 
SYRTE,  the  MSC  applicant  will  foster  challenging  developments  in  atom  interferometers,  with  a  high 
impact on the communities of atomic physics, geophysics and gravitational wave detection.  On this path, the 
Experienced  Researcher  will  benefit  from  an  original  and  efficient  training  by  the  host  group  through 
knowledge  transfer,  acquisition  of  new  scientific  and  management  skills,  enlargement  of  her  professional 
network and development of her track record.</objective>
  <title>High Sensitivity Matter-Wave Gravitation Sensors</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAIF2014</identifier>
</project>
