<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205955</rcn>
  <acronym>LINCOLN</acronym>
  <objective>LINCOLN presents three new concepts of added-value specialized vessels able to run requested services for several maritime sectors in the most effective, efficient, economic valuable and eco-friendly way. LINCOLN will develop three types of completely new vessels concepts at TRL5, through dynamic simulation model testing. The first is a Multi-platform Catamaran to serve as: Service crew vessel and Multipurpose survey vessel, optimized for Ocean energy and Aquaculture. It will develop a new people transfer system, able to improve safety during people transfer, it will have reduced operations costs and will be eco-friendly. The second is a Module Based High Speed Patrol Boat Platform, that is reconfigurable to adapt to the different operational requirements of Patrol and Security operators. Here LINCOLN will develop one platform, where different vessels can be designed for several markets, built as series production at low cost and it will enable the new “Vessel as a Service” business model. The third one is an Emergency Response and Recovery Vessels series for Coastal Rescue activities, with integrated electronics, IoT connectivity and an enhanced and low cost Integrated Dynamic Position System, which will help rescue operators during their activities and enhancing safety and security. All the three vessels will share the same design methodology. In fact, LINCOLN will be also a success story for the use of innovative design methodologies and tools in the marine sector. It will use: a lean fact based design model approach, which combines real operative data at sea with lean methodology, to support the development and implementation of the vessel concepts; IT customized tools to enable the acquisition and usage of field data, coming from an IoT platform; High Performance Computing Simulation. This new design approach will be demonstrated with the three vessels designed and delivered in the project and disseminated to bring back EU yards to the edge of innovation.</objective>
  <title>Lean innovative connected vessels</title>
<identifier>H2020BG20161</identifier>
</project>
