<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>207434</rcn>
  <acronym>INSTRUCT-ULTRA</acronym>
  <objective>Instruct-Ultra aims to advance the scope and efficiency of implementation of Instruct and consolidate the foundations for long-term sustainability. This will be achieved through specific objectives: expand Instruct membership to new Member States and increase global links; engage new user communities; improve efficiencies in service delivery; improve data capture and management; adjust the scale and reliability of the infrastructure. Instruct-Ultra will deliver these alongside the transition to ERIC legal status and rapid developments in, and increased demand for, integrated structural biology infrastructure. These advances in the scale and speed of delivery will earn further trust within the life science community. One focus will to expand membership to Eastern European states and EFTA countries, integrating their structural biology communities into Instruct and providing new opportunities to support research excellence and raise standards. Opportunities for engaging with industrialised and developing countries outside the ERA will build on existing cooperative work between Instruct and Asian, African and South American countries to establish strong bilateral programmes of benefit to both parties, giving Instruct better engagement in emerging global challenges and positioning Instruct as a trusted global resource for high quality structural biology services. Starting from baseline operations four years ago Instruct has now identified key areas of service which should be expanded, new potential user groups, and opportunities for more reliable, efficient and sometimes remotely used workflows. Instruct-Ultra will therefore test new modes of access and pilot new service methods in high demand areas to accelerate access for more users. Instruct-Ultra will reinforce Instruct operations by updating and expanding the business plan and structural biology roadmap, whilst improving the interface with academia and industry as a strategy to sustainability.</objective>
  <title>Releasing the full potential of Instruct to expand and consolidate infrastructure services for integrated structural life science research</title>
<identifier>H2020INFRADEV20161</identifier>
</project>
