<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>199597</rcn>
  <acronym>INCOBRA</acronym>
  <objective>INCOBRA – Increasing Science, Technology and Innovation (STI) International Cooperation between Brazil (BR) and the European Union (EU) – is a 36-month Coordination and Support Action aiming to increase, enhance and focus Research and Innovation (R&amp;I) cooperation between BR and EU.
INCOBRA is expected to contribute to (i) Increased cooperation patterns – by supporting cooperation networks among BR and EU R&amp;I actors (Work Package –WP2), (ii) Enhanced framework conditions – by fostering coordination and alignment of R&amp;I funding in BR and EU (WP3), (iii) More focused BR-EU R&amp;I cooperation – by identifying emerging topics and opportunities in priority R&amp;I areas for cooperation (WP1). Capacity building, sustainability will also be fully addressed by INCOBRA (WP4 and WP5, respectively).
INCOBRA’s approach is completely aligned with the EU Strategy for International R&amp;I Cooperation, the EU Roadmap for R&amp;I Cooperation with BR, the BR-EU Policy Dialogue priorities and with the work of the Strategic Forum for International STI Cooperation (SFIC). It thus draws upon a multilateral perspective (interests and needs of BR-state level, BR-federal level, EU and EU-Member States), whilst capitalizing and going beyond the outcomes of the previous R&amp;I cooperation project with Brazil (B.BICE+). INCOBRA’s approach also assumes innovation (holistic concept) as a key driver for BR-EU STI cooperation and Strategic Foresight as a relevant tool to anticipate R&amp;I trends of mutual interest for BR and EU R&amp;I actors, while promoting mutual openness of BR and EU R&amp;I funding programmes to encourage cooperation.
The INCOBRA consortium comprises 13 partners (7 from EU and 6 from BR), including Universities, Research Organizations, International Organizations, Technology Parks, Private Companies and Funding Agencies. Building upon a stakeholder-driven basis, INCOBRA already incorporates 36 organizations as members of the Stakeholder Group to be deployed during the project.</objective>
  <title>Increasing INternational Science, Technology and Innovation COoperation between BRAzil and the European Union</title>
<identifier>H2020INTINCO2015</identifier>
</project>
