<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>205923</rcn>
  <acronym>POWDERBLADE</acronym>
  <objective>POWDERBLADE aims to gain market acceptance and rapid market take up of an innovative materials technology involving
carbon/glass fibres in powder epoxy to be commercialised initially in the production of larger wind turbine blades (60 metre
+). The immediate impact of this disruptive materials technology in the wind energy sector will be reduced wind turbine cost
(-20%). This in turn will lead to increased productivity of low-carbon energy from more rapid market deployment of large
turbines. The reduction in costs and increase in productivity will reduce the Levelised Cost of Electricity (LCOE) for the
European citizen – the ultimate beneficiary of this innovation.
This ambitious project is led by Éire Composites, an established industry player in composites manufacturing for the
Aerospace and Renewable sectors and an experienced FP7/Horizon 2020 participant.In the year after project end,
ÉireComposites will generate over €7m in revenue from direct sales of larger blade components using the new materials,
increasing to €39m by 2021. The longer term commercial strategy is to focus on recurring revenues from the supply of
advanced materials directly to manufacturers to produce blades and other products under license. This revenue stream will
generate €60m by 2021. ÉireComposites will employ an additional 78 staff in direct production at project end increasing to
489 employees over both revenue streams three years later.
Suzlon, a large wind OEM and end user, is the second industry partner. Their involvement demonstrates early market
acceptance of the new technology. Suzlon are committed to investing substantial funds in the commercialisation of this
technology in return for the opportunity to gain significantly as the first large industry player to market with light, cost-effective
carbon-glass hybrid blades. Technology partner (University of Edinburgh) and innovation specialists (WestBIC) will support
the industry partners in achieving the goals of POWDERBLADE.</objective>
  <title>Commercialisation of Advanced Composite Material Technology: Carbon-Glass Hybrid in PowderEpoxy for Large (60-100m) Wind Turbine Blades</title>
<identifier>H2020FTIPilot20161</identifier>
</project>
