<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206084</rcn>
  <acronym>CA-RES3</acronym>
  <objective>The Concerted Action will support the implementation of the renewable energy directive 2009/28/EC. As with the first and second phase, the objectives of CA-RES3 are directly linked to the transposition and implementation of the RES Directive. The third phase of the CA-RES will also provide further opportunities to explore possibilities for common approaches in specific areas of implementation of the RES Directive. The CA-RES3 will achieve the objectives stated above through a series of six plenary meetings for discussion on the various topics. These meetings will provide a confidential forum for structured discussions and cross-learning between participating countries. This exchange concentrates on key requirements of the RES Directive according to the needs of the participating countries as well as the European Commission. As such, it will contribute to the achievement of the national RES targets set by the Directive. The CA-RES3 will emphasize topics that require common approaches and/or benefit from good practice exchange between participating countries. The CA-RES3 Core Themes will address a number of aspects including support schemes for electricity and heat, integrating RES into electricity networks, the use of RES for heating and cooling and in buildings, disclosure/guarantees of origin, biomass mobilisation and sustainability as well as the use of RES in transport. The confidential character of the CA-RES3 allows participating countries to discuss in confidence how to best implement the RES Directive. Thus, the need for confidentiality will be emphasized towards all participating institutions, and confidentiality agreements will be signed by all participants.</objective>
  <title>Concerted Action supporting the transposition and implementation of Directive 2009/28/EC on the promotion of the use of energy from renewable sources (RES Directive)</title>
<identifier>H2020Adhoc201420</identifier>
</project>
