<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210403</rcn>
  <acronym>pHenom</acronym>
  <objective>The objective of the pHenom project is to produce the next generation pH sensor capable of accurate, calibration free and
smart operation, with integral quality and control. Development and commercialisation of this smart sensor, named the
“pHenom” will provide a revolutionary pH sensor that meets the ocean monitoring and water management needs. Beyond
the ocean monitoring and water management industries, the global pH meter market is expected to reach nearly £1.48 bn by
2022. The pH meter market is segmented into bench top (55% share - £815m), portable, and continuous pH meters. pHims
technology can deliver to all three and has the potential to meet a wide range of needs within the segments; pharmaceuticals
and biotechnology, food science (41% share), water and waste treatment, research institutes and environmental control
boards. Despite US dominance, in 2014, Europe was the highest revenue generating region at 32% due to the high level of
R&amp;D activities, advanced healthcare, and industrial infrastructure. Drivers are new technology (microprocessors for auto
temperature and pressure compensation), growing health concerns and regulatory pressure to monitor environmental
pollution (waste water pH in industries such as chemicals, pharmaceuticals, food processing) and the need to regulate pH
levels (routine testing of soil, water, food, beverage, and dairy products). The objective of this feasibility study is to carry out
activities that enable the provision of a comprehensive feasibility report with conclusions, recommendations and a
specification of the Phase 2 project objectives, together with a detailed marketing and business plan for the development
and commercialisation of pHims.</objective>
  <title>A cost effective, smart, calibration free, low maintenance pH sensor providing an integrated approach to monitoring sea and drinking water, facilitating improvements in ocean, animal and human health.</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
