<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196631</rcn>
  <acronym>DRAGON-STAR Plus</acronym>
  <objective>China is already an important global actor in the fields of research and innovation, and has the potential of becoming a leading force in the next few decades. The shift in China’s strategy focusing towards R&amp;I and transforming the essence of its economy has been complimented with massive public investments in research and technology. The EU having recognised the leading role China is expected to play, and having adopted a strategic position for becoming a knowledge-based economy, is required to collaborate with China in areas of mutual interest, and for common benefit and prosperity. Moreover for critical global issues which demand close scientific and technological cooperation at an international level, EU has identified in China a natural partner able to contribute and complement its own capacity.
The proposed initiative aims to provide support services to European and Chinese researchers, and a flexible platform to facilitate policy discussions between European and Chinese stakeholders. Moreover, DRAGON-STARPLUS will provide the EC and the Member States with a toolset for setting a long term cooperation strategy in research and innovation with China.  
The project aims to provide efficient services on three levels (priority areas): 
- Support the European and Chinese research communities to establish collaborations under Horizon 2020 and beyond. 
-Provide a cooperation platform and tools to policy makers, aiming ultimately to support and enhance the bilateral cooperation, through the concept of mutual benefit.
-Provide an ERA-NET style platform to funding agencies for exchanging best practices and planning joint activities.
The proposed activities take into account the current on-going policy dialogue and the peculiarities of the research and innovation environment in China, and are based upon the outputs and the established mechanisms of the previous DRAGON-STAR project, as well as upon the sound results of previous related projects (e.g. OPEN-ICT, CO-REACH).</objective>
  <title>Dragon - Sustaining Technology And Research Plus (EU-China Collaboration)</title>
<identifier>H2020INTINCO2014</identifier>
</project>
