<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>198248</rcn>
  <acronym>ERBSN 4 H2020</acronym>
  <objective>ERBSN 4 H2020 is a 4-partner partnership covering Macroregion 2 (RO2) in Romania with the objective is to address the topic of H2020 Work Programme 2014-2015 ERBSN 4 H2020 «Establishing services for enhancing the innovation management capacity of SMEs in the Enterprise Europe Network». In this view ERBSN 4 H2020 will develop a viable macroregional network of 9 innovation experts, of which 3 Key Account Managers, all staff of 3 ERBSN-EEN centres, able to deliver the two innovation services proposed by H2020, namely „Key account management under SME Instrument of Horizon 2020” and „Services to enhance the innovation management capacities of SMEs” in the targeted Romanian Macroregion 2. 
The Key account management (KAM) services will be delivered to 4 SMEs benefiting of SMEs Instrument under H2020 and support them receiving the most appropriate services which will enhance the probability of a successful exploitation of their financed innovation projects over the first two SMEs Instrument phases, while posting them for further EEN services not covered financially by H2020, for phase 3. The services to enhance the innovation management capacities of SMEs with significant innovation activities and potential for international growth will be delivered to 55 SMEs, both identified under a thorough analysis of the RO2 innovative businesses, and among the unfinanced successful RO2 SMEs under the SMEs Instrument. 
To achieve its specific objective, ERBSN shall apply and extend a strategy of building its capacity for delivering H2020 services in the first months of implementation and apply KAM and EIMC imposed delivery procedures based on the deep knowledge of the Romanian business and innovation culture.</objective>
  <title>Eastern Romanian Business Support Network support for innovative SMEs</title>
<identifier>H2020Adhoc201420</identifier>
</project>
