<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>199201</rcn>
  <acronym>NANOGUARD2AR</acronym>
  <objective>The overall project idea is on contribution to European culture and creativity through developing technological readiness of the breakthrough engineering solution for indoor air safeguard via inter-sectoral European and international cooperation, knowledge sharing, broad skills development and mobility of researchers and innovation staff. 
Under NANOGUARD2AR it is expected to build new and enhance existing network of international and inter-sectoral cooperation in the form of joint research and innovation activities between the project Partners with multidisciplinary skills and complementary competences in nanomaterials, physics, civil engineering, chemical engineering, green chemistry, microbiology, environmental protection, indoor air quality control and safety. It will significantly strengthen the interaction between academic and non-academic sectors within MS/AC Countries France, Portugal, Spain, Ukraine and Third Country the Republic of Belarus in the field of the innovative nanomaterials engineering application for the environmental protection.
The main objectives of the NANOGUARD2AR project are to develop and design, test, validate and demonstrate an innovative nanomaterials-based “microbial free” engineering solutions and responsive system [NANOGUARD2AR system] for the indoor air safeguard to support concept of green buildings. 
To achieve this goal the NANOGUARD2AR project will explore the use of nanomaterials (NMs) as photosensitizers coupled with advanced air-curtains technology and innovative interactive dark operating oxidizing composite materials being able to generate adsorbed hydroxyl radicals without any external energetic excitation. The emphasis of the project activities is on the proof of the concept of the innovative nanomaterials-enhanced air-barrier engineering solution towards efficient and sustainable protection of the indoor environment from microbial contaminations (fungus, fungal propagules, bacteria, their spores and germination).</objective>
  <title>NANOMATERIALS-BASED INNOVATIVE ENGINEERING SOLUTION TO ENSURE SUSTAINABLE SAFEGUARD TO INDOOR AIR</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCARISE2015</identifier>
</project>
