<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206407</rcn>
  <acronym>ERA-MIN 2</acronym>
  <objective>Building on the experience of ERA-MIN FP7 funded project, the objective of the ERA-NET Cofund on Raw Materials (ERA-MIN 2) is to strengthen the coordination of national and regional research programmes in the field of non-energy non-agricultural raw materials by implementing one joint call for proposals resulting in grants to third parties with EU co-funding.
In line with the integrated strategy proposed in the EU Raw Materials Initiative and the Strategic Implementation Plan of the European Innovation Partnership on Raw Materials, the ERA-MIN 2 Call topics will address the three segments of the non‐energy non-agricultural raw materials: metallic, industrial and construction minerals and will cover the whole value chain: exploration, extraction, processing/refining, as well as recycling and substitution of critical raw materials. 
ERA-MIN 2 supports the objectives of the EIP on Raw Materials, particularly in the area of research and innovation co-ordination; improve synergy, co-ordination and coherence between regional, national and EU funding in the relevant research fields through international collaboration; reduce fragmentation of raw materials research and innovation efforts across Europe; improve use of human and financial resources in the area of raw materials research and innovation.
As measures to maximise impact, ERA-MIN 2 will cooperate with the existing initiatives, projects and associations, by establishing an effective communication aiming to assure that all dissemination activities, including the promotion and follow up of project results, will reach out to a wider audience of stakeholders, therefore strengthening the raw material community.
To further increase its impact and to better fulfil the overarching objectives, ERA-MIN-2 will develop and implement at least two additional joint calls without EU co-funding, in topics of common interest and based on the updated Roadmap provided by CSA VERAM.</objective>
  <title>Implement a European-wide coordination of research and innovation programs on raw materials to strengthen the industry competitiveness and the shift to a circular economy</title>
<identifier>H2020SC52016OneStageB</identifier>
</project>
