<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>209162</rcn>
  <acronym>&lt;IMPACT&gt; Connected Car</acronym>
  <objective>"&lt;IMPACT&gt; Connected Car will fund 2 European Superstars and 64 Disruptive SMEs in the Connected Car OpenSpace by 5 European Cluster and 2 global ecosystems with the support of 10 Global Corporations and 4 pioneering startups.
An acceleration and smartization virtuous cycle methodology in the OpenSpace with vehicle, infrastructure and device &amp; TelCo interactions and consumer &amp; business services across 6 industrial value chains (Mobility, Automotive, Electronics, ICT, Services and Infrastructure) will lead to Value Link-Chains.
The &lt;IMPACT&gt; Connected Car consortium consists of CTAG, Mov´eo, INSERO, MSAK and LPMT as Gold+ clusters and PSA Citröen, Ferrovial and FIWARE Foundation (Telefonica, Orange and Atos) as Corporations; Mobile World Capital as the world´s best digital event out of Barcelona; ISDI as the world´s first native digital Business School; and FundingBox as the European leading platform for SMEs funding will guarantee excellent implementation. FIA Region 1 out of Brussels leverages the OpenSpace to a LivingLab with 112 Mobility Clubs and 38 Million of drivers.
Argus, Hevo, Botcar and Little are the pioneering connected car startups that will collaborate in the disruption discovery process.
PARP, the Polish Agency for SME Development and 19 regional ecosystems will ensure the Connected Car OpenSpace is aligned with ESIF and Smart Specialization to guarantee sustainability across the territories.
Beyond the 4 million euro support for the SMEs within the project, &lt;IMPACT&gt; Connected Car will seek private funding of 4 million euros and 1 million euros of mobilized ESIF. For this purpose, the “&lt;IMPACT&gt; Connected Car Label” will be instrumental. 
&lt;IMPACT&gt; Connected Car will demonstrate that public clusterization and disruption discovery with key Innovation actors (SMEs) and proper corporate engagement develops Emerging Industries and builds the EU of ""entrepreneurial states”."</objective>
  <title>Impacting on the Emerging Connected Car VaLuE Chains</title>
<identifier>H2020INNOSUP012016twoStage</identifier>
</project>
