<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>204474</rcn>
  <acronym>CIVITAS ECCENTRIC</acronym>
  <objective>The cities of Madrid, Stockholm, Munich, Turku and Ruse have formed the CIVITAS ECCENTRIC consortium to tackle the challenges of mobility in suburban districts and clean, silent and CO2 free city logistics. In many cities, these two important areas have received less attention in urban mobility policies.

Though European cities have made significant steps forward in making city centres attractive and liveable urban nodes, there is a remaining conflict between providing high quality public space and meeting the accessibility requirements for freight deliveries. The suburban areas have remained largely unaddressed with a much higher car usage as a consequence. Recent or expected urban growth processes are posing additional pressure to peri-central areas, which face the specific challenges of:

• Becoming sufficiently appealing to avoid an unnecessary traffic flow towards to the city centre; 
• Providing sustainable and high quality mobility options to enable and encourage car independent lifestyles; and
• Planning the urban future according to carbon neutral mobility principles.

ECCENTRIC will demonstrate and test the potential and replicability of integrated and inclusive urban planning approaches, innovative policies and emerging technologies to reach sustainable urban mobility objectives. The solutions will be implemented in 5 living laboratory areas in the outskirts that face high population growth and an increasing pressure on the existing transport networks. 

As highlighted in the SUMPs of the ECCENTRIC cities, this action on a wider geographical scale than the city centre is needed in order to meet the targets of the Transport White Paper in terms of air quality, energy use and CO2 emissions, road casualties and wide uptake of clean vehicles.

To reach CO2 free city logistics by 2030, ECCENTRIC will test clean vehicles and fuels, formulate new regulations and services and develop consolidation solutions in close partnerships with the private sector.</objective>
  <title>Innovative solutions for sustainable mobility of people in suburban city districts and emission free freight logistics in urban centres.</title>
<identifier>H2020MG2015TwoStages</identifier>
</project>
