<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210335</rcn>
  <acronym>WorldlyMatter</acronym>
  <objective>The aim of this project is to re-evaluate established narratives of Conceptual Art in North America and Western Europe and their global context. It will examine the importance of materiality and subject matter – or “worldly matters”, to borrow Conceptual artist Douglas Huebler’s term – for Conceptual Art in the 1960s and early 1970s. Engaging with theories of conservation as well as the most recent discourses around materiality, the project combines a genuinely art historical objective, oriented towards the reconstruction of historical contexts, with broader theoretical perspectives. By studying artistic practices in-depth and reconstructing historical debates, it will make an important contribution to the history of Conceptual Art, and hence the immediate prehistory and preconditions of today’s cultural production.
The project will enable the researcher to qualify for tenured positions in modern and contemporary art by building on his already extensive qualifications and record of research on nineteenth- and twentieth-century art. The fellowship will enhance his international experience from former fellowships at prestigious institutions in the United States and in France by providing another national context and a different type of organisation.
The collaboration with a highly renowned supervisor at a top-ranked institution that attracts a vibrant international research community will offer the researcher the ideal context to attain his research objectives, broaden his expertise, extend the reach of his network, and diversify his skills through specialised training programmes. With his focus on the neglected material aspects of Conceptual Art, he will contribute to the host institution’s commitment to object-based research and teaching. Based on strategies developed in his personal career development plan, the researcher will disseminate his findings to target audiences and contribute broader understanding to society at large.</objective>
  <title>Worldly Matter: The Materials of Conceptual Art</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAIF2016</identifier>
</project>
