<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>194059</rcn>
  <acronym>HNN 2.0</acronym>
  <objective>Health NCP Net 2.0 aims at improving and professionalizing the NCP service, thus achieving a more consistent level of NCP support services across Europe with the final goal to better support applicants and raise the average quality of proposals submitted. 
HNN 2.0 builds upon the experience and results of the previous Health NCP Net project with the objective of responding to the new challenges that the “Health, Demographic Change and Wellbeing” NCPs face in the new programme Horizon 2020, such as the broadened thematic scope of the Societal Challenge 1, and the enlarged mandate of the “Health” NCPs. An objective of the HNN 2.0 project is to satisfy the needs and priorities of all different types of NCPs, notably newcomers, NCPs with fewer resources, NCPs from EU-13 and NCPs in Third Countries so as to face the  challenge of the current heterogeneity of the network 
The enlarged mandate of “Health” NCPs and the holistic focus of H2020 imply that NCPs need to create expert knowledge and look for it outside the SC1 Network by having a holistic approach and liaising and collaborating with other support structures, projects and programmes. HNN 2.0 will therefore have a real structured coordination with the other NCP and support networks such as Ideal-IST, EEN and Fit for Health 2.0, where collaboration for joint activities like training courses, meet and exchange workshops and brokerage events is established. Main tools towards the objectives: 
 - support and information materials 
- comprehensive training programme 
- mentoring programme (staff exchanges, mentoring programme for EU-13, twinning with the European Commission) 
- Meet and Exchange workshops with NCPs from other disciplines 
- system of email alert for NCPs about research funding and related policies
- information and communication hub for SC1-NCPs (easy access to information and services , exchange of information and opinions between SC1-NCPs)
- International brokerage events</objective>
  <title>Improving and professionalizing the Health NCP service across Europe.</title>
<identifier>H2020HCO2014</identifier>
</project>
