<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206248</rcn>
  <acronym>PJ01 EAD</acronym>
  <objective>In order to meet forecast traffic growth, PJ01 will develop concepts, tools and procedures to increase the capacity of Terminal Manoeuvring Areas (TMAs) in a safe, cost-effective and environmentally sustainable manner.  This will be achieved by taking advantage of the latest technological developments from both an airborne and a ground-system perspective and through the secure sharing of data. The needs of all Airspace Users will be addressed including General Aviation and Rotorcraft.
 
All types of European TMA environments will be considered. For low to medium density/complexity TMAs the driver will be to exploit the environmental benefits achieved from Continuous Climb Operations, Continuous Descent Operations and improved arrival sequencing.  For the capacity-constrained high-density/complexity TMAs, particularly including multiple airports, the focus will be to minimise delays and improve resilience alongside providing environmental benefits. This will be achieved by enhancing arrival and departure management by the dynamic use of precision navigation routes.  Traffic flows will be optimised by improving the integration of the management of arrivals with departures and by improving the capability to balance traffic demand and available capacity across the network and airports.
 
To provide increased resilience in poor weather and a reduction in go-arounds, investigations will assess the use of tools that display traffic information in the cockpit. This will help manage airborne spacing, sequencing and merging with other aircraft, under the overall control of Air Traffic Control in systemised airspace. 
 
To ensure that the full benefits are achieved and that the expected performance improvements are realised in the context of the overall ATM network, close co-ordination will take place with other projects, particularly those addressing airport management, network management, separation management and the overall content integration within the programme.</objective>
  <title>Enhanced Arrivals and Departures</title>
<identifier>H2020SESAR20152</identifier>
</project>
