<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>209020</rcn>
  <acronym>MOSK</acronym>
  <objective>The experienced researcher, Dr. Benjamin Mosk, wants to investigate a description of gravity in terms of non-local degrees of freedom. This approach is motivated by the AdS/CFT correspondence and the recent progress made by Dr. Mosk and his collaborators on the subject of kinematic space, the space of totally geodesic sub manifolds of Anti de Sitter (AdS) space. Dr. Mosk proposes to generalize the idea of kinematic space and the description of dynamical fields on this space to more general classical geometries, starting with the AdS-Schwarzschild geometry. The scientific objective of this project is to make progress towards a fundamental description of gravity at the non-classical level, which is arguably the largest open question in theoretical physics.

Dr. Mosk, who is currently conducting postdoctoral research at Stanford University, is applying for a Global Fellowship. During the outgoing phase, Dr. Mosk wants to go to UC Berkeley, where he will work with Professor Raphael Bousso. The return phase will take place at the University of Cambridge, where Professor David Tong is supporting his application. Both research groups have their specific specializations, which are complementary in the project and allow for a great degree of synergy and knowledge exchange between the partner organizations and the experienced researcher.

Special emphasis will be put onto developing Dr. Mosk’s international network and visibility, which are key factors towards Dr. Mosk’s long term career goals. The proposal elaborates on the appropriate training necessary to reach these career goals. A MSCA Individual Fellowship (Global) would support Dr. Mosk’s professional development optimally, by enabling him to work in the perfect environment and by facilitating for the appropriate training described in the proposal.</objective>
  <title>Gravity and Kinematic Space</title>
<identifier>H2020MSCAIF2016</identifier>
</project>
