<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>196305</rcn>
  <acronym>EMBRYON</acronym>
  <objective>Infertility is a heavy social issue,experienced by nearly one in six couples during reproductive lifetime.
In Vitro Fertilization (IVF) is growing 8-10% p.a.,to 1.5 million therapy cycles and 7.5 billion dollars in 2013.
Despite stressful and costly procedures,IVF success rate is low (15-20% births/cycle),leaving big opportunities for innovation and process optimization.
EMBRYON introduces to IVF clinics and specialists a last-generation diagnostic-imaging system,favoring better outcomes through deeper,smarter analysis of clinical images.
It merges tailored image-processing software and algorithms,patented by ACS,with a high-end commercial IVF microscope.A prototype is under validation with top clinics in Italy and Switzerland,supported by Nikon Instruments (global leader in IVF microscopy).
EMBRYON improves the key success factor of any IVF procedure:the identification of 1-2  embryos with best “pregnancy potential” to be transferred in utero,amongst 5-10 generated in vitro.
EMBRYON’s precision is double than current handcrafted approaches,favoring higher success rates.
It is safer (100% not invasive),thus simpler to certify and adopt,fully compliant with ethical regulation,easier to use (no change to lab procedures) and cheaper than similar products.
Key innovations
1. Automated deep scan of embryo shape,overcoming today’s subjective and approximate observations carried by the physician
2. Proprietary algorithms for the measurement of complex morphological patterns,strong predictors of potential
Sales forecasts are 1200-1400 units (40-45 M€ gross revenues) by 2020 in Europe and US,favored by:
- High reactivity of the IVF sector (scientists/patients) to validated solutions improving outcomes
- Commercial partnership with a global IVF microscopy leader
In Ph1 we’ll finalize and publish the ongoing clinical studies and make a deep market analysis for Europe-US
In Ph2 we plan CE/FDA clearance,WW extension of patents,3 trials in Europe-US,set-up of newco and sales org</objective>
  <title>EMBRYON - Develop and commercialize a highly innovative diagnostic-imaging product, improving success rates in the Assisted Reproduction IVF sector</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST12014</identifier>
</project>
