<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>198349</rcn>
  <acronym>MAYA</acronym>
  <objective>MAYA aims at developing simulation methodologies and multidisciplinary tools for the design, engineering and management of CPS-based (Cyber Physical Systems) Factories, in order to strategically support production-related activities during all the phases of the factory life-cycle, from the integrated design of the product-process- production system, through the optimization of the running factory, till the dismissal/reconfiguration phase. The concurrence and the cross-combination of the Cyber and the Physical dimensions with the Simulation domain is considered as cornerstone in MAYA innovations, to successfully address a new generation of smart factories for future industry responsiveness. MAYA finds complete validation in one of the most competitive, advanced and complex industrial sector in Europe, the automotive, where it will accomplish reduced time to production &amp; reduced time to optimization within two use-cases (Volkswagen and FinnPower).
In order to realize such a vision, MAYA addresses actual technological constraints through research and development activities focusing on the following three high level objectives:
- MAYA for Digital Continuity;
- MAYA for the Synchronization of the Digital and Real Factory;
- MAYA for Multidisciplinary integrated simulation and modelling.
MAYA’s concept and motivation have been born within the framework set by the Pathfinder initiative, and represent a concrete first step to empower the vision there drafted, and consolidated thanks to the contribution of several academic experts and industrial key-players (http://www.pathfinderproject.eu/contributors.asp).</objective>
  <title>Multi-disciplinArY integrated simulAtion and forecasting tools, empowered by digital continuity and continuous real-world synchronization, towards reduced time to production and optimization</title>
<identifier>H2020FoF2015</identifier>
</project>
