<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>208045</rcn>
  <acronym>CORDIAL</acronym>
  <objective>The overall objective of the CORDIAL project is to develop a new compact drilling and fastening unit for One Way Assembly. The effector has to be used by operator or lightweight industrial robots. Six sub-objectives contribute to achieve such a goal:
- To define how robots and operators can interact in an OWA cell. 
- To evaluate a typical assembly layout and endeavour new OWA opportunities and risks assessment.
- To develop compact automated effector(s) for drilling, fastening and counteracting
- To establish a test plan according to requirements for commercial aircraft structures.
- To demonstrate the technology, realize specimens and test the proof of concept under real conditions.
- To disseminate the results widely to maximise the impacts of the CORDIAL project.

To complete the project, the capabilities of the partners include:
-SONACA Engineering, industrialization, qualifying and manufacturing means for small subassemblies such as slats of landing gear doors, including composite manufacturing.
-AEROSPLINE innovative engineering in robotics and drilling and fastening effectors. Including innovative fastener with sealant feeding, which permits to simplify and lighten any effector.
-XLIM Advanced sensor vision technologies using small size vision sensors and capable of multiple information computation: coordinate positioning, centring, normality, hole and fastener quality.

The CORDIAL project is perfectly in line with the Clean Sky 2 objectives since it will contribute to develop eco-friendly processes (reduction of the impacts on health, creation of sustainable capabilities), to demonstrate new technologies (human/robot close collaboration in the aeronautics, new structures design), improve the European competitiveness (lighten the assembly process, cost reduction and shorten time-to-market) and create market opportunities (technology transfers, innovation stimulation and attraction of elite in Europe) and new skilled jobs like cobotics engineering.</objective>
  <title>Collaborative OWA robots for drilling and fasteners insertion in assembly lines</title>
<identifier>H2020CS2CFP03201601</identifier>
</project>
