<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>206850</rcn>
  <acronym>FLEXPOL</acronym>
  <objective>FLEXPOL aims to develop a pilot line for the production of a cost effective antimicrobial (AM) adhesive film for its use in hospitals. 
The obtained adhesive film will inhibit growth of a wide range of microbes and will be suitable for high-touch surfaces, providing a durable protection with good resistance. It will assure the highest level of hygiene and patient safety, reducing the use of disinfectants.
These objectives will be achieved, using a multi-functional approach combining prevention of adhesion with killing of microorganisms, by means of essential oil (EO) emulsions embedded in a micro and nanopatterned polypropylene matrix. 
FLEXPOL covers the following key aspects:
-It addresses the development, upscaling and demonstration in a relevant industrial environment of the production of films with AM, biocompatible and anti-adhesive properties. Existing extrusion and nanoimprinting pilot lines will act as the starting point in which new additives based on blends of EO will be incorporated. 
-Previously validated technologies constitute the basis of the approach. These technologies will be extended to large scale production and demonstrated in a real operational environment. The pilot line will include real time characterization for inspection of the film at the nanoscale.
-Robustness and repeatability of film fabrication and its behavior in a real environment will be studied. The effectiveness of the solution will be compared with standard protocols.
-Materials are chosen according to their cost for large-scale application. Productivity and cost of the fabrication process will be analyzed attending to energetic optimization of the product fabrication and the raw material cost. 
-Access to the pilot line for AM films in this or a different application will be ensured to European Industries at a cost that promotes technology transfer.
-Non-technological aspects key for the marketing of the product (such as regulatory issues, HSE aspects, LCA...) are considered.</objective>
  <title>Antimicrobial FLEXible POLymers for its use in hospital environments</title>
<identifier>H2020NMBPPILOTS2016</identifier>
</project>
