<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>210382</rcn>
  <acronym>WATEC</acronym>
  <objective>"WATEC project deals with the design, fabrication, "on-field" testing and commercialization of an innovative hydro-turbine able to convert into electricity the kinetic and potential energy of waves and the kinetic energy of tidal streams. 
The technology works in three ways:
1-	it converts the kinetic energy of tidal streams by applying an undershoot waterwheel principle utilising a flow diverter to accelerate and redirect flow under the rotor;
2-	this deflector also redirects waves onto the upper platform where an overtopping principle converts wave potential energy as flow drains past the side of the rotor;
3-	a similar approach and flow path is used to capture wave kinetic energy.
Thanks to the simultaneous exploitation of both potential and kinetic waves and kinetic tidal hydro-energy in a compact plant and to the technology design optimization, WATEC leads to a industry leading LCOE of 71 €/MWh, much lower than the competing solution for low-head hydropower conversion (100÷270 €/kWh ).
The HP plant floating structure is semi-submersible utilising a taut mooring principle and anchor cable shock absorbers to minimise wave impact forces. This approach also eliminates the need for: 
 -) voltage limiting ‘wet mate’ inductive couplings; 
 -) expensive subsea interventions for maintenance and defouling;
 -) expensive subsea construction techniques.
The technology has a low environmental impact (no piling for the deployment of the deadweight anchors and limited seabed trenching are required), an easy installation, a low visual impact in comparison to industry alternatives (it protrudes 10 meters above water level), a full material recovery during the decommissioning process.
By WATEC, low-head hydropower sector will be revolutionized as it will be possible to apply a technology able to make competitive damless HP, thus dramatically enlarging the HP application potentialities."</objective>
  <title>Development of a novel wave  tidal energy converter (WATEC) to lower renewable electricity generation costs.</title>
<identifier>H2020SMEINST120162017</identifier>
</project>
