<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>194403</rcn>
  <acronym>SYNAMERA</acronym>
  <objective>This proposal for a Coordination Action aims at improving visibility  for essential stakeholders, most notably national/regional programming and funding authorities, on programming synergetic actions between the European Union and member states in the NMP Program. This shall be done by organising a forum and collecting road maps focused in particular on the use of the new ERANET instrument in the NMP area.

In doing so, the CSA shall acknowledge that the NMP program has an important role in translating result from flagships towards industrial application and in facilitating key enabling technologies towards the Grand Societal Challenges. It shall also take into account the methodology of technology readiness levels is leading the programmation of the NMP work program. Programming should also acknowledge that industrial leadership, for SMEs in particular is an important objective. This objective should result in a road-map with the aim to increase visibility on themes to program. 
 
In exploiting synergies, the new ERANET Instrument is an important  tool. In order to operationalize it in Horizon2020 visibility should be improved on best practices in using the ERANET under FP7 as well collecting a database on projects funded through it. This shall give input to a forum to discuss future opportunities and identify critical mass of funding agencies willing to support it.

Synergies shall often require alignment of European, National and Regional funding.  In fact operational programs under ERDF demand these synergies. In NMP many topics demand an alignment of proposals with regional Smart Specialisation Strategies. How these synergies can be organised is an explicit objective, with the aim, to enlarge the number of funding agencies (national or regional) able to use it. Therefore particular attention in this project shall be given to reach out to as many regions as possible.</objective>
  <title>Synergies in Nanotechnologies, Materials and Production in the European Research Area</title>
<identifier>H2020NMPCSA2014</identifier>
</project>
