<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>200155</rcn>
  <acronym>guarantEE</acronym>
  <objective>Energy Performance Contracting (EPC) is a proven model for modernizing mostly public buildings by ESCOs with guaranteed energy and cost savings. Nevertheless, a broad roll-out of EPC is being prevented mainly because of two unresolved issues: the split incentives dilemma and the lack of adequately flexible contract models.
The guarantEE project will address prevailing barriers to EPC in a team of 14 experienced partners, covering large parts of Europe in a mix of advanced and emerging ESCO markets.
Based on a concise market analysis, guarantEE will develop innovative business and financing models addressing and overcoming the split incentives dilemma in performance based ESCO projects. This will be done by adequately sharing costs and benefits between user, building owner and ESCO (triple-win approach), thus opening up new project opportunities. Furthermore, EPC contract variants will be elaborated and tested, addressing the need for enhanced flexibility (e.g. exit clauses, simplified M&amp;V, future energy market needs, storage). The target groups are public and – especially in advanced EPC markets – private sector clients.
The developed models will be applied in 33 pilot projects involving private and public building owners. The project will achieve 78 GWh PE and 18000 tCO2 savings per year and will trigger investments of &gt;11 M€.
Particularly in emerging EPC markets, guarantEE will support market development by providing standards, an online EPC pre-check, good practice examples, EPC information and project facilitation for mainly municipal clients. Broad dissemination activities, including the European Energy Service Award, will maximise the project visibility.
The project will address or consult at least 1000 building owners and EPC facilitators and will inform at least 2000 energy sector stakeholders on EPC.
The guarantEE project will unlock additional EPC project opportunities, contribute to standardisation, and provide political advice and steps towards a common energy service market in Europe.</objective>
  <title>Energy Efficiency with Performance Guarantees in Private and Public Sector</title>
<identifier>H2020EE20153MarketUptake</identifier>
</project>
