<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211435</rcn>
  <acronym>CECM</acronym>
  <objective>Kraków educates a large number of medical and IT professionals; its research hospitals are well recognised in the scientific community. Furthermore, the local entrepreneurial sector, with a significant number of life science companies, is steadily growing. In light of this evolution we propose to establish the Centre of Excellence for New Methods in Computational Diagnostics and Personalised Therapy.
The Centre's mission comprises development of new computation-based solutions for diagnostics and therapy in daily healthcare to improve personalised patient treatment, enhanced growth of SMEs which deal with technologies and services for novel personalised diagnostics and treatment strategies, as well as strong advancement of algorithms, models and technologies involved in personalised medicine.
The project aims to develop a Business Plan establishing the Centre and enabling it to operate in such a way as to achieve measurable success through introduction of a certain number of solutions based on computational models to clinical trials, development of a number of new market-ready products and services based on innovations, authoring highly cited scientific papers, obtaining patents and securing grants.
The Plan will be based on the Polish Specialisation Strategy and will be elaborated by two Polish partners: Cyfronet AGH (experts in simulation and computing infrastructures for science) and Klaster LifeScience Kraków (top cluster of industry, academia and hospitals in the life sciences domain), in collaboration with the University of Sheffield and Insigneo Institute (experts in translation of in-silico modelling and simulations to clinics), Forschungszentrum Jülich (experts in innovative HPC and data techniques for science and industry) and Fraunhofer ISI (experts in systemic multi-domain solutions and innovation in medicine).</objective>
  <title>Centre for New Methods in Computational Diagnostics and Personalised Therapy</title>
<identifier>H2020WIDESPREAD042017TeamingPhase1</identifier>
</project>
