<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>211652</rcn>
  <acronym>HubIT</acronym>
  <objective>The long term strategic objective of HubIT is to contribute to the high level of European research and innovation and ensure that H2020 funded and further ICT related innovation is responsible, inclusive and aimed at reversing inequalities.

The direct objective of HubIT is to build a hub that will activate and improve constructive and co-creating interactions between SSH and ICT disciplines in developing and implementing a shared vision of inclusive 

HubIT will activate constructive interactions between the stakeholders forming the RRI-SSH eco-system via various network and engagement activities embedded intro the WP structure, that have the overall goal of developing a tangible European Framework Model for implementing responsible and inclusive ICT research and innovation. The Framework Model is a comprehensive set of jointly developed and used definitions, guidelines and tools for enforcing RRI and SSH issues in ICT research and innovation:
• The concept of responsible R&amp;I
• Matrix of the key challenges
• Tool for assessment of RRI and SSH perspectives in ICT within an organisation
• Guidelines for responsible ICT R&amp;I informed by SSH
• Best Practice Repository
• Fact Sheets and Policy briefs
• Key measurable success indicators 
• Policy Recommendations
• Virtual Matching Catalogue
• HubIT exploitation plan 

The mechanisms for network building, engagement and awareness rising embedded in the WP structure are:
• Advisory Board workshops
• Expert Group workshops
• Community building and knowledge sharing – national network events, thematic workshops, policy, SSH researchers and ICT industries workshops
• Practical collaborations and experimentation - Common Ground Camps, Interactive ICT Labs, Inclusive Hackathons
In total 35 network activities are implemented and in total 1140 participants. HubIT online platform will be the interactive environment, where the project tools and services can be accessed in modular, visually attractive and dynamic way.</objective>
  <title>The HUB for boosting the Responsibility and inclusiveness of ICT enabled Research and Innovation through constructive interactions with SSH research</title>
<identifier>H2020SC6REVINEQUAL2017</identifier>
</project>
