<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>193896</rcn>
  <acronym>New_Innonet</acronym>
  <objective>Europe generates around 3 billion tonnes of waste yearly, which is expected to grow further. Despite the introduction of innovative waste and recycling technologies, market uptake varies drastically amongst the 27 Member States.

New-InnoNet is the new stakeholder platform initiative by 12 European consortium members active as entrepreneurs, researchers and policy makers. These recognise that in order to reach a European near zero waste economy, all value chain stakeholders must cooperate, exchange generated knowledge, insights and hands-on experience and enforce changes to the value chain structure together. Previous initiatives were unable to achieve actual, large scale results towards a sustainable growth of the European economy. The reason is that they either focussed on a  specific waste area or they lacked the involvement of the competent industries. This project includes various waste value chains which enable exchange of information and technology transfer from one chain to another. In addition, the consortium’s network includes over 2000 relevant industrial stakeholders and several already expressed their interest in this new stakeholder platform, its goals and actions. During the project, key stakeholders will be mobilised to participate in the platform and road mapping workshops, as only an active involvement of industrial organisations will lead to the desired changes in the structure of the value chain. The many letters of support show the consortium's strength in mobilising stakeholders.

NEW_InnoNet’s main objective is to mobilise stakeholders towards building a circular economy by developing and reinforcing solid foundations for building the European Near-Zero Waste Platform through: 
1. Set-up and maintain near zero waste stakeholder platform
2. Analyse selected waste streams and develop innovation roadmaps per waste stream 
3. Develop an integrated near zero waste strategic research and innovation agenda
4. Stakeholder mobilisation and interaction</objective>
  <title>NEW_InnoNet: The Near-zero European Waste Innovation Network</title>
<identifier>H2020WASTE2014onestage</identifier>
</project>
