<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212683</rcn>
  <acronym>EU-TRAIN</acronym>
  <objective>Rejection is the major cause of allograft failure with dramatic consequences in terms of mortality, morbidity and increased cost for the society. The field of transplantation lacks a robust assessment of risk stratification. Thus, it impairs the development of relevant clinical trials to address graft and patient outcomes. We formed the EU-TRAIN project by gathering reference kidney transplant centres in a fully operating European network including 12 partners. Our ambitious but realistic goals are: to provide clinicians with innovative and accessible tools for early prediction of individual risk of allograft rejection and transplant loss; to personalise clinical management and treatment and; to improve allograft outcomes. This project will engineer a risk stratification system applied to kidney transplant patients by analysing the integration of several layers of data (clinical, histological, immunological data as well as gene expression and novel biomarkers) - the TRAnsplant Comprehensive Evaluator of Risk (EU-TRACER). EU-TRACER will be generated and validated in 2 dedicated studies including a randomised control trial. Translation to patients will be achieved by delivering: 1) A multiplex non-invasive biomarker system for the stratification and immune monitoring of low and high risk kidney recipients; 2) A prognostic system for individual risk stratification for allograft rejection and failure that will assist decision making via an interactive web interface. The EU-TRACER, developed with our 3 industrial partners, will define a new standard of care in transplantation. The EU-TRACER will have the potential for a large implementation and diffusion in other centres in Europe and will be suitable for industrial collaboration.</objective>
  <title>The EUropean TRAnsplantation and INnovation (EU-TRAIN) consortium for improving diagnosis and risk stratification in kidney transplant patients</title>
<identifier>H2020SC12017TwoStageRTD</identifier>
</project>
