<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>193959</rcn>
  <acronym>INCAME</acronym>
  <objective>The project aims to enhance SMEs’ competitiveness and innovation processes management and to improve the regional innovation environment,  increasing the efficiency and the effectiveness of investments in research, development and innovation. The project partners will operate in the regions  under the EEN BRIDGeconomies consortium: Abruzzo, Basilicata, Calabria, Campania, Molise, Puglia and Sicilia. The overall objective of the project is helping SMEs to adopt, implement and deploy an innovation management system. 
The project has two main specific objectives,  structured in 2 Work Packages: 
WP1) to support innovation management capacities of SMEs beneficiaries from H2020 SME Instrument; 
WP2) to enhance SMEs, with significant innovation activities and high potential for internationalisation, who lack knowledge, skills and abilities to manage innovation activities and helping them to unlock their potential by better managing the innovation processes. 
To reach such specific objectives, during the period covered by the action, the project partnership intends to deliver seven days service packages to a number of 94 SMEs, benefiting from SME Instrument grants  and services for enhancing their innovation management capacities. 
Project partners intend to implement these actions since SMEs play a crucial role in reaching the objectives of the Europe 2020 Strategy and notably the Innovation Union. SMEs are key drivers of innovation serving as an important conduit for knowledge spill-overs. Tapping the full innovation potential of SMEs requires efficient support mechanisms. The focus needs to be oriented to impact on SMEs, looking at their internationalisation, their knowledge and R&amp;D capabilities, competitiveness and growth.</objective>
  <title>INnovation CApacities of Mediterranean Enterprises</title>
<identifier>H2020Adhoc201420</identifier>
</project>
