<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>212913</rcn>
  <acronym>INFACT</acronym>
  <objective>Exploration discovery of raw material resources requires innovations that either change the geological targets of exploration, the physical places that are reached, or the manner in which they are explored. Despite its rich history of mining and residual mineral wealth, current conditions within the EU present a number of social, political, legislative, cost, technical and physical obstacles to raw material exploration: obstacles to be overcome by innovation, dialogue and reform.

The Innovative, Non-invasive and Fully Acceptable Exploration Technologies (INFACT) project unites stakeholders of Europe’s future raw materials security in its consortium and activities. Via effective engagement of civil society, state, research and industry, the project will focus on each of these obstacles. It will co-develop improved systems and innovative technologies that are more acceptable to society and invigorate and equip the exploration industry, unlocking unrealised potential in new and mature areas. 

The project will develop innovative geophysical and remote sensing technologies (less-invasive than classical exploration methods) that promise to penetrate new depths, reach new sensitivities and resolve new parameters. The project will also set the EU as a leader on the world stage by establishing permanent infrastructure to drive innovation in the next generation of exploration tools: tools that are cost-effective, designed for EU conditions and its raw materials strategy, and high-performing in terms of environmental impact, social acceptability, and technical performance. 

INFACT is comprised of the following main components:
Development and test of innovative, non-invasive exploration technologies. 
Foundation of 3 test sites for exploration technology in the south, centre and north of Europe.
Stakeholder engagement, education and policy reform.
These actions combine to reach each of the main areas in which the EU has the power to influence change in its raw materials security.</objective>
  <title>Innovative, Non-invasive and Fully Acceptable Exploration Technologies</title>
<identifier>H2020SC52017OneStageB</identifier>
</project>
