<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project xmlns="http://cordis.europa.eu">
  <rcn>204973</rcn>
  <acronym>NeMo</acronym>
  <objective>Electromobility is a major factor towards transport decarbonisation. However a number of challenges (limited charging options, lack of interoperability, absence of a unified identification/payment process, energy grid overload, expensive charging tariffs) limit the potential for interoperable and seamless electromobility services to a wider of actors and geographic area, hindering electromobility adoption. These challenges stem from lack of standardisation in electromobility data and services. NeMo addresses all issues through a pan-European eRoaming Hyper-Network that allows seamless and interoperable use of electromobility services throughout Europe. In addition it provides an Open Cloud Marketplace, where third parties can provide services (B2B2C) aiming to increase EV attractiveness. The NeMo Hyper-Network is a distributed environment with open architecture based on standardised interfaces, in which all electromobility actors, physical (i.e. CPs, grids, EVs) or digital (i.e. CPOs, DSOs, etc.), can connect and interact seamlessly, exchange data and provide more elaborate electromobility ICT services in a fully integrated and interoperable way both B2B and B2C. The connection will be based on dynamic translation of data and services interfaces according to needs of the specific scenarios and involved stakeholders. NeMo is not just another proprietary platform for electromobility but a full open eco-system allowing continuous and uninterrupted provision of data and services. NeMo will raise awareness, liaise with standardisation bodies and contribute to the evolution of protocols and standards by developing public Common Information Models which incorporate all existing electromobility related standards and constantly update them to reflect standards evolution. NeMo will also propose sustainable business models for all electromobility actors opening new opportunities for SMEs and EU Industry.</objective>
  <title>NeMo : Hyper-Network for electroMobility</title>
<identifier>H2020GV2015</identifier>
</project>
